<?xml version="1.0"?>
<arch:spatialUnit xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/SpatialUnit/SpatialUnit.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/space_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" UUID="D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4" ownedBy="A5DDBEA2-B3C8-43F9-8151-33343CBDC857">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>Petra Great Temple</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <oc:item_class>
    <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
    <oc:iconURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_50x50.jpg</oc:iconURI>
  </oc:item_class>
  <arch:observations>
    <arch:observation obsNumber="1">
      <arch:properties>
        <arch:property>
          <arch:variableID>63D70C2B-DBF4-4A17-89B9-818F1F25334D</arch:variableID>
          <arch:valueID>F609C0A9-1EB4-4555-D9F8-18AF970A7281</arch:valueID>
          <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/5500C8BE-1B85-4DA4-EF59-837F9676261F">5500C8BE-1B85-4DA4-EF59-837F9676261F</oc:propid>
          <oc:var_label type="alphanumeric">More (Link)</oc:var_label>
          <oc:show_val>http://www.brown.edu/Departments/Anthropology/Petra/temple/temple.html</oc:show_val>
        </arch:property>
        <arch:property>
          <arch:variableID>E09F2554-906B-4D09-9A26-43242ACC1310</arch:variableID>
          <arch:valueID>B776F358-8257-4CB2-EA5E-5022CDE9A4FF</arch:valueID>
          <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/A41310B6-4BC3-423C-DDA1-4580A63BF8D4">A41310B6-4BC3-423C-DDA1-4580A63BF8D4</oc:propid>
          <oc:var_label type="alphanumeric">History</oc:var_label>
          <oc:show_val>Petra (from the Latin word 'petrae', meaning 'rock') lies in a great rift valley east of Wadi 'Araba in Jordan about 80 kilometers south of the Dead Sea. It came into prominence in the late first century BCE (BC) through the success of the spice trade. The city was the principal city of ancient Nabataea and was famous above all for two things: its trade and its hydraulic engineering systems. It was locally autonomous until the reign of Trajan, but it flourished under Roman rule. The town grew up around its Colonnaded Street in the first century CE (AD) and by the mid-first century had witnessed rapid urbanization. Following the flow of the Wadi Musa, the city-center was laid out on either sides of the Colonnaded Street on an elongated plan between the theater in the east and the Qasr al-Bint in the west. The quarries were probably opened in this period, and there followed virtually continuous building through the first and second centuries CE. According to tradition, in ca. 1200 BCE, the Petra area (but not necessarily the site itself) was populated by Edomites and the area was known as Edom ("red"). Before the Israelite incursions, the Edomites controlled the trade routes from Arabia in the south to Damascus in the north. Little is known about the Edomites at Petra itself, but as a people they were known for their wisdom, their writing, their textile industry, the excellence and fineness of their ceramics, and their skilled metal working. The next chapter of history belongs to the Persian period, and it is posited that during this time the Nabataeans migrated into Edom, forcing the Edomites to move into southern Palestine. But little is known about Petra proper until about 312 BC by which time the Nabataeans, one of many Arab tribes, occupied it and made it the capital of their kingdom. At this time, during the Hellenistic rule of the Seleucids, and later, the Ptolemies, the whole area flourished with increased trade and the establishment of new towns such as Philadelphia (Rabbath 'Ammon, modern Amman) and Gerasa (modern Jerash). Infighting between the Seleucids and Ptolemies allowed the Nabataeans to gain control over the caravan routes between Arabia and Syria. Although there were struggles between the Jewish Maccabeans and the Seleucid overlords, Nabataean trade continued. With Nabataean rule, Petra became the center for a spice trade that extended from Arabia to Aqaba and Petra, and onward either to Gaza in the northwest, or to the north through Amman to Bostra, Damascus, and finally on to Palmyra and the Syrian Desert. Nabataean Classical monuments reflect the international character of the Nabataean economy through their combination of native tradition and the classical spirit. But among the most remarkable of all Nabataean achievements is the hydraulic engineering systems they developed including water conservation systems and the dams that were constructed to divert the rush of swollen winter waters that create flash floods. In 64-63 BCE, the Nabataeans were conquered by the Roman general, Pompey, whose policy was to restore the cities taken by the Jews. However, he retained an independent Nabataea, although the area was taxed by the Romans and served as a buffer territory against the desert tribes. Completely subsumed by the Romans under the Emperor Trajan in 106 CE, Petra and Nabataea then became part of the Roman province known as Arabia Petraea with its capital at Petra. In 131 CE Hadrian, the Roman emperor, visited the site and named it after himself, Hadriane Petra. The city continued to flourish during the Roman period, with a Triumphal Arch spanning the Siq, and tomb structures either carved out of the living rock or built free-standing. Under Roman rule, Roman Classical monuments abounded &#x97; many with Nabataean overtones. By 313 CE (AD), Christianity had become a state-recognized religion. In 330 CE, the Emperor Constantine established the Eastern Roman Empire with its capital at Constantinople. Although the 363 earthquake destroyed half of the city, it appears that Petra retained its urban vitality into late antiquity, when it was the seat of a Byzantine bishopric. The newly excavated Petra church with its papyrus scrolls document this period, especially in the sixth century, a phenomenon less well-attested in other sites so far south of 'Amman. In this period there is also striking archaeological and documentary evidence for accommodation between Christians and the pagan aristocracy. Thereafter one can read the archaeology of a fragmented middle Byzantine community living among and re-using the abandoned limestone and sandstone elements of its classical past. The inhabitants during the Byzantine Period recycled many standing structures and rock-cut monuments, while also constructing their own buildings, including churches &#x97; such as the recently excavated Petra Church with the extraordinary mosaics. Among the rock-cut monuments they reused is the great tomb or the Ad-Dayr (known also as 'The Monastery'), which was modified into a church. With a change in trade routes, Petra's commercial decline was inevitable. An even more devastating earthquake had a severe impact on the city in 551 CE, and all but brought the city to ruin. With the rise of Islam, Petra became a backwater community. Petra was revealed to the western world in 1812 for the first time since the Crusades when it was re-discovered by the Swiss explorer Johann Ludwig Burckhardt.</oc:show_val>
        </arch:property>
        <arch:property>
          <arch:variableID>9FFEAF8C-D39D-4054-2EBC-0AD16CED91B6</arch:variableID>
          <arch:valueID>AB806C15-1B5C-4903-B2C8-80DED98886ED</arch:valueID>
          <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/AB749C1F-2F7D-4BC2-69B6-7AAE972239D8">AB749C1F-2F7D-4BC2-69B6-7AAE972239D8</oc:propid>
          <oc:var_label type="alphanumeric">Sponsors</oc:var_label>
          <oc:show_val>This campaign would not have been possible without the generous assistance of the Jordanian Department of Antiquities, Fawwaz al-Kraysheh, Director, and Suleiman Farajat Director of the Petra National Park, Sami Al-Nawafleh our Department of Antiquities Representative and the American Center of Oriental Research, Pierre M. Bikai, Director. We would also like to express our thanks to Brown University for making this season possible. We were supported by a work force of 50 devoted Bedouin, directed by Dakhilallah Qublan, Foreman. The Petra Crowne Plaza Hotel and the American Center of Oriental Research in Amman, to whom we are most grateful, also provided additional support.</oc:show_val>
        </arch:property>
        <arch:property>
          <arch:variableID>676861D3-AFB3-4D41-ACEE-5F0913C08B3B</arch:variableID>
          <arch:valueID>83CF1ECC-AE3B-45C6-6399-2C0F9A2619F1</arch:valueID>
          <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/C3936260-2E11-4243-EF59-E20629E92B91">C3936260-2E11-4243-EF59-E20629E92B91</oc:propid>
          <oc:var_label type="alphanumeric">Overview</oc:var_label>
          <oc:show_val>The Great Temple contains eclectic exquisite art and architecture from the Nabataean period and demonstrates that the values of the Nabataeans of Petra during this period who felt that aesthetic decoration of structures with frescos and architectural sculpture was sufficiently significant on which to expend time, money and energy. This blending of different cultures is seen in this palatial building and its precinct with the use of elephant heads, frescos, elegantly carved pilasters and capitals. There is a high level of skill and technology possessed by her builders as well as the high level of organized government that would be needed to plan the building of this monumental structure. The Great Temple is one of the key sites in the Nabataean Petra, and it is a significant site for our knowledge of the development of Petra. The lives of the Nabataeans were influenced by a unique blend of cultures. The study of the Great Temple is essential to the understanding of many different aspects of the archaeology of Petra. Such an interpretation when considered in relation to what is known about other Nabataean sites can effectively enrich the web of knowledge we possess regarding both Petra and the people whose lives ultimately created it. Each of our seasons of excavation has proved to be provocative and propitious as many questions were raised and many extraordinary artifacts were recovered. The Great Temple represents one of the major archaeological and architectural components of central Petra. Located to the south of the Colonnaded Street and southeast of the Temenos Gate, this 75602 m precinct is comprised of a Propylaeum (monumental entryway), a Lower Temenos, and monumental east and west Stairways which in turn lead to the Upper Temenos &#x97; the sacred enclosure for the Temple proper. The Petra Great Temple was first explored by R. E. Br</oc:show_val>
        </arch:property>
        <arch:property>
          <arch:variableID>CB1099D8-E70F-4CF7-0CB0-99CE14E658F5</arch:variableID>
          <arch:valueID>624FB433-589C-4CDC-9914-A8E3C5312B9B</arch:valueID>
          <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/CCB87F83-8993-4740-A459-20ADC8AA1865">CCB87F83-8993-4740-A459-20ADC8AA1865</oc:propid>
          <oc:var_label type="alphanumeric">About</oc:var_label>
          <oc:show_val>Brown University professor Martha Sharp Joukowsky is at present directing the archaeological excavations of the Great Temple at Petra, Jordan. Although the excavation is funded by Brown University as part of its programs in Anthropology and the Institute of Archaeology and the Ancient World (formerly the Center for Old World Archaeology and Art), it is also an international and interdisciplinary project, with the active involvement of the American Center of Oriental Research (ACOR) located in Amman, and the Department of Antiquities of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</oc:show_val>
        </arch:property>
      </arch:properties>
      <arch:links>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">1A990A73-AC7C-4D9B-68BB-92942D42072A</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">179695F0-CCA1-4917-0967-D49B827CEBD7</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">FBFB4AEA-1878-43B9-4334-064031034063</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">D8984E21-6277-4029-622B-33C74988509A</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">42ED2D89-B58C-4933-5795-8D74D68D6661</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">B2691F8A-9930-4F59-FFF6-2DB987BAE124</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">3206464A-0515-405E-FAAB-54D80528C7F4</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">BACECEC2-A47A-436D-F6F8-A15DAD7BF5BC</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">0D5D1CD1-FB98-40EA-58CA-4A0243FE0B2A</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">F58065FD-5A53-47F0-99CF-7684148B7843</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">28533CB7-C94F-4ECE-2D02-0F5516CACB0E</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">8D4F9C6D-7BBC-4D2D-12F7-4E89705A8A7C</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">50C85ADE-DE71-4863-EE67-4F049E36C50F</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">966FD8EE-E548-43DF-4BEA-22F078E0E351</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">B8B249A9-B743-4D96-015E-424F20ACEF30</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">4B70F8BE-5E49-4ACE-C771-5C71FE70E5AC</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">1FCD84C2-E00C-4CC6-A77B-A76D60DA9F79</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">45582973-8F00-41C2-D28A-F2676190A61A</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">77AEB90B-38D6-4D7E-C3D9-211C5FD3FC8F</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">34011111-A202-49B0-C026-F70B0B0D17B5</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">17197EBF-FA77-4B60-A53B-CADFBE7152E7</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="Standard">9047CD14-85F3-4790-EAF9-FD99D901EF20</arch:docID>
        <arch:docID type="person" info="Editor">1EFB20BC-BE05-486A-C434-988892277ED5</arch:docID>
        <oc:media_links>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/1A990A73-AC7C-4D9B-68BB-92942D42072A">
            <oc:name>1992 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>1A990A73-AC7C-4D9B-68BB-92942D42072A</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_1A990A73-AC7C-4D9B-68BB-92942D42072A_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/179695F0-CCA1-4917-0967-D49B827CEBD7">
            <oc:name>1993 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>179695F0-CCA1-4917-0967-D49B827CEBD7</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_179695F0-CCA1-4917-0967-D49B827CEBD7_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/FBFB4AEA-1878-43B9-4334-064031034063">
            <oc:name>1994 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>FBFB4AEA-1878-43B9-4334-064031034063</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_FBFB4AEA-1878-43B9-4334-064031034063_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/D8984E21-6277-4029-622B-33C74988509A">
            <oc:name>1995 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>D8984E21-6277-4029-622B-33C74988509A</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_D8984E21-6277-4029-622B-33C74988509A_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/42ED2D89-B58C-4933-5795-8D74D68D6661">
            <oc:name>1996 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>42ED2D89-B58C-4933-5795-8D74D68D6661</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_42ED2D89-B58C-4933-5795-8D74D68D6661_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/B2691F8A-9930-4F59-FFF6-2DB987BAE124">
            <oc:name>1997 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>B2691F8A-9930-4F59-FFF6-2DB987BAE124</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_B2691F8A-9930-4F59-FFF6-2DB987BAE124_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/3206464A-0515-405E-FAAB-54D80528C7F4">
            <oc:name>1998 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>3206464A-0515-405E-FAAB-54D80528C7F4</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_3206464A-0515-405E-FAAB-54D80528C7F4_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/BACECEC2-A47A-436D-F6F8-A15DAD7BF5BC">
            <oc:name>1999 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>BACECEC2-A47A-436D-F6F8-A15DAD7BF5BC</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_BACECEC2-A47A-436D-F6F8-A15DAD7BF5BC_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/0D5D1CD1-FB98-40EA-58CA-4A0243FE0B2A">
            <oc:name>2000 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>0D5D1CD1-FB98-40EA-58CA-4A0243FE0B2A</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_0D5D1CD1-FB98-40EA-58CA-4A0243FE0B2A_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/F58065FD-5A53-47F0-99CF-7684148B7843">
            <oc:name>2001 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>F58065FD-5A53-47F0-99CF-7684148B7843</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_F58065FD-5A53-47F0-99CF-7684148B7843_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/28533CB7-C94F-4ECE-2D02-0F5516CACB0E">
            <oc:name>2001 Overall Trench Plan</oc:name>
            <oc:id>28533CB7-C94F-4ECE-2D02-0F5516CACB0E</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_28533CB7-C94F-4ECE-2D02-0F5516CACB0E_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/8D4F9C6D-7BBC-4D2D-12F7-4E89705A8A7C">
            <oc:name>2002 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>8D4F9C6D-7BBC-4D2D-12F7-4E89705A8A7C</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_8D4F9C6D-7BBC-4D2D-12F7-4E89705A8A7C_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/50C85ADE-DE71-4863-EE67-4F049E36C50F">
            <oc:name>2002 Overall Trench Plan</oc:name>
            <oc:id>50C85ADE-DE71-4863-EE67-4F049E36C50F</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_50C85ADE-DE71-4863-EE67-4F049E36C50F_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/966FD8EE-E548-43DF-4BEA-22F078E0E351">
            <oc:name>2003 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>966FD8EE-E548-43DF-4BEA-22F078E0E351</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_966FD8EE-E548-43DF-4BEA-22F078E0E351_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/B8B249A9-B743-4D96-015E-424F20ACEF30">
            <oc:name>2003 Overall Trench Plan</oc:name>
            <oc:id>B8B249A9-B743-4D96-015E-424F20ACEF30</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_B8B249A9-B743-4D96-015E-424F20ACEF30_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/4B70F8BE-5E49-4ACE-C771-5C71FE70E5AC">
            <oc:name>2004 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>4B70F8BE-5E49-4ACE-C771-5C71FE70E5AC</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_4B70F8BE-5E49-4ACE-C771-5C71FE70E5AC_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/1FCD84C2-E00C-4CC6-A77B-A76D60DA9F79">
            <oc:name>2004 Overall Trench Plan</oc:name>
            <oc:id>1FCD84C2-E00C-4CC6-A77B-A76D60DA9F79</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_1FCD84C2-E00C-4CC6-A77B-A76D60DA9F79_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/45582973-8F00-41C2-D28A-F2676190A61A">
            <oc:name>2004 Overall Trench Plan2</oc:name>
            <oc:id>45582973-8F00-41C2-D28A-F2676190A61A</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_45582973-8F00-41C2-D28A-F2676190A61A_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/77AEB90B-38D6-4D7E-C3D9-211C5FD3FC8F">
            <oc:name>2005 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>77AEB90B-38D6-4D7E-C3D9-211C5FD3FC8F</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_77AEB90B-38D6-4D7E-C3D9-211C5FD3FC8F_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/34011111-A202-49B0-C026-F70B0B0D17B5">
            <oc:name>2005 Overall Trench Plan1</oc:name>
            <oc:id>34011111-A202-49B0-C026-F70B0B0D17B5</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_34011111-A202-49B0-C026-F70B0B0D17B5_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/17197EBF-FA77-4B60-A53B-CADFBE7152E7">
            <oc:name>2006 Aerial</oc:name>
            <oc:id>17197EBF-FA77-4B60-A53B-CADFBE7152E7</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_17197EBF-FA77-4B60-A53B-CADFBE7152E7_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/9047CD14-85F3-4790-EAF9-FD99D901EF20">
            <oc:name>2006 Overall Trench Plan</oc:name>
            <oc:id>9047CD14-85F3-4790-EAF9-FD99D901EF20</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Standard</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>image</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/importer/import_review/project_files/petra/thumbs/th_9047CD14-85F3-4790-EAF9-FD99D901EF20_jpg.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
        </oc:media_links>
        <oc:person_links>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/1EFB20BC-BE05-486A-C434-988892277ED5" cite="creator">
            <oc:name>Martha Sharp Joukowsky</oc:name>
            <oc:id>1EFB20BC-BE05-486A-C434-988892277ED5</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>Editor</oc:relation>
          </oc:link>
        </oc:person_links>
      </arch:links>
    </arch:observation>
  </arch:observations>
  <oc:context>
    <oc:tree id="default">
      <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D9AE02E5-C3F3-41D0-EB3A-39798F63GGGG">
        <oc:name>Jordan</oc:name>
        <oc:id>D9AE02E5-C3F3-41D0-EB3A-39798F63GGGG</oc:id>
        <oc:level>1</oc:level>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:parent>
    </oc:tree>
  </oc:context>
  <oc:children>
    <oc:tree id="default">
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E41A7A26-46FE-4CBE-DDCE-4FCB166C05FB">
        <oc:name>Lower Temenos</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E41A7A26-46FE-4CBE-DDCE-4FCB166C05FB</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/BB0C24AB-A6AB-471F-FB95-F37839047CE3">
        <oc:name>Propylaeum</oc:name>
        <oc:id>BB0C24AB-A6AB-471F-FB95-F37839047CE3</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/4ADC50BD-E55D-4421-131B-602196B6B89F">
        <oc:name>Surface</oc:name>
        <oc:id>4ADC50BD-E55D-4421-131B-602196B6B89F</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/A8E5E4D3-3FA6-444F-9F7E-00D6A2DE65F4">
        <oc:name>Temple</oc:name>
        <oc:id>A8E5E4D3-3FA6-444F-9F7E-00D6A2DE65F4</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/94AF0767-3B49-4727-F8DA-2427980EF719">
        <oc:name>Unprovenienced</oc:name>
        <oc:id>94AF0767-3B49-4727-F8DA-2427980EF719</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
      <oc:child href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/3B9F7885-FB53-4327-BEC3-08BD7615667E">
        <oc:name>Upper Temenos</oc:name>
        <oc:id>3B9F7885-FB53-4327-BEC3-08BD7615667E</oc:id>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:child>
    </oc:tree>
  </oc:children>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Petra Great Temple Excavations: Petra Great Temple (Site)</dc:title>
    <dc:date>2007-11-12</dc:date>
    <dc:coverage>Jordan</dc:coverage>
    <dc:creator>Martha Sharp Joukowsky</dc:creator>
    <dc:format>Text/HTML</dc:format>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:rights>Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Religion</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Hellenistic</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Jordan</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Roman</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Roman Empire</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Architecture</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Nabateans</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Nabatean</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Petra</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor>Martha Sharp Joukowsky</dc:contributor>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/subjects/D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name>Petra Great Temple Excavations</oc:project_name>
    <oc:primary_xsl>default/petra_area_spatial.xsl</oc:primary_xsl>
    <oc:pub_date>2007-11-12T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Petra%20Great%20Temple%20Excavations%3A%20Petra%20Great%20Temple%20%28Site%29&amp;rft.date=2007-11-12&amp;rft.creator=Martha%20Sharp%20Joukowsky&amp;rft.contributor=Martha%20Sharp%20Joukowsky&amp;rft.subject=Religion&amp;rft.subject=Hellenistic&amp;rft.subject=Jordan&amp;rft.subject=Roman&amp;rft.subject=Roman%20Empire&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.subject=Architecture&amp;rft.subject=Nabateans&amp;rft.subject=Nabatean&amp;rft.subject=Petra&amp;rft.format=Text%2FHTML&amp;rft.coverage=Jordan&amp;rft.language=eng&amp;rft.publisher=&amp;rft.source=Open%20Context&amp;rft.rights=Creative%20Commons%20Attribution%203.0&amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.opencontext.org%2Fsubjects%2FD9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4</oc:coins>
    <oc:no_props>This item has no descriptive properties associated with it yet.&#xD;
It may have been lumped with another item. Check for the containing context for related items.</oc:no_props>
    <oc:copyright_lic>
      <oc:lic_name>Creative Commons Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3.0</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>30.3287</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>35.4421</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4">
        <oc:source_name>Petra Great Temple</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
      <gml:Polygon>
        <gml:exterior>
          <gml:LinearRing>
            <gml:posList>30.32897096092139 35.44197849995533 30.32864806294793 35.44191233632192 30.32859666913463 35.44204562004059 30.32818104863834 35.44197384838523 30.32811658622153 35.44256934183349 30.32875721959696 35.44267392175537 30.32878559835931 35.4425244602625 30.32881360884527 35.44219170209237 30.32894262340953 35.44220636200033 30.32897096092139 35.44197849995533</gml:posList>
          </gml:LinearRing>
        </gml:exterior>
      </gml:Polygon>
    </oc:geo_reference>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2008-11-01T22:32:13Z</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>370</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>August 14, 2008, 11:57AM</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(200 BCE - 360 CE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-200</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>360</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4">
            <oc:source_name>Petra Great Temple</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>D9AE02E5-C3F1-41D0-EB3A-39798F63F6C4</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2008-08-11T21:45:49Z</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:spatialUnit>
