<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:spatialUnit xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/SpatialUnit/SpatialUnit.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/space_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" UUID="1A2FC648-C547-4538-9434-689C7FA7492A" ownedBy="3FAAA477-5572-4B05-8DC1-CA264FE1FC10">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>SDAC 431</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <oc:item_class>
    <oc:name>Reference Collection</oc:name>
    <oc:iconURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/collection_trays_50x50.jpg</oc:iconURI>
  </oc:item_class>
  <arch:observations>
    <arch:observation obsNumber="1">
      <arch:links>
        <arch:docID type="resource" info="link">2BCFC4EF-F7C9-460E-B24A-7C7D189A6FA4</arch:docID>
        <oc:media_links>
          <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/media/2BCFC4EF-F7C9-460E-B24A-7C7D189A6FA4">
            <oc:name>P37-029476 Report</oc:name>
            <oc:id>2BCFC4EF-F7C9-460E-B24A-7C7D189A6FA4</oc:id>
            <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
            <oc:type>acrobat pdf</oc:type>
            <oc:path/>
            <oc:filename/>
            <oc:thumbnailURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/oc_icons/sm_document_icon.jpg</oc:thumbnailURI>
          </oc:link>
        </oc:media_links>
      </arch:links>
      <arch:notes>
        <arch:note>
          <arch:string>&lt;p&gt;&#13;
The project area falls within the Coastal Zone and the Mission Hills Community Planning Area, &#13;
City  of  San  Diego,  California.    Specifically,  the  project  site  is  located  in  the  800  Block  of Washington Street and is bounded by Falcon Street to the east, Fort Stockton Street to the north, and Goldfinch Street to the west (APN 444-414-04 through 11) in the Mission Hills community of San Diego, California.   The project  comprised  rehabilitating  some of  the  commercial  space &#13;
fronting  on Washington  Street  as well  as  constructing  a multistory  affordable  living  complex with subterranean parking on the 51,130 square foot lot. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
The  City  of  San  Diego,  acting  as  the  Lead  Agency  under  the  California  Environmental  Act (CEQA),  issued  a  Mitigated  Negative  Declaration  (MND)  for  the  project  (No.  40292)  that required a Mitigation Monitoring and Reporting Program (MMRP) for cultural resources.   ICF Jones and  Stokes was  contracted  by  Paseo  de Mission Hills,  LLC  to  provide  cultural  resource &#13;
monitoring  services. Construction  monitoring  was  conducted  in  two  phases,  Phase  I  on &#13;
November 14, 2006 and Phase II from March 31 to April 14, 2008.  ICF Jones and Stokes Senior &#13;
Archaeologist Robert P. Case, RPA, served as Principal Investigator, monitor, and report author.   Associate  Archaeologists  Andrea  Craft  and  Joshua  Patterson  served  as  field  monitors  while Michael  DeGiovine  assisted  with  the  excavation  and  recording  of  Feature  1.    Carol  J.  Serr &#13;
directed the laboratory processing and authored a portion of the report. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
Mitigation monitoring was performed in two stages dictated by the construction plans.  The first &#13;
stage  of  construction  was  restricted  to  the Washington  Street  frontage  where  the  respective corner building would undergo rehabilitation but  the central building would be demolished and replaced by new commercial construction.  Upon the removal of construction debris, ICF Jones and Stokes personnel monitored the excavation of shallow trenches for foundations and utilities on November 14, 2006.  No cultural resources were detected. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
The second stage of construction occurred in the major portion of the APE.  ICF Jones and Stokes &#13;
personnel monitored these excavation activities from March 31 to April 14, 2008.  All buildings &#13;
and hardscape had been previously removed. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
An alignment of mortared bricks was  identified  in  the back yard of 4035 Goldfinch.   This was &#13;
the only  archaeological  feature  identified during  the  course  of monitoring  although  occasional isolated historic artifacts were  recovered by  the monitors and  taken  to  the  ICF Jones and Stokes laboratory for cleaning and identification.   &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
The  brick  feature  ultimately  proved  to  be  a  very  elaborate  septic  system  consisting  of  a  large western compartment, measuring 9 feet 2 inches (E-W) by 4 feet (N-S), connected by an 8-inch pipe  to  a  smaller  eastern  compartment  measuring  4  feet  (E-W)  by  4  feet  5  inches  (N-S).  Excavation of  the eastern compartment produced six historic artifacts  including a whole patent medicine bottle and half of a fragmented interior-glazed yellow ware cooking pot.  The western compartment produced seven fragmentary  items.   And  three  isolates was also recovered during general construction monitoring. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
The  total  recovered  assemblage  contains  6  glass  items,  4  ceramic,  2  metal,  2  composite materials,  and  2  faunal  items.    Functionally,  these  were  categorized  as  7  kitchen  items,  5 consumer containers, 2 household objects, 1 building material item, and 1 other item. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt; &#13;
No  prehistoric  cultural  resources  were  encountered  during  the  course  of  the  mitigation monitoring of undisturbed native soil for the Paseo de Mission Hills Affordable Housing project.  One  historical  resource,  a  septic  system  (P-37-029476),  was  thoroughly  recorded  during  its removal; the amount of recording performed on the resource exhausted its research potential and reduced project effects to the resource to less than significant.  Additionally, monitors collected the small amount of temporally and functionally sensitive historic artifacts present that reflect the early  decades  of  the  community.    The  field  and  laboratory work  has  been  documented  in  an updated site  record as well as  this  technical  report.   The cultural assemblage and  its associated documentation  have  been  legally  transferred  to  the  San  Diego  Archaeological  Center  as stipulated in the MMRP. &#13;
&lt;/p&gt;</arch:string>
        </arch:note>
      </arch:notes>
    </arch:observation>
  </arch:observations>
  <oc:context>
    <oc:tree id="default">
      <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/4_global_USA">
        <oc:name>United States</oc:name>
        <oc:id>4_global_USA</oc:id>
        <oc:level>2</oc:level>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:parent>
      <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/8_global_Cal">
        <oc:name>California</oc:name>
        <oc:id>8_global_Cal</oc:id>
        <oc:level>1</oc:level>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>http://www.opencontext.org/database/ui_images/oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
      </oc:parent>
    </oc:tree>
  </oc:context>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>San Diego Archaeological Center: SDAC 431 (Reference Collection)</dc:title>
    <dc:date>2010-02-23</dc:date>
    <dc:creator>San Diego Archaeological Center</dc:creator>
    <dc:subject>historical archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>San Diego</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>California</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Spanish colonial</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Mexican</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>finds catalog</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>education</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>cultural resource management</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>archaeological collections</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/subjects/1A2FC648-C547-4538-9434-689C7FA7492A</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3FAAA477-5572-4B05-8DC1-CA264FE1FC10">San Diego Archaeological Center</oc:project_name>
    <oc:primary_xsl>default/</oc:primary_xsl>
    <oc:sourceID>z_7_LYX425626</oc:sourceID>
    <oc:pub_date>2010-02-23T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=San%20Diego%20Archaeological%20Center%3A%20SDAC%20431%20%28Reference%20Collection%29&amp;rft.date=2010-02-23&amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fsubjects%2F1A2FC648-C547-4538-9434-689C7FA7492A</oc:coins>
    <oc:no_props>No properties</oc:no_props>
    <oc:copyright_lic>
      <oc:lic_name>Creative Commons Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3.0</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>33.0986</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>-117.005</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1A2FC648-C547-4538-9434-689C7FA7492A">
        <oc:source_name>SDAC 431</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>1A2FC648-C547-4538-9434-689C7FA7492A</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2010-02-23T00:00:07Z</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2010/02/23 00:00:07</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:spatialUnit>
