<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="00E0FA3F-4306-489B-9856-B4F74064E7F8" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-6-2002-08-024-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>38FD4DF5-54B0-45FD-B78C-DF2409346248</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7575A054-4130-4112-8F51-A0B2DEA78FC4">7575A054-4130-4112-8F51-A0B2DEA78FC4</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002-08-24</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719">
        <oc:name>Trench 6</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-6-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench D6 Final Summary	     August 24, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Baris Uzel, Drew McGaraghan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Introduction:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench D6 was started on July 3, 2002 directly South of Trench D4. This is on the Southern slope of the main mound of Kenan Tepe. The reasoning behind this placement was to capture views of the continuations of surface and architecture found in D4 during the 2001 season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As expected, we found many surfaces with architecture that we could directly link to D4. Unexpectedly, however, we immediately found a large 7 chambered (5 main chambers, 2 "auxiliary") furnace just under the topsoil in the NW quarter of the trench. As work continued, the furnace grew in proportion and complexity, with many associated features and surfaces, and although it was found in excellent condition, it did not provide many easy answers. It also proved to be extremely slow to excavate, because of the care required for a find of it’s importance, and also because of the nature of the beast itself. When fully exposed, it stood over a meter and a half tall, and made for extremely cramped and precarious working positions. We spent the entire season exposing this feature and its associates, and the other work we did in our trench (the Southern ½) was mainly for relief and to learn about the upcoming features in section. The western baulk was drawn at the end of the season, and we followed the standard closing procedures regarding the removal of features surfaces as best we could. This meant removal of the furnace and associated walls, and cleaning of the adjacent surfaces. Next years team will find a complex setup awaiting them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Excavation Notes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We excavated L20 and the surrounding contexts with as much care as we could with the time and resources that we had. We took several hundred photographs of this region and saved about ½ of the material as samples for microanalysis and other research. We did not sift any material at all as the material we were looking for would easily be missed by such field techniques (small metal flakes), instead relying on the volume of the samples collected. We worked with two dayplans, one for the overall trench, and the other focusing on the North West corner. We documented the location of at least 90% of the slag we found with elevations and on the dayplans. Upon final removal of the furnace structure, we brought photographs to the field, and marked on the photographs the location of each KT. These photographs can be found as dayplans on the dates of August 17, 18, and 19. Also note that all elevations were taken off the datum ~8m South and a little west of the SW corner of D6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our strategy focused on revealing as much of L20 and its related features at once so we could better understand the context as a whole (this context was frequently referred to as the L20 complex, and included the loci 20, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 6, 5, 14, 47, 48). After we had accomplished this we began by removing the unorganized structural debri. As we were working we cut many sounding/section loci to preview the upcoming contexts. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Furnace (L20 complex):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L20 (started as L2) is the structure (walls and later "pillars") of the large 1.3 by 1 x 1 meter tall 5 chambered furnace that is pottery dated to ~1800 BCE. The eastern walls of this structure continue down into a large pit just to its East. We realized late the nature of this pit and included these lower portions of L20 as the Western walls of the pit itself. Similar progression happened elsewhere and so the large pit is defined by L20 (mixed), L6 (mixed) and L5, which consists of the Eastern wall of this pit. This pit will be described as "pit 20/6/5". Also note that the Loci 24, 25, 26, 27, and 28 refer to the contents (fill) inside the individual chambers, and that 21, 22, and 23 are buffer/buttress loci designated for excavation purposes rather than material differentiation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The structure of L20 itself consisted of a heavy earth and stone wall forming a gentle curve in the west. From this jumbled wall extended 6 brick lined walls, the interior 4 extending directly east (more or less) and the outer 2 following the curve of the back wall before running parallel with the others. The two larger interior chambers consisted of large pillars built of mudbrick walls with very hard packed interior fill. Large pieces of pottery were set into this fill at a moderate eastward angle. These areas did not show any exposure to heat, and their purpose is still a good mystery. Throughout this construction, a general pattern revealed itself. It appears some areas of the furnace were considered more critical than others, and that they were carefully constructed of shaped bricks. Others areas were built of jumbles of rock and earth. In many cases large rocks float in a matrix of soil rather than set on other rocks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L6 was first noted as debri to the North of L20. As we excavated this debri we noted strange orange yellow debris which gradually became clear to be a wall made of very hard friable earth which appeared to have been cooked at high temperature. We excavated the debri from L6, and eventually followed it into the pit 20/6/5. We did not notice any distinct breaks in this debri, but rather a continuous jumble of varying qualities. This leaves L6 as define as 3 entities, which will be separated by description. "L6 wall" is the Northwestern wall to the pit L20/6/5. "L6 debri" is the unconsolidated debri starting near the top of L6 and continuing and filling the Northern arm of the pit L20/6/5. Finally, as we were excavating, the debris resolved into a small single chamber furnace with slag coated walls, which will be referred to as "L6 chamber". The foundation line (and some mudbricks) provided a direct link between L6 and L20, showing them to be the same structure. Much of the material making up the varied parts of L20 was very subtly differentiated, and the timeline in which we excavated it led in part to the confusion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L5 was first noted as a hard line across the surface of L30. Excavation revealed it to be a very hard friable wall partially covered in slag, very similar to wall L6. We later realized it was in fact the edge of a large pit that had been hardened by heat and material. At this point the nature of L6 and L20 also became clear. It is interesting to note that despite the direct connection between L6, L5, and L20, there is no direct join. Instead the walls are offset to overshoot each other slightly. This may possibly be an air intake, as the gap is only about 10 cm wide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L14 is a small single chamber furnace to the South (with slag coated interior). It later became clear that in at least one rebuilding this was open (ie, only it’s Southern wall existed). This wall joins cleanly with L20, and the foundation line clearly showed these to once have been parts of the same structure. L14 also contains the South western part of the walls of the pit L20/6/5.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L29, L44 and L50 comprise the contents of pit L20/6/5. We excavated L29 about 4cm at a time continuing down almost 1.20 m before determining that we were below the bottom of the furnace L20. Near this elevation to the North we found a new surface (L54) under the debri in L6 and a mudbrick divider/wall (L55). Note that the slag stopped on the West walls of the pit L20/6/5 at about 1 meter below surface 17. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We designated L44 after noticing a color shift in the pit baulk below L14. It appeared that the North wall of L14 might continue downward. Upon excavation, however, we discovered the material in L44 was the same jumble as we found in L29. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L50 is another locus that consists of the jumbled mudbrick fill first found in L29. It was originally underneath the eastmost walls of L26, 27, and 28. The part directly under L27 and 28 was excavated and the more northerly portion was left for next year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L10 was first found as a 2 course 1 row wall just to the south of the back (west) wall of L20. It continues in a southwest arc into the west baulk. As we removed the back wall of L20 we noted that it continues through about half of the back wall of L20, although a very large (40 cm) flagstone was found abutting the actual join with the furnace.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L16 is a wall that appears to align with L10 about half a meter North of the back wall of L20. It continues the same general arc as L10, and is composed of about the same materials. It is good to note that the upper courses of each of these walls consists of large stones set on (in some areas) smaller stones and then hard mudbrick like material, After a few cm of this material both walls set on the surfaces L17 and L30. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L17 and L30 are two sections of the same surface. This surface has a general tendency to slope downward to the South and East (as do other surfaces in D6) these surfaces make up the foundation for L20, 14, 6, 16, 10.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L47 is a small curving wall extending from the NW corner of L20. It’s purpose has not been fully explored yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L48 is a large pile of rocks under L47. Although we can only see about half a square meter of it, it appears to be the terminus of a large row heading off to the west. Again, we do not have much to work with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Other associations:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The surface L17 continues all the way across D6, and towards the South we found a pile/surface of large (~20cm) stones focused around a large conglomerate. This feature consisted of basalts, sandstones, and other large rocks (~20cm) in a very similar manner to what has been referred to as the Kenan Tepe rock garden, previously found in area C.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L35 consists of a large conglomerate piece that abuts the wall of L5. I do not include it as one of the principle characters as it is ~20 cm below the main action (based on surfaceL17) and because we did not excavate down to its related surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Theories:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The L20 complex is currently believed to be a bronze/copper/tin smelting furnace. The sheer amount (maybe 20 kilos) of slag found supports this. It may also have been a pottery kiln or was built for some other furnace, as its possible the slag simply leeched from the building materials used. The varieties of slag found combined with the type of material it was found on (mudbricks of many colors, pottery, earthen walls, stone) seem to refute this. It seems unlikely that such a variety of materials could produce such a consistent volume of like material (slag). That being said, we did find at least four main varieties of slag. 1. Bright green and drippy 2. Dull green and crackled 3. Black with big drips. 4. Grey green with small eddies and drips. We did not have much time to thoroughly examine all the slag however, forgive the rough description.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the time of writing it is currently believed that the L20 complex actually represents at least two phases of construction/reconstruction. The debri in the pit L20/6/5 contained many layers of slag and mudbricks of varying size and composition. This seems to indicate multiple structures are represented in this collapse. Also, the side chambers L6 and L14 both consisted of a small chamber contained within a U shaped wall. These chambers were then sitting on debri inside L20/6/5. When we finally removed all structures the foundation line showed a shallow arc that did not include the south wall of chamber L6 or the north wall of L14 (the "interior walls"). The current theory is that there were two building phases, the first more open and utilizing the entire large pit, and the second more compartmentalized and less deep. This is supported by the slag, which from continuous drips in areas that would have been filled if the interior walls existed. The other option would be that these interior walls are false, and composed of tumble and debri. The slag on these walls was correctly oriented, however, and does not support this. This general theory might be applied to the main furnace itself, as the extensions to chambers 25, 26 and 27 also continued out onto areas of debri. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pit L20/6/5 was bordered by a broken wall to the east (L5). It is possible that the northern, more narrow end might have been used as the fuel (wood, for this time period) input for the earlier phase of the furnace. I’m not sure how the spacing would have worked on the later, more divided variant. The east wall L5 does not quite join with L6, and these gaps may have been air intakes. Also found during excavation was a soft spot in the hard baked coating of L5 that was being used by a mouse as a passage. This hole only measures about 8 cm in diameter, so perhaps may have been used as a bellows hole or to add small amount of catalysts/ingredients.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The whole of this area is divided by the walls L10 and L16. Neither surface 30 or 17 crosses the boundary of these walls, and the material inside is made up of hard mudbricks, which we missed while excavating but show up in the section. We believe that the furnace possibly set against the outer wall of some building or maybe terrace. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Others&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The southern half of D6 revealed many surfaces and jumbled features. It is interesting to note that the lower surface L37 followed the same boundary (set by wall L10) as the upper surface L17. One theory set out was that the use period for the L20 complex was not very long, and that perhaps the 10cm difference between L17 and L30 could have occurred within the space of a few years, or even a season. We found slag and a metal piece about halfway across floor 37.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We cut several sections down in the southeast corner finding many stone groupings and evidence of many new surfaces. We found many artifacts in this area, including a large stone "bowl", an animal figurine, and a nice grindstone (almost worn out).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We did not have a lot of time to thoroughly explore this area however, and most of the architecture we found was very jumbled and confusing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-6-2002-08-024-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/00E0FA3F-4306-489B-9856-B4F74064E7F8</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-6-2002-08-024-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F00E0FA3F-4306-489B-9856-B4F74064E7F8</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830535</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813647</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/00E0FA3F-4306-489B-9856-B4F74064E7F8">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 6</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>00E0FA3F-4306-489B-9856-B4F74064E7F8</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:20:07-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:20:07</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
