<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="01EC2A99-EA4B-4FE4-E09C-1CB6C1BA1397" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-5-2005-06-010-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>2B8165AC-B7CA-4BAC-0FC6-71A0C4424836</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/4BC66A5D-B1C5-4954-20A1-9813E91A90B4">4BC66A5D-B1C5-4954-20A1-9813E91A90B4</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-10</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="person" info="Recorded by">9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4">
        <oc:name>Trench 5</oc:name>
        <oc:id>5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:person_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F" cite="contributor">
        <oc:name/>
        <oc:id>9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Recorded by</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:person_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-5-2005-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Final Trench Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D. Trench 5.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;D 5 is a continuation of the 10 x 5m trench last excavated in the 2002 season on the eastern slope of Kenan Tepe. At the end of the 2002 season the trench was divided along north-south lines with excavated features of Ubaid domestic architecture (including L5139, L5140, L5149) and an oven (L5126, L5127) in the southern section. However, there were a limited number of features in the northern section, except for a human burial (L5137) in a later pit in a slip trench in the northwestern area. At the beginning of the 2004 season there was an expectation that these Ubaid features might overlie an earlier phase of habitation in the form of a separate house and that the northern section of the trench might also provide additional Ubaid contexts with further excavation. To further investigate these possibilities a new parallel 6 x 4m trench, D9, was also opened to the east of D5 aiming to capture any continuation of the Ubaid contexts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Summary of the excavations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The primary method of excavation was by the use of small picks to strip 3-5cm increments of material from tightly designated areas with troweling employed during the fine excavation of surfaces and features. Where possible each surface was also sampled following guidelines set out in the Kenan Tepe Household Archaeology Protocol.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On average, during the 2004 season the level of the trench was lowered to 586.13m in the northern section of the trench and 586.52m in the southern section from average starting levels of 586.8m and 587.15. However, in the last three days of the season a 1 x 1m sounding (5202, 5203, 5204) was excavated in the southwestern corner of D5 with a final level of 585.31. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a guide the northern and eastern baulk sections provided an idea of the orientation of the paleo-landscape of the eastern side of the Tepe - pronounced ashy layers in the northern baulk and a layer of gravel in the eastern section that makes a sharp dip downward at approximately the 2m mark from the northern baulk. The ancient slope of the hill ran in a generally southwest to the northeast direction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result of this it will probably be more useful to summarize the excavations in D5 by dividing the trench into a southern, a central and a northern section. The main reason for this is that the ashy layers in the northern baulk section showed as a blackish line running northwest-southeast across the trench. As the excavation continued from south to north we were therefore progressing "downhill" in stages. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The southern section of D5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This section was characterized by thick layers of fill (5164, 5167, 5190) between the 2002 contexts and significant features especially in the southwestern section of the trench. During troweling it was possible to distinguish boundaries in this fill through consistency and compactness of material leading to the hypothesis that this area had been artificially leveled in advance of the construction of the 2002 Ubaid house. These fill levels were contained by wall 5170 that followed the orientation of the 2002 west-east wall although this feature had only a thin horizontal slice remaining and was not connected by any mud brick courses to the wall above.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although the Ubaid domestic context had been divided into interior and exterior areas in the 2002 season the 2004 excavation revealed a number of floor surfaces (5169, 5185, 5194) that were initially considered to be interconnected. These were different from the compacted silt surfaces of the 2002 season in that they were readily visible as compacted silt and pebble layers and the overlying fill could be slowly levered off with a trowel. Although floor 5169 in the southwestern section was relatively level in terms of the orientation of the trench both 5194 and 5185 sloped from west to east into the baulk shared with D9. During excavation it was also noted that 5185 bonded with wall 5170 but that this wall overlaid 5169.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the southeastern corner of the trench the Ubaid contexts were cut both by the edge of the oven found in trench D9 and by a mud brick lined pit (5180) both of which were later period.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There was therefore no clear evidence of an earlier Ubaid structure, although the surfaces, pits, layers of fill and wall suggested the 2002 house had gone through a number of construction phases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the lack of evidence for a separate house it was decided to test the hypothesis that the 2002 house was resting on virgin soil and a sounding (5202, 5203 and 5204) was dug in the southwestern corner of the trench to a depth of 1.3m below the final locus level (5197). However, as well as continued pottery finds, in the eastern section of the sounding pieces of mud brick showed through between 75 and 80cm below the level of 5197 and two pieces of corrugated tile (KT2, 5204) were recovered from the lowest level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The central section of D5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The preliminary dominant feature in this area was the oven excavated in 2002 as a tripartite structure – a central core (5156), a surround of fill (5155) and a hemispherical section of mud outer-walling (5157). Although the oven had been proxy dated to the Ubaid from a spatially adjacent feature’s carbon sample a surface scrape of the central core immediately showed two potsherds that implied that the oven might be later. The central core was therefore excavated as a series of layers (5171, 5173, 5178) that were derived from a section cut from the front of the feature (5172) and pottery and carbon samples collected for analysis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although 5157 contained mud brick debris the oven structure in trench D9 provided an outline of how a later oven might be preserved in section with a thick beehive of ashy material and distinct mud brick layers for the surrounding containing wall. The eastern baulk section for the D5 feature showed that the central core was the active element of the tripartite structure and it was not clear whether there was a surrounding ashy fill that had been contained within a constructed outer shell. The excavation of the fill surrounding the core suggested that this material was similar in color and consistency to fill encountered in other areas of the trench and not primarily ashy. Having excavated all the features of the oven a circular indentation was noted that identified locus 5191 as a pit. The hypothesis was therefore that the oven was actually the central core area alone and had been built onto or into an earlier pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the western section there were a number of indicators that this area had been used as an activity area in the Ubaid period (5174, 5198). Firstly, it underlay the chaff-covered surface from the 2002 season and abutted wall 5181. Secondly, as the excavation proceeded it followed a south-north slope identified by flat-lying sherds and a complete decorated cooking vessel (KT40, 5174) and a smoothed stone (KT8, 5199) under which grain impressions were preserved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As more concrete proof a thick layer of rocks, 1.5 x 1.1m in area, embedded in compacted silty material was excavated and HAP sampled. This contrasted sharply with the floors in the southern section of the trench in area and description of material within the silt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The northern section of the trench&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The aim in the this area of the trench was to excavate beneath the thick ashy layer noted in the northern baulk section and to assess whether this layer provided a useful stratigraphic indicator of the boundary between the Ubaid and later periods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two walls, one below and one resting on the ashy layer were noted toward the end of the season. 5183 rested on the ashy layer and was associated with Chalcolithic pottery (KT9, 5199). 5201 was only visible in plan except in the half-section of pit 5201 where mud brick outlines were recorded beneath the ashy layer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A notable find in the northeastern corner of the trench was an inscribed cylinder seal or bead (KT10, 5182) inscribed in a zigzag pattern in two registers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Interpretation of the results of the season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Although there are limited opportunities to discuss dating a general summary of hypotheses could be put forward. The southern section of the trench revealed interior features that were part of an earlier phase (or phases) of the 2002 house that were then covered with fill to provide a level base for later occupation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Associated with this is the hypothesis that the activity area in the central section of the trench, exterior to the house, was also used before the chaff-covered surface of the 2002. However, it seems unlikely that the cooking vessel and the smooth stone grinding surface would be abandoned, although any ritual explanation would be hard to argue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The later pits and the oven along the eastern side of the trench imply that this area is associated with trench D9 rather than with the Ubaid and again it is worth considering the slope of the ancient hill which may have moved further eastwards over time. Therefore during the Ubaid the side of the hill may have been more flush with the 2002 house and then, having been filled in over time, employed in a more "industrial" capacity in later periods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another possibility connected with the slope of the hill is that wall 5201 in the northern section of the trench may act as a retaining wall rather than in any domestic context and, if Ubaid in date, be associated with the exterior activity area to the north of the 2002 house.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The results of the excavation in D5 in the 2004 season have therefore been determined by the transformation of the shape of the hill in requiring the leveling of areas in earlier periods and the shaping of the Tepe by human occupation that allowed new areas to be exploited.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-5-2005-06-010-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor href="http://opencontext.org/persons/9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F"/>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/01EC2A99-EA4B-4FE4-E09C-1CB6C1BA1397</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-5-2005-06-010-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.contributor=&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F01EC2A99-EA4B-4FE4-E09C-1CB6C1BA1397</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830708</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813714</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/01EC2A99-EA4B-4FE4-E09C-1CB6C1BA1397">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 5</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>01EC2A99-EA4B-4FE4-E09C-1CB6C1BA1397</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:03:12-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:03:12</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
