<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="0746472D-0FE6-4881-C777-9E9FE7C3D782" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-8-2004-07-026-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>BEF191FC-E9F0-474D-C54A-0AFD87AF098D</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/F1974596-98D7-4E60-1E96-C8F2B105E029">F1974596-98D7-4E60-1E96-C8F2B105E029</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2004-07-26</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2004</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/E5BF187C-B64A-46CA-AB1F-61ADB92DDACA">E5BF187C-B64A-46CA-AB1F-61ADB92DDACA</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2004</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB">
        <oc:name>Trench 8</oc:name>
        <oc:id>A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-8-2004-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary, Year 2004 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 26, 2004&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;E.O.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the trench summary for Trench D8 for the 2004 season. D8 is a new trench this year. It is situated to the south of D5 and east, or downhill from D6 and D7. This trench was intended to be a ten by five meter trench. The grid lines are somewhat off what the overall tepe grid scheme would indicate. this is because the south D5 balk has been creeping back every season and if we had strung the D8 balk lines where the total station indicated they should be the balk between the two trenches would have been very thin which would have risked the lives of everyone in D5 because the trench is so deep. Because of this we used the total station lines as a guide and strung the trench so that there is a full meter balk between D8 and D5. This means that we took the full meter of balk room off of the north side of the trench so the south balk line lies directly on the grid lines. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because this was a brand new trench we spent the first three days just getting the trench ready and moving topsoil. We started in the northwest corner of the trench which was the point of highest elevation. The topsoil was removed in curved sections. These topsoil loci were tailored to the curvature and slant of the tepe. On July 4, the first day of digging, we divided the whole trench into three sections which would be the steps. Loci 1, 2, and 3 were that first step. There are multiple loci because we were adjusting the balk lines and each adjustment necessitated an additional locus. Loci 4 was a rock area that disappeared into the west balk and L5 was the second step. the third step was topsoil and we did not assign it a loci number because we knew we had a lot to do before we reached that level, as it turned out the south east corner of the trench is still topsoil. Loci 4, originally the rock pit soon became a long column of rock and broken pottery which was changed to loci 6 with loci 7 the area south of it in the first step and L3 continuing in the first step to the north of L6. L6 was a wash or drainage ditch. It disappeared midway through the first step. Though there was a lot of pottery in this locus it was so close to topsoil that there was really no good context for it. overall the first step was brought down a full meter and a half from the height of the north west corner (590.11) to the closing level of Loci 7 and 3 (588.66.) The loci were changed because under the wash material of L6 we found a cobbled surface (L9.) This cobbled surface continued north but made a straight edge at what had been the south border of L6 now the north border of L11 (previously L7.) L10 was the soil that still remained on the cobbled floor. On July 10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; we found an area of mudbrick in the north east corner of the trench. The mudbrick turned out to be a corner of a building which makes a square with the balk lines of the trench. This wall (L14) existed in both steps of trench. There is an artificial line through one of the rows of bricks which was made by our excavation methods as opposed to any architectural feature of the wall. L13 was part of another cobbled surface which had been on top of L9 which we found when we were straightening the very crooked balk. The section we found was approx 40cm square. L12 was a third step which we created within the boundaries of what had been L5 but also extended out further to the east and south taking some topsoil with it. L15 was designated as the area inside of wall L14 and is a rectangular area in the very northeast corner of the trench. Within L12 a large area of rock which we originally thought might be a pit became L16. L16 turned out not to be a pit and is designated as a feature. For a few days we continued with these loci using picks to move as much dirt as we could. In many areas we were still in top soil or sub topsoil. The next discovery was some mudbrick in the south west corner. This area of mudbrick, L17 is a wall which is still in the trench. The construction of this wall (brick size ect.) seems to match that of wall L14. However they are on opposite sides of the trench. To the south of L17 between the edge of L17 and the south balk there was an area that appeared to be made of burned mudbrick with an ash pit in it. To the north of L17 more brick material was found. When we finally excavated this area (L22,) it became clear that this was mudbrick slump most likely from wall L17. When we had the floor L9 completely uncovered we could see a very clear line where the floor ended. This straight edge of the floor butted up against what appeared to be another wall. This area (L19) appeared to be wall and was sandwiched between L9 and L14. At first this was puzzling but when we excavated L19 we found that it was not an entire wall. The only wall area was directly up against the floor (wall L34.) L19 was mudbrick slump mixed with pottery which was both on top of L34 and between it and L14. We had placed a sounding L31 running east west through L19 and part of L14 to figure this out. We discovered another wall at the south border of the floor. This had been loci 11 but was changed to L23 for the wall and L24 as the fill to the south. There was an undefined area between Loci 19, 9 and 23 which was L18 and then 7cm deeper L25. With all of the areas around the floor fully assigned and documented we removed L9. Uncovering, documenting, and then removing L9 was a time consuming process. We took a HAP sample from this Locus. This is also one of the only loci whose pottery was read and the floor turned out to be 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium though there were several pieces of type 7 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;rd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium high fire green/yellow in there. L9’s sub floor was soil (L26.) We were going through L26 with small picks because the soil was so hard packed and because of this we missed part of another floor L28 which was under it. L28 was the floor which we found in the southern half of the area which had been L26. L29 was the sub floor which we hit in the northern part of that same area. In L24 we found what first appeared to be a pit (L30.) this locus was much softer than the surrounding soil. This pit butted up against Wall L23 and by taking it down we were exposing the south side of wall L23 which was needed because though the material felt like brick we could not find definite brick lines. There had also been an area of very fine and soft soil (L27) to the north of wall L23 which was fill up against the wall. L24 became L32 after we hit the pit. We also opened up L33 which was the remains of the second step from the original excavation. The purpose of taking this down was to even out the trench so we wouldn’t have as many arbitrary breaks and steps. However before we could accomplish this we hit two areas of cobbled surface L41 and L47. There appeared to be part of the same floor though there were separated by over a meter of space. The sub floor of both of these loci was visible. The sub floor (L46) is large paving stones. There appears to be a line where the bricks stop near the eastern edge of L30. Through a succession of loci (32, 42, 45 and 48) the area south of L30 was brought down to the same level as that of L46. Because the floor was not contiguous we could not follow it. So we decided to follow the sub floor bricks (L46) to see if they would connect L14 to L17. L46 is connected to wall L23 and we found parts of floor L41 touching wall L14 At one point we had decided to remove wall L23 and as we were taking it out we found defined bricks. These bricks appear to be construction like that of L17 and L14. We were most likely looking at hard mudbrick slump on top of the wall. In the balk we can clearly see the triangular shape of the slump. It appears that L23 slumped on top pf L30. To follow the bricks we had to take out L16 and as we were doing that we hit L49 which was a cache of large pieces of broken pottery and one pedestal piece. We had been trying to follow the brick lines of L46 on the last day of excavation but we were prevented from doing so by finding L49 In the northwest corner of the trench another wall is visible as lines. This wall does not line up (either perpendicularly or parallel) with Wall L14 or 23. One part of this wall touches L14, it does not touch L23. L34 was on top of this so it is unlikely that this wall and its associated surfaces (L43 inside, L35 and 38 outside) are connected with L14 and its associates. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	With what we have currently excavated it looks like Walls 14, 17 and 23 all go together. They are connected by the sub floor L46. L30 which at one point appeared to be a pit is actually fill inside a room. L23 is the northern wall of this room. There are two more walls (east and south) which are currently visible only as lines. It is unclear if wall 34 and floor L9 which go with one another go with the rest of the currently visible architecture. At the beginning of next season the first thing that we should do is to thoroughly clean the entire stretch between the walls to make sure of their connection. The large pits that were created by the excavation of L16 and 49 will hamper this somewhat but it will still be possible. The most notable finds from this trench were several animal figurines. One which came out of L15 was found right up against the wall and still retains its head, and appears to be a cow or ram. There were also a large number of fishnet weights and in L16 two grinding stones. Overall there was not a lot of household items which may suggest that the majority of the trench is a non workspace, possible a street or area between buildings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note: Final Trench plan saved as July 22 B &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-8-2004-07-026-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/0746472D-0FE6-4881-C777-9E9FE7C3D782</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-8-2004-07-026-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F0746472D-0FE6-4881-C777-9E9FE7C3D782</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830596</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813717</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/0746472D-0FE6-4881-C777-9E9FE7C3D782">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 8</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>0746472D-0FE6-4881-C777-9E9FE7C3D782</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:13:07-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:13:07</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
