<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="07971F38-3FEA-481A-0F1F-0D54D5A5AACB" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-8-2005-05-021-Weekly</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>FABC613D-55D6-4924-C12A-C8ABDCB92351</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188">6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Weekly</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>22397D29-2307-4434-6EB9-5834E7D649E5</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/D494B455-75AE-4EDA-72F4-D8A73D9613E0">D494B455-75AE-4EDA-72F4-D8A73D9613E0</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-05-21</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="person" info="Recorded by">B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB">
        <oc:name>Trench 8</oc:name>
        <oc:id>A887ED68-9819-42EF-0C0D-7756F42212EB</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:person_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C" cite="contributor">
        <oc:name>JW</oc:name>
        <oc:id>B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Recorded by</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:person_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;May 21-16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Week 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This week was my first full week of excavation in this trench. For the most part what we did this week was move though layers of fill. We did have some non fill loci come up but none were particularly interesting and most were taken out the same day that they were found. The most interesting find of this week was the baby burial. How the baby was buried is one of the interesting things that were discussed this week. The material that made up the ‘casing’ which the body was in was not plaster as previously thought it was simply harder packed mud. While it is very interesting we determined that nothing could be gained by removing it in sections and doing a float sample on it. If it is just a hard packed mud it is likely that it was mud made from the soil nearby or from the Tigris and therefore there would not be chips of stone or bone which would give us information about how they lived. The hard packed mud seems to have encompassed the entire burial however, when the pot was first lifted there was no mud pack, only a sandy soil. One theory for how this pack occurred was that the bowl was taken, lined with mud, and then the baby was placed in. When the bowl was turned upside down the mud shifted and filled the soil of the hole which was dug for the pot to be placed in and stayed separated because it is of a different consistency. Another possibility is that the bowl was filled with mud, the body placed in and then it was coved with mud. This would explain the difference in the curvatures. The curve of the pack which was in the bowl (facing up) and the curve that was in the open part of the bowl (facing down) which was relatively shallow or flat. Either way it is clear that the body was packed in soil inside the bowl.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The sherds are ubaid when Bradley, Bekir and I stood back and consulted the baulks it was clear that the current level of my trench is almost a full meter above the ubaid trench. Because of this it seems unlikely that the pit is an original ubaid context. More probably the sherds were brought up when the pit was dug. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The other interesting find of this week was L58, the large pit in the northern section of the trench. This pit, which is roughly cylindrical, when completely dug was .66m deep. The pit has hard packed sides filled with a very soft dark ash fill (10YR 3/1 Very Dark Grey). The top of the pit, excavated on May 24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, contained very large chunks of bone and pottery fragments. The deeper the pit went the fewer items there were. In the bottom 10cm there were three grindstones. Along with the large amounts of bone and pottery multiple small finds came out of the pit. These included: two spindle whorls or loom weights (identification uncertain), a fragment of a ceramic beer strainer, a round stone, and three grind stones. The puzzling thing about this trench is the precise date for it. Many of the sherds pulled out are ubaid. It appears that there were at lease two different ubaid pots, one white painted with black, one red painted with black. The other pieces, when analyzed in the field, were inconclusive. There needs to be only one piece of a later dating pot to make this an EB pit since the date of the pit cannot be earlier than the latest piece of pottery. These bags have been marked for Lynn to analyze. When we continued to bring down the area around the top of the pit we were pulled out pieces from the EB and later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today with loci 55 gone and loci 58 completely excavated there is nothing to do but continue to bring the whole trench down. We are continuing to bring down loci 59, the loci in the western half of the trench. In the western baulk I can see an ashy layer and a larger mud brick layer, possibly slump. We never found these layers in the fill loci, we must have missed them when we went through the area with picks or they were so broken up that we could not have seen them. The ubaid house was 1m 40cm below a ceramic and cobble surface which is visible in both my trench D8 and D5 which is next door and which had the ubaid house. Currently the highest locus is 68cm below that surface. The pit goes down even further, another 60cm. This means that the bottom of the pit should be on top of the ubaid layer. One troubling point about this is that there is nothing visible in the inside of the pit, no mud bricks, and no surfaces. This may mean that there is nothing for the next 60cm. We must wait until the pottery is read until we know or sure what period we are in. At this point it’s possible that we are in ubaid but Bradley and Bekir think that it is unlikely.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-8-2005-05-021-Weekly</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C">JW</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/07971F38-3FEA-481A-0F1F-0D54D5A5AACB</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-8-2005-05-021-Weekly&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.contributor=JW&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F07971F38-3FEA-481A-0F1F-0D54D5A5AACB</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830596</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813717</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/07971F38-3FEA-481A-0F1F-0D54D5A5AACB">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 8</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>07971F38-3FEA-481A-0F1F-0D54D5A5AACB</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:59:56-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:59:56</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
