<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="0CAEFFBC-6AB9-4321-7B47-4D41D2947CF1" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>E-2-2005-06-05-Weekly</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>FABC613D-55D6-4924-C12A-C8ABDCB92351</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188">6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Weekly</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>FE44032A-3687-4ED3-B68C-6387F7FB4963</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/94200B44-9FDB-4631-67B9-DDCF850878C2">94200B44-9FDB-4631-67B9-DDCF850878C2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-05</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="person" info="Recorded by">B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
              <oc:name>Area E</oc:name>
              <oc:id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:person_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C" cite="contributor">
        <oc:name>JW</oc:name>
        <oc:id>B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Recorded by</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:person_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Weekly Summary 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area E, Trench 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. Henecke&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; We ended last week with very few features or good contexts in the trench, and I began this week by cleaning and reevaluating the existing loci (L65, 66, 45 and 58). The trench currently has three different areas of activity, which I have not yet been able to correlate into an understandable whole.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To the north of L45 – an area of approximately 4m x .7m – I finished removing the L66 surface, taking a HAP sample, soil sample and sifting all soil. I quickly removed the L68 subsurface fill locus, and finished excavating the L63 ash pit. At this point, the entire area was L69, a gray ashy fill. Eventually, we uncovered L81, a second pebbled surface with a similar positioning and dimensions to the previous L66 surface. This locus was so small and disjointed that I did not take samples. This floor effectively divided the area, leaving L69 to the northeast and L86 to the southwest. L69 has a much harder and compact clay soil than the looser fill of L86. I created L87 and 84 based on natural lines in the soil, but rather than color demarcations the loci are separated by deep cracks. These lines run parallel to each other, but until I remove this area, it is impossible to tell whether these are fill or features. It has been suggested briefly that they may be associated with the large wall found last season in the northeastern baulk. The gray soil cuts of at the edge of this feature and these lines are at a layer contiguous with the possible wall. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L86 is clearly distinct from the soil in the rest of the trench, and there is a visible line between the two soils near the west corner of the trench. The line follows the path of stone wall L70, which began to emerge last week and has now grown into a full sized stone wall. The southwestern half of the trench, bounded to the north by this wall, is dominated by a possible street feature. A few centimeters below the L71 fill locus, we discovered a pebbled surface, covering the entire area between L70 and L72. The pottery impressed into this surface seems to be from the Chalcolithic period. The mudbrick wall L72 has three rows of bricks and extends across the south corner. In the corner created by the wall is L73, an otherwise undistinguished fill locus. We took aerial photographs of this architecture, and I also HAP sampled the entire street surface. Both walls extend deeper into the ground, and it is possible we may find other associated surfaces. I am unable to remove either feature until I have excavated further in the fill areas surrounding them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The area to the southeast of L45 began as a section of the general L71 fill locus, but on the 29&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; I divided this into two halves. The distinction is arbitrary based only on the assumption that L77 – to the south – maybe contaminated by topsoil. It seems unlikely that this is the case however, because L72 extends into the possible erosion zone with its bricks intact. Just beneath the surface, we uncovered the ashy pit L74 in the east corner, and at the bottom of this feature is wall L92, constructed of small and medium stones. The wall only extends for about a meter, and may have been blownout by the activity in L80-90. There is also a mudbrick wall that lies between L77 and 75, and seems to extend beneath the L78 street surface. In order to determine how best to excavate this area, I examined the southeastern wall of L45 and was able to discern a line of black burnt material. I also saw a distinction in soil texture between what was L75 and L80. I excavated L75 as a pit, and in the process missed a layer of darker soil, which should have been separate. At the bottom of this locus is a tan semi-circle line, which may be a pit of residue associated with features found last year. This area – now L100 – is level with the sounding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The area of L80 was so small and disconnected that it was very difficult to tell what might have been happening in this location. All layers seem to extend into the northeastern baulk – leaving an excellent profile – and more information may lie within our current baulk. L80 was not as clearly a surface as it appeared in the cross section, and rainfall did not help to clarify the picture. Beneath this black hard packed layer was a series of layers of flat lying pottery and lithics (L85). It is possible that these were two or three surface layers, but the pottery was very scattered and there were a few pieces standing vertical. I believe that this is either a very degraded surface or a fill locus. Beneath this L88 is more clearly fill, with light gray soil, carbon and ash inclusions. Part of this locus was blown away during excavation revealing a cluster of small stones and lithics under the surface (L90). It seems likely that this locus continues under all of L85, and is possibly associated with L92. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Next week, I will continue to attempt to reach the level of the Ubaid sounding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: E-2-2005-06-05-Weekly</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C">JW</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/0CAEFFBC-6AB9-4321-7B47-4D41D2947CF1</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+E-2-2005-06-05-Weekly&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.contributor=JW&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F0CAEFFBC-6AB9-4321-7B47-4D41D2947CF1</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830333</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813539</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="contained" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
        <oc:source_name>Area E</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:53:59-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:53:59</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
