<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="1B6B6263-9584-47EA-2620-DCE07286C6B5" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>C-3-2002-08-014-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>3AF60EE2-4738-4637-3A18-84E8D7957FEF</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/19B93BC7-1365-4DBC-4065-EEDA21B527CE">19B93BC7-1365-4DBC-4065-EEDA21B527CE</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002-08-14</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71">
        <oc:name>Trench 3</oc:name>
        <oc:id>9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C">
              <oc:name>Area C</oc:name>
              <oc:id>48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:C-3-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench Summary, Year 2002 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 14, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	C3 is a 10x10 trench on the west side of Kenan Tepe W of B2 and sharing its NW baulk with the S baulk of C2. It was opened in the 2001 season and continued in 2002. It was dug down to approximately 598.53m in 2001 in the E and 597.22 in the W. The trench was stepped in 2001 and the W ¼ was left just 10cm below topsoil. This season the focus of excavation was the E portion of the trench and bringing it down to the level of the W side so that we could continue it as a full 10x10. We also wanted to see what was happening with the major architecture of the trench, like the 10m long stone wall, L3068, which was discovered last year at the end of the season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We started the season by looking for the surface that was associated with the 10m long N-S running stone wall, L3068. We could see the foundation trench, L3074, was already visible E of the wall in L3060 and L3063, so we knew that we had already cut through the surface associated with the wall in the East. Knowing this, we searched West of the wall starting in locus L3065 and peeling off layers with trowels. There were several poorly preserved surfaces, possibly outside work surfaces or surfaces that were seasonally used. At this point I realized that the surface associated with the wall had definitely been removed in 2001 and no further surfaces were associated with the wall and so we began to take out the wall. While taking down the south-most portion of the wall, the portion that approaches the south baulk, we found a limestone doorpost, C.3.3068.6, and soon after a doorway (that is, an opening in the wall where there were no stones) with a clearly visible floor, L3074, which is a partly plastered pebble strewn surface. We did not find the termination of the wall in the North because it goes all the way into the baulk. While removing the Northern portion of the wall we found a pit, L3077, which is a pit that cuts into the wall and breaks the connection of stones between the northern and the southern parts of the wall. This is an important feature for two reasons, firstly it tells us why the stones of the wall are missing and secondly it gives us a connection with a feature from last year, the large oven that was founded on the wall, L3030.	Pit L3077 is a large pit and can be seen in the section of the E baulk directly underneath the oven. We find that the soil in the pit is ashy and in the ash we found another, smaller broken oven in fragments, C.3.3077.5 &amp;amp; 8. This is probably an earlier oven that was broken and discarded in the pit to make way for the larger oven, L3030 thatwas built later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After taking out these two features (L3077 and L3068), there was nothing of true significance left in the east portion of the trench. All the other loci were either fill or poorly preserved surfaces that weren’t connected to any architecture and were not telling us anything about the trench. This area could be an area that was not used much outside of a major building, whose west wall we caught, L3068, or this could be interim fill between occupation periods, and the material we find in the levels here are from erosional fill coming down from the top of the mound. So, with small picks, we started trying to level the trench that we would have a flat area to start working with. As we dug we noticed that there were many carbon samples coming from the E portion of the area we were digging, mostly near the baulk, L3079, L3078 and L3081. We also found a decent amount of slag samples and a piece of a lead pin C.3.3079.3. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After getting down through L3081 , a fill layer continuation of L3020 from last year, we found a couple of features that can help us interpret the trench. First we found a mud brick wall, L3083. It runs N-S and almost directly under the stone wall, L3068. Also we can see only 4 bricks and no connecting wall so we were not sure what to make of it. As we worked in the second important feature that we discovered, an ash layer L3085, we found that part of the wall was collapsed over the ash layer L3085. At first we thought that L3083 was a mud brick cap for the ash layer in order to lay the stone wall, L3068, but we found that only part of the mudbricks were collapsed over the ash layer and that the bricks continued down. Also we found that the ash layer extended a bit further than we expected because it had a thin, 1cm, layer of mud brick collapse over it. The collapse is most likely run off from L3083. The ash layer with collapse over it is L3094. We did not get to finish digging L3085 or find how far down L3083 goes, but we did find the associated surface for the wall on its east side. A small cobble surface coming out of the E baulk at the south most brick of wall 3083 had an intact, in situ piriform jar minus the handle, C.3.3091.1, lying both on it and against the wall, showing that the wall and the surface on which the jar lay were associated. Our goal for the last couple of days of excavation was to bring down all of the trench, minus the wall and what was E of the wall, to the same level so that next season it can be dug completely and comprehensively. While digging L3093, the layer designated as fill S of the ash layer, L3085, we found a large, 30cm+, slag flow coming out of the baulk. We cannot see the surface that it was associated with in section, but it seems like there was a light work surface that was there and continued W into the part of the trench that we didn’t dig this season. The pottery we pulled from the area looks to be LBA. It is possible that in removing the fill that surrounded the slag with big picks, we may have collected material from an interim surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	What we found this year is in some respects similar to what we found last season. Last year in the far eastern, mostly south eastern portion ,we found a series of broken surfaces most unconnected with and architecture. As mentioned above we found a 10m long stone wall running north-south and founded on top of that a large, square oven feature that had several different ash layers in it. In the far eastern area we also found a good amount of carbon and ash, as we did this year. West of the large stone wall we found many ephemeral, outside work-like areas and in the north western quarter we found a series of surfaces that were eroded and looked to be running downhill.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 The information that pulled from the trench this year, as well as the information gained last season, leads me to believe that the area we in the central and western portions of the trench is largely an outside work area. The two walls that we found separate the E meter to two meters from the rest of the trench. They may be inside surfaces because they are in better shape than those outside the walls and are preserved better. Alternatively, the area where the smashed cooking pot and the piriform jar were found could be either an inside area, or an area of a courtyard bounded by a wall, in comparison to the area on the other side of the wall which (given the presenc eo fth eslag flow) would best be described as an outside surface. The surfaces outside (west) of the walls seem to be largely degraded and partially mixed by water. Also in the N/NW there seems to be some sort of water event that caused the surfaces to erode down hill, for instance L3094, L3088 and L3082. The outside of the wall seems to be a work area because of the multitude of animal bones, and slag present in the loci there along with many carbon sample, usually 4+ for each locus. The most convincing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;of these loci is L3085, the ash layer, which contained several bags worth of large bones, including an equine jaw.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Next year t would be interesting to dig the entire area looking at the work surfaces. Because the trench is no longer stepped we can see if the surfaces that were found in the W are continuous throughout the trench. Also the SE should be looked at carefully to see why there is LBA pottery coming up in L3093. Also it would be important to push down in the NW to see if we can catch the metal working contexts that are associated with the slag pits found in C2 two years ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: C-3-2002-08-014-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/1B6B6263-9584-47EA-2620-DCE07286C6B5</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+C-3-2002-08-014-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F1B6B6263-9584-47EA-2620-DCE07286C6B5</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830658</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812673</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1B6B6263-9584-47EA-2620-DCE07286C6B5">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 3</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>1B6B6263-9584-47EA-2620-DCE07286C6B5</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:31:34-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:31:34</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
