<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="26A6C96C-C233-4B2B-9071-74C9A60DC23B" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>C-3-2001-08-016-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>4D0A7054-4855-40AA-F4B0-75F102DBF113</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/335BA6F1-8F2D-45B4-0298-27E7B05B9EEB">335BA6F1-8F2D-45B4-0298-27E7B05B9EEB</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-16</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71">
        <oc:name>Trench 3</oc:name>
        <oc:id>9E83B5E9-C42B-44B0-6C64-145DAB960C71</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C">
              <oc:name>Area C</oc:name>
              <oc:id>48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:C-3-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;C 3 Final Trench Summary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;C 3 is the 10mX10m trench on the west side of the Tepe sharing its NW baulk with the S baulk of C2 and lying NW of area B. This is a new trench this season starting in topsoil. We dug here in order to get a better view of what is going on in this area which has many confusing surfaces and features. We also dug here because last year in C2 there were a couple of slag samples found along with what seemed to be slag pits. My main goal in this trench for this season was to try and find metal production contexts to help strengthen the hypothesis that there was local metal production at this site in this area. I hoped to find some of the same materials, slag pits, ovens for ore reduction, and work surfaces, which were found last year in C2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt; I removed the levels of topsoil, L3000, L3001 and L3002, which were mostly erosion and plowed earth. I hit cultural material in the western half of the trench after only about 10 cm of topsoil removal. In the eastern half of the trench I hit culture after about 20 cm. Because of the slope of the hill, the western half of the trench naturally lies almost 1 m below the eastern half, we ended up making a large step, close to 50 cm, separating the two halves, East and West, of the trench. We did this with the big picks and ended up going through some incredibly light, uncoordinated surfaces that are partially washed away here but we caught in the eastern half. The section that this created was a N-S running baulk which I named the mid-trench baulk. The southern portion still remains.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt; In the west side of the trench we came down onto two things at the same time that made us stop. First was the N-S running, 1 row stone wall that came up in about the center of the western side. The other was the round, clay oven coming out of the NW baulk abutting C2. We stopped using big picks and started digging more carefully articulating L3010 which was a work surface with many animal bones, several of them connecting together, which was actually a series of work surfaces deposited on top of one another and hard to follow with a trowel. This/these surface(s) abutted the wall, L3005, at its south end, which happens to contain a 20 cm in diameter piece of conglomerate, most likely slag which we have sampled and will test for metal content to determine whether it is slag or not. This could mean that these work surfaces at one point were involved in ore reduction and the conglomerate on the end of this wall is slag left form the refinement of metal. However, it is so close to topsoil that it is hard to tell. Next to this locus there was another locus, L3011, which is similar to L3010 in the fact that it seems to be a series of maybe 1 cm thick, light work surfaces which are impossible to follow because of their un coordination and their proximity to topsoil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt; Under these surfaces we found two more, L3020 and L3021, which abut the wall 3005 but we did not dig enough to find there relationship to the wall. L3020 is like the surface L3011 before it, light hard to define layers of brief occupation. While trying to follow this surface the workers kept missing the small surfaces and made some small steps. L3021 is a fill layer to the west of the wall 3005. This may have a couple of uncoordinated surfaces like L3020 and L3011 but it is so close to topsoil, 10 cm, that is impossible to discern them from the fill. When articulating the wall 3005 in order to find out if these uncoordinated surfaces were associated with the wall we found KT3304 which is a stone carved animal figurine. We found that L3021 is not the surface that goes with the wall because it is above the top of the wall. North of these surfaces and the wall we thought we had found two mudbrick walls L3016, and L3017. When we tried to trowel to them in order to articulate we found that they weren’t walls they were actually just fill above two surfaces L3018 and L3025.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt; L3018 is a hard, compact surface that seems to want to run the entire width of the trench, east to west, except in the east part of the trench it is cut by at least 2 very large pits, L3042 and L3043 and finally stopped by the stone wall 3037. It has several of the same attributes as all the other surfaces so far mentioned, it seems to be several hard to define surfaces closely deposited one on top of the other and also when trying to follow it is easily lost. The difference between it and the other surface is that it is so compact and hard the workers had to stop toweling it and start carefully small picking it. I was not able to make a clear connection with this surface and any other features other than the pits that cut it. This is because it is hard to follow and also we didn’t completely excavate around it this season. It will remain to be investigated in the next season. While examining and in some places cutting this surface we found a surface underneath it. L3025 is a strange cobble surface. It slopes downhill and has a large mound like build up/accumulation in the south area of it. This seems to correspond to some light broken cobbles found in the south of L3018 and even lighter, less preserved cobbles in the south west of 3024 which is east of and above 3018. These could either be an accumulation of eroded surfaces from the upper part of the area or it could be some form of path or step way that has been worn and eroded coming from the east and heading west. I think the later may be truer because of the presence of the cobbles in a clear channel and because they seem to follow a rough linear pattern from east to west spanning several elevation changes. In the north this locus is cut by a trench like pit L3045 which makes it impossible to see it in the section of C2 which is where the surface runs to. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The other two things in this NW part of the trench are L3006 and L3023. L3023 is a pit that cuts out of the N baulk and into L3025 and L018, which seems to be characteristic of this surface, which is cut by 4 pits. Locus 3006 is an oven, which starts maybe 5 cm underneath the topsoil. It seems to be founded in the trench L3045 which would make it newer than the pit and therefore newer than L3018. We were not able to completely excavate this oven so we are not 100% sure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Underneath the topsoil in the eastern half of the trench, east of the mid trench baulk we found an oven 3003 very soon after removing the topsoil. It was a very well preserved oven. The walls were intact and the only missing part was the top of it which we fond most of in the fill inside the oven and surrounding it. This is suggestive of when the oven went out of use. Because of its well preserved state the oven could have been abandoned before it was heavily used. This could be because of a change in the use of the area or of a site. Because it was so well preserved and we found it relatively close to its top I stayed in situ for a long time in order for us to find the surface it was founded on and originally used with. After excavating around it we got close to the surface on which the oven was placed. It was then we learned something about the construction of ovens from the workers in the trench who use the same type of oven in their culture still. They told us that the oven was put on a surface, which was dug into a little. Then they take mud and place it to make a floor for the oven, which is lower than the level of the bottom course of the oven. Then they take mud from the surrounding area and pile it around the oven building a layer of mud coming from the associated floor up to the side of the oven and building up a kind of conical/pyramidal outside layer for the oven. This gave us a guideline for finding the surface for this oven. First we look to se where this outside layer ends and then find the softer ash layer that would be created by use of the oven and the surface that turns into this ashy lens that surrounds the oven is the surface that the oven was founded on. In this case it happened to be L3027 which is a broken cobble surface. We then look to see what surface the floor is founded on. That will be the surface which is not cut by the oven and which the oven floor turns into. This oven floor was founded on the stone wall L3037 beneath it. This is very interesting because several meters north of this oven is another, this time square oven, which has 3027 as a use surface and is founded on the same wall 3037. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This oven is L3030 and is a square oven. It consists of 3 courses, a hard baked clay cap above a packed silty soil resting on a hard mudbrick material. This has several different fill layers in it: L3032 an ashy fill, L3036 an ashy fill with a little plaster and a potsmash, L3040 a mixture of ash and what seems to be weathered soil or fired soil or weathered mudbrick collapse, L3041 which is similar to L3041 but contained KT3390 which was a conical pottery piece, L3050 a lightly ashy clay full of small fragments of pottery. The floor for this oven is L3051 which is clearly founded on L3037 because it contains several of the stones from that wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Outside of the oven we have 3 key loci, L3048, 3038 and 3027. L3027 I mentioned before as being a use surface for this oven. We deducted this from a scorch mark which is present both on the oven wall and on the surface. L3048 was the fill that was outside of the oven right after we found and identified the oven. This is an important locus because in it we found KT3239, which is a metal pin like object about 8cm long. L3038 is south of the oven and east of the wall 3037. It is beneath L3027 and contained 10+ carbon samples. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The wall that I keep mentioning is the largest feature in my trench. Labeled L3037 it starts coming out of the south baulk continues north under the oven 3030 and all the way to the north baulk making this a 10 m long wall. It is about a meter plus thick and is broken in 3 places (though it may be revealed further after more soil is removed). The first place is where pit L3046 cut unto it just southwest of the oven L3030. The second place is around oven L3030 where stones were probably removed in the founding of the oven. The third is in the N and I’m not sure why it is cut there. In that area, the NE quadrant of the trench we decided to use the big picks to go down from the level that we were at and stop at the level of the western half of the trench. We did this because we weren’t finding any surfaces in that area and we were having a hard time following surfaces in the SE quadrant. So we decided to cut this, making a section, which we could use as a guide for the rest of the upper area. Because of this we may have missed a pit cutting the wall or we ourselves may have removed some of the stones. We will have to wait until next year to answer that question. Also because of the existence of L3024 surfaces found in the south that continue north are cut by this locus as well as the oven L3030 and its fill layers. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;These loci in the SE quadrant are sealed by the loci above them. The two most mentionable of these are L3015 and L3013. L3015 is a stone feature, which we only catch a corner of coming out of the east baulk a little south of center. It is cut in its NE corner by the pit L3026 whose subdivision is L3035. This feature has two very interesting things about it. First it has a conglomerate chunk which seems to have been applied wet or molten. When examining it looks to be slag. This is interesting because it is beneath an oven, L3007 and a pit 3008 which abuts the oven and could be a slag pit. If this were slag it would be good evidence that the oven above it was used for ore reduction. The second interesting thing is that this feature was within L3013. The surface L3013 contained all of L3015 but stopped where L3015 ends. L3013 was a cobble surface similar to the other cobble surfaces found in this area except that it is not as well kept together and it falls apart easily. Above these were fill layers and topsoil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This entire trench seems to be an outside work and occupation area. The surfaces in this area are discontinuous and hard to follow. Many of them seem to be eroded heavily. There is not much architecture here enclosing any areas. The large stone wall L3037 could be a retaining wall or the outside of a structure wall. Also the presence of so many pits, L3014, 3008, 3023, 3026, 3035, 3045, 3042, 3043, 3029, 3046 and any that we missed also makes me think that this area was not indoors. Furthermore there are 4 ovens in this area and several ash lenses that we see in section. The fact that we also have a large oven, L3030, which was clearly used for large amounts of burning as we found more that 10 carbon samples surrounding it makes me believe that this area would not have been enclosed inside a building. The oven is similar to those seen locally, which are all used outside. Some of this area could have been used for ore reduction as we found a significant, seven plus samples, amount of slag throughout the area. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-bottom:0.0000in;margin-top:0.0000in;margin-right:0.0000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the season C 3 has the following loci still open: 3049, 3047, 3038, 3054, 3037 and parts of the fill above it in the north and the south 3039 and 3052, 3034, 3024, 3055, 3018, 3042, 3020, 3021, 3005, 3025, 3006 and 3045, whose eastern side starting at the oven 3006 remains unexcavated as well as a bit 75 cm east from the west baulk and 85 cm south of the north baulk in this loci’s SW corner. The cobbles hat flow west from 3024 through 3018 and into 3025 are still present but caution should be taken in trying to find this next season as seasonal rains may degrade it. After closing the trench I drew the East baulk. The baulk is accurate in depicting the nature of the trench as it shows broken surfaces hard to follow lines and many animal burrows. The center and northern half of the baulk do not represent the levels in the trench very well. First in the northern half we had dug through several un identified layers while digging L3024. Second we cannot see in the section the oven L3030 but we can see several layers of the fill. In the south we can see the 2 cobble surfaces that we found L3013 and L3027 as well as the fill layers. All in all, the south 3.5 to 4 meters of this baulk represent the layers found in the trench while the remaining north section depicts the complexity of the layers in this trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: C-3-2001-08-016-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/26A6C96C-C233-4B2B-9071-74C9A60DC23B</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+C-3-2001-08-016-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F26A6C96C-C233-4B2B-9071-74C9A60DC23B</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830658</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812673</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/26A6C96C-C233-4B2B-9071-74C9A60DC23B">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 3</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>26A6C96C-C233-4B2B-9071-74C9A60DC23B</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:06:02-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:06:02</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
