<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-7-2002-08-08-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>AB7DDF9B-BC9F-4620-1199-CF96645BD9D9</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1323F97B-1134-4E99-85B6-B3FF995F77C2">1323F97B-1134-4E99-85B6-B3FF995F77C2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002-08-08</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Concurrent">E229E4EA-4977-484C-B3E7-0D8BA5F16789</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Next">AB633299-97C2-41DE-D1B1-8B16BCE79FC6</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD">
        <oc:name>Trench 7</oc:name>
        <oc:id>D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/E229E4EA-4977-484C-B3E7-0D8BA5F16789">
        <oc:name>F-7-2002-08-08</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E229E4EA-4977-484C-B3E7-0D8BA5F16789</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Concurrent</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/AB633299-97C2-41DE-D1B1-8B16BCE79FC6">
        <oc:name>F-7-2002-08-10</oc:name>
        <oc:id>AB633299-97C2-41DE-D1B1-8B16BCE79FC6</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Next</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-7-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 8, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;During the 2002 field season I continued working in Area F Trench 7. Area F is on the lower mound at Kenan Tepe that dates from the Chalcolithic to the Early Bronze Age. This area is characterized by a lot of ovens, ash, and was significantly lacking any material remains or structures that implied a domestic use. F7 is the only 10x10 meter trench currently being excavated in this area. Therefore, this trench gives us the opportunity to catch a large area in one context and get the horizontal picture of this lower mound. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the second year that F7 was excavated. We went down about 1 meter last year in the western half of the trench and about ½ a meter in the eastern part of the trench due to a natural slope. This year we continued to go down in elevation about 20-30 centimeters in the western half of the trench and about 15 to 25 centimeters in the eastern half of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trenches surrounding F7 include F5(?) to the East, F8 to the Southeast, and F9 to the South. None of these trenches were excavated this season. F13 lies to the Southwest and F14 lies to the West. Both of these trenches were excavated and had some structures in them, namely a possible mudbrick wall in F13 and a cobble surface in F14. (I believe). Neither of these trenches seemed to have a direct relation to what was going on in my trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the beginning of the season, the main goal that we had in place was to determine the nature of and the relationships that existed to a 3 sided mudbrick structure in the center of F7 and hopefully push on through to the next context. We were able to accomplish this goal this season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Excavation&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We needed to clean the baulks, so Loci 7060, 7061, 7062 and 7063 were opened to collect the debris from the 4 baulks in the trench. After cleaning the baulks we were ready to begin cleaning the debris left from last year and taking care of loci that were unexcavated. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were 2 surfaces left over from the 2001 field season, L7047 and L7049. L7047 had been pedastled, so it was a priority to articulate the cobbles that it consisted of, photo it, take samples from it, and take down the elevation. We took a 10 Liter soil sample from the surface for a chemical microanalysis. After taking down the surface we opened fill locus 7048. It was a cleaning locus in the northeastern part of the trench that abutted cleaning fill locus 7046. We took down elevation in fill 7046 in order to articulate surface 7049 and then opened another fill locus 7056. After taking down elevation in this fill, we found another surface directly to the east of surface 7049. I opened locus 7059 for this surface. This surface was cut by pit 7050 that was also located in the northern half of the trench. Pit 7050, surface 7049 and surface 7059 were all photographed with the spider so that they could be accurately portrayed in a measured top plan that we did during the season. After shooting the photographs, we excavated these surfaces much like surface 7047: articulation, chemical microanalysis, and removal. After excavating surface 7059 there appeared another surface underneath it, perhaps a subfloor. It was excavated in the same manner and a 10L soil sample was taken from it as well. However, L7079 was not completely excavated this year before the season ended. There is a small area of concentrated cobbles that is part of this surface. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pit 7050 was excavated at the same time as pit 7051 that was located in the center of the eastern half of the trench. They were both large and circular in shape and started out as fairly soft. However, in both cases during excavation, after about 10 cms the soil changed and become more hard and clayey. In the bottom of pit 7050 there were a lot of flat-lying pottery sherds and animal bones. In pit 7051, we were not sure if we had reached the bottom, so we sectioned it and the new half of the pit we were digging deeper became pit section 7058. We continued digging this for about 20 cms. After analyzing the section it was clear that we had excavated the entire pit. Both pits, 7050 and 7051, turned out to be quite shallow and although I noticed the change in soil in both and changed their KT bags, so we would be sure to have an uncontaminated sample, I did not take elevations when the transition occurred. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The next related loci to talk about are all related to a 3-sided structure that was in the middle of F7. This mudbrick structure was slightly more red in color and had a much more course texture than the surrounding fill. The borders of the structure were clear in soft light, and it had very definite boundaries. This structure was L7053. There was a wall probe that was left over from the previous year that I opened as L7052. Before we had reached the related surface, we opened loci 7056 and 7057 as cleaning loci. Fill 7056 represented the fill on the exterior part of the structure and fill 7057 represented interior fill. There was also a human burial directly east of where the southern wall seemed to end and we were not sure if the wall actually ended or if it was cut by this burial. The burial itself was L7054 and the burial fill was L7055.  In an attempt to get a better idea about structure 7053, we opened fill L7064 to the east of the southern wall to see if we could find any wall extensions. We did not. Once we had determined what our situation was, we were able to start excavating the fill and figure out the nature of this structure. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In order to have as much control as possible on the material remains and soil samples we took from this area, we instituted a grid system for excavation that extended over the entire trench. The grid was laid out in 1x1 meter blocks. The rationale behind this was that we could analyze where debris was coming from in a very specific area. This could possibly aid in the analysis of what type of activities were undertaken in this structure. We also predetermined that we wanted to take a 10% sampling of the soil and we determined what quadrants those would be based on their location in the structure. It is clearly shown on the dayplans from when this system was being used. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There was a series of fill loci that were opened that were delineated as interior or exterior fill. Loci 7068 and 7070 were interior fill. Loci 7067 and 7069 were exterior fill. There were other arbitrary fill loci assigned in the case that the walls did extend eastward. I wanted to keep the interior and exterior debris separate from one another, but the walls did not extend, so these loci ended up being completely arbitrary. But for the record, the fill that was labeled as interior included loci 7072, and 7077 and the fill that was labeled as being exterior included loci 7071, 7073, 7076 and 7078. The fill layers that had most of the debris were L7067 and L7068. They were riddled with pottery smashes and large animal bones, mainly of goat and cattle. It was this context that was captured in the measured top plan. After removing this fill loci, it became clear that there was no concrete surface that was visible. We called locus 7074 the exterior surface interface and locus 7075 the interior locus interface. We believe that it was just a transition in soil and not anything that would be visible in excavation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Related to the relationships between the surfaces and the structure of 7053, is burial 7054 and fill 7055. Once the burial team extracted the burial and took out the excess fill, we found what seemed to be a doorpost in relation to where the southern wall ended. The doorpost was a semi-circular rock with a fairly deep depression in the center. This doorpost is small find F.7.7077.22. We took photos of the relationship and collected the doorpost.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After we had determined the nature of the relationship between the walls, the debris and the surfaces, it was time to determine the nature of the wall. We pushed wall probe 7052 down about 20 additional centimeters. The red soil seemed to be only one course that was followed by a lighter soil. I continued to push down the probe to see if it could be alternating red and white courses, but it did not seem to be the case. We dug around the structure and then took structure 7053 out. After we took out structure 7053, we ceased using the grid system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After excavating this context, the trench was basically fill. I opened a series of arbitrary fill loci that included L7080, L7081, L7082, L7083, L7088, L7089, L7090, L7093 and L7096. In the midst of excavating these fill layers, there was a small pit that I opened as L7086. At least I thought it was a pit, but after taking off a few cms, it was clear that it was just soft dirt that was the same as the surrounding fill of 7089, so it was closed. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also found another human burial that is L7084 in fill L7085. As of my last day of excavation, this burial had not yet been excavated, but plans include extracting this burial before the end of the dig season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There also appeared in the Eastern half of the trench 2 circular features that we have not yet determined what their exact nature is. They both have slightly darker interiors and a lighter exterior border that measures about 20cms and surrounds the interior. The first was identified and excavated in the northeastern part of the trench. The interior was L7094 and the exterior border was L7095. The last day my trench was opened we started pushing down elevation in the interior of this feature. We did it in sections, ½ was excavated in 5 cm. intervals and the other ½ in 10 cm. segments. We found quite a few small finds in this feature. There were 2 whole pots that we were able to articulate and extract. One was a small bowl that is KT F.7.7094.9 and one is a larger pedastled bowl that is KT F.7.7094.4. We also found a small metal pin in this area. Due to these finds on my last day, the decision was made not to close this locus and keep it open after my departure so we can figure out the nature of this feature this season. The other circular feature is further south against the eastern baulk. The interior of this feature is L7099 and the exterior is L7100. This feature remained unexcavated for this season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some loci that don’t really seem to fit in the groups I have discussed above include L7065 which was a feature of a ring of pottery and rocks. There was a similar feature in F8 last year. This had a goat metapodial in the center. The goat metapodial is KT F.7.7065.1 We articulated it, took photos, and removed it. Another such locus was a small pit in the southern half of the trench. It contained a small bird or rodent skeleton that was KT F.7.7066.1. I also need to mention L7092. I skipped a number on my locus sheets, so this locus is nothing. It does not exist.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The last thing to address is the loci that were opened but remained unexcavated for this season and have not yet been mentioned. This would be a pit L7087, an area of concentrated virgin soil in the southeastern corner L7097, and another pit, L7098. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;III. Small Finds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The notable finds that I had this season that have not been mentioned above in relation to their contexts is as follows:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7048.4 - OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7053.3 - CERAMIC RING/WEIGHT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7067.9 – SMALL FIGURINE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7069.62 – METAL PIN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7069.94 – OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7070.8 – OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7072.27-30 – POTTERY SMASH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7073.8 – OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7073.39 – BURNISHING TOOL (?)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7078.6 – OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7078.29 – OBSIDIAN BLADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7083.1 – SMALL FIGURINE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F.7.7089.8-10 – POTTERY SMASH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Sections&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-left:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This year we were able to draw all of my sections. The East, South and West baulk only contained layers of topsoil, sub-topsoil, and perhaps another deposit. But none of them really reflect what is being found within my trench. The exception to that would be the North baulk. It has captured some of the cobbled surfaces from last year and this year. As for this year, both surfaces 7049 and 7059 are represented in the baulk. As for last year’s loci, I have not analyzed them yet for the sections, so unfortunately I cannot be more specific.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Interpretation&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-left:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F7 dates to the early Bronze Age and we had a very good context this year with which we can hopefully extrapolate a lot of insight into this time period. The structure 7053 was the first structure to be found in the lower mound and we were lucky enough to catch it entirely. The abundance of pottery, bones and lithics lead me to believe that it was used in a domestic context, perhaps in the context of meal preparation. The new circular features, Loci 7094 and 7095, and 7099 and 7100 could also be pits or ovens. Locus 7094 definitely holds some interesting pots and the idea has been tossed around that it may be for a cooking context. Hopefully as we come upon the next context in this trench and do the analysis of the material remains from this year, we will have a better idea of what it is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-left:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Attention!&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There was an area that I saw in the southwest corner that looked like a circular structure of reddish mudbricks. It was fairly obvious when I sprayed it with water, but it was not visible at the time I did my final day plan. Whoever excavates this trench next year may want to keep an eye out for it. It could possibly be a small oven.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also, this year we used the wrong value for the F1 Datum. We were using 570.82, but we discovered it was the GPS point. Just an FYI!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Things To Do:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scan all Dayplans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Loci on all Sections&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Loci on Measured Top Plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-7-2002-08-08-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-7-2002-08-08-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.831542</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.815434</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 7</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:35:29-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:35:29</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,600 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3600</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 7</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>2E1D29E3-A870-40B6-691F-B2582C9B0A56</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:51:07-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
