<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="3166FFD7-0E8E-4A05-D947-2BF27E09D791" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-6-2007-07-03-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>26E6570D-EADF-46C0-BD7E-D99125629CCC</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/17E656A7-7610-46CB-C426-5868B209C82B">17E656A7-7610-46CB-C426-5868B209C82B</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2007-07-03</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2007</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7E147590-C31A-4A9E-9A21-E31D3A4AC0B7">7E147590-C31A-4A9E-9A21-E31D3A4AC0B7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2007</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719">
        <oc:name>Trench 6</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E5B52F10-333F-4CB8-C397-7DFAD00A3719</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-6-2007-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 3, 2007&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jason Kennedy and Baris Uzel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench D6 was started in 2002 excavation season directly south of Trench D4. This is on the Southern slope of the main mound of Kenan Tepe. The reasoning behind this placement was to capture views of the continuations of surface and architecture found in D4 during the 2001 season. The trench was excavated again in the 2005 field season in order to complete the excavations of the 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium furnace complex in the northwest portion of the trench. The purpose of the excavations in D6 this season were to attempt to discern any connections between the Ubaid walls discovered in trenches D8 and D5 and possible associated architecture in trench D6.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavation Notes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trench had not been excavated in two seasons and a significant amount of erosion had fallen into the trench. Our initial starting elevations for the cleaning locus (Locus 83) was 590.01 meters above sea level, accumulating nearly .4 m of deposits above the plastic used to preserve the levels from the 2005 season. The erosion had also expanded our trench to its dimensions of 9.25 meters by 4 meters. Our initial task was to remove the erosional deposits to uncover the remains unearthed in 2005. After cleaning we began excavating beginning with Locus number 84. We began by emphasizing the Middle Bronze age pebble cobble street surfaces that more or less ran roughly north to south through the center of the trench. We uncovered at least seven different layering phases of this surface including Loci 85, 91, 96, 102, 106, 113 and118, combining for roughly .9 meters of deposit. These surfaces were composed of pebbles, cobbles, and a substantial amount of potsherds. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To the west of this street we found only one potential architectural structure, a2.1 meters long and .5 meters wide stonewall (Locus 108) which was cut by pit Locus 101, and runs into the northern baulk of the trench. The remaining Middle Bronze Loci (86, 92, and 97, and 103) yielded no associated architecture. Of note is that Ubaid painted ceramics began emerging mixed with Middle Bronze ceramics in Locus 97, and that Loci 107, 114, 120, 121, 122 all yielded primarily Ubaid ceramics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To the east of the streets we discovered mixed contexts pretty much throughout our excavations suggesting that this portion of the trench had been heavily altered by slope erosion. The stonewall uncovered at the end of the 2005 season (Locus 73) was renamed Locus 87 and was the only significant architecture associated with the second millennium streets that we discovered. Locus 91 of the streets probably lay under any associated structure with Locus 87 in that two streets combined to form a junction with main street running north to south through the trench and a cross street joining it running east towards the Tigris. Loci 89, 90, 88, 93, 94, 95, 99, 100, 104, 105, 109, 110, 115, and 119 all contained mixed contexts and different soil consistencies that the western portion of the trench suggesting that these loci were affected by the erosional processes of the mound. An earlier stonewall foundation was discovered in Locus 112 running along the eastern border of street Locus 113, but no connecting walls were discovered as it ran both into the eastern and southern baulks. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Below the Middle Bronze street deposits and their associated loci, we uncovered largely Ubaid contexts throughout the trench. The later Ubaid deposits in the trench consisted of largely ephemeral outdoor surfaces, and we only uncovered two walls (Locus 117 and Locus 131) that ran roughly parallel to each other. Locus 117 was a mudbrick wall 3.3 meters long and .55 meters wide roughly north to south along the western baulk of the trench and was either cut or ran up against an oven or fireplace represented by Loci (124, 129, and 147). Locus 131 was a 3.5-meter long and .6 meter wide mudbrick wall with 2 discernable rows of bricks of 20 by 50 cm, however only one course of bricks was present. No connecting walls were discovered between these two walls. Below these walls lay roughly .35 meters of fill with no architectural features, however two fetus burials were discovered Locus 145 and Locus 155. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the northern portion of the trench we discovered wall Locus 159 which provided the connection with the house structure that had been uncovered in D8 and D5 in previous seasons. To the north of wall Locus 159 we uncovered a layer of collapsed and burnt mudbrick (Locus 167). This was most likely created by the collapse of the roof followed by the collapse inward of the mudbrick wall sealing the floors (Locus 172 and Locus 184). The collapsed layer in Locus 167 contained several small finds including whole pots, tools, and body adornment, suggesting either that these items were on the roof of the building or located in some manner on the inner walls of the building. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After uncovering the floor of the house (Locus 172) we began removing the eastern baulk of the trench to ascertain the specific connections between our wall Locus 159 and the walls in Trench D8 and Trench D5, as well as the remainder of the collapsed building located and uncovered this season in Trench D4. In the eastern baulk extension we uncovered an eastern room of the house that contained a doorway into the main room represented by Floor Locus 172 and a doorway into the courtyard represented in Loci 178, 186, 180, 171, 193, 174, and 173. Wall Locus 159 extended into the eastern baulk and came to a corner and became the same wall discovered earlier in trenches D8 and D5. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A large stonewall of unknown date (Locus 170) and an earlier foundation or wall (Locus 182) was discovered in the eastern baulk extension as well. Both Ubaid and Early Bronze age diagnostic pottery was uncovered in the removal of both portions of the wall. An earlier wall was discovered in Locus 188 that was Ubaid in date and abutted the southeast corner of Wall Locus 159. Locus 188 probably represents a courtyard or terrace wall associated with the collapsed house. A doorway into this courtyard was discovered in the room in the eastern baulk extension. In the courtyard were a number of features. A burnt surface (Locus 171) with a rock and potsherd foundation (Locus 193) was located along the western baulk in the center of the trench. A large stone lined pit (Locus 174) abutted the stone courtyard wall of Locus 188, and was tentatively dated to be Ubaid based on ceramic typology. A surface (Locus 173) was located directly to the west of the pit and contained some small cobbles, potsherds, and a significant amount of ash and charred seeds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Below the floors of both the rooms and located below the foundation of Wall Locus 159 we discovered a series of surfaces (Loci 189, 190, 192) that probably represented earlier Ubaid outdoor work surfaces. A large pit (Locus 191) was discovered in the eastern room in the baulk extension that ran below the wall and into the northern baulk between D6 and D4. This pit was filled with burnt earth and ash, and revealed a hard burnt earth surface suggesting that it was an earlier Ubaid hearth associated with the outdoor work surfaces in Loci 189, 190, and 192.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Significant Finds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;LocusKT #Tentative DateContexts/Remarks834MBStone Mold from baulk cleaning near the furnace excavated in 2002 and 2005.855MBBronze Arrowhead from 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium street982 and 3MBWorked ceramic disks991MBOven Leg1025MBBronze Pin from the 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium street1302UbaidBasalt Fishnet weight1434 and 5UbaidGrinding stone and Pestle from between walls Locus 117 and Locus 1311472 and 3Ubaid Hammerstones found in association with two large lithic cores, numerous smaller cores and heavy concentrations of debitage. Located below the burnt surface Locus 129.1549Ubaid Bone Pin1601UbaidObsidian Arrowhead From a pit cutting the Collapsed room in Locus 167.1641UbaidSpindle Whorl – from fill north of wall 1591672, 3, 17, 34UbaidBone awls from the Collapse of the house north of wall 159.1674UbaidStone Pendant from the collapsed house1675, 16, 21, 22UbaidBeads recovered from the collapsed house1676UbaidWorked shell pendant from the collapsed house16714, 19, 20UbaidStone axes from the collapsed house. The three were all small hand tools but each was of a different size suggesting different functions or for working different materials.16718Ubaid Obsidian blade discovered in the area of the stone axes from the collapsed house 16728UbaidWhole Pot from the collapsed house16727UbaidStone pendant from the collapsed house16729UbaidWhole Pot from the collapsed house16738, 39, 40UbaidSpindle whorls from the collapsed house16741UbaidStone Pendant from the collapsed house16745UbaidSeal Impression from the collapsed house, with both impressions of the stamp seal and rope.16746UbaidStone Pendant from the collapsed house16749, 64UbaidUnfired clay andirons from the collapsed house16760UbaidWhole pot from the collapsed house16761UbaidObsidian arrowhead1682UbaidStone pendant from the fill south of the collapsed house1715 and 6UbaidPossible metal fragments from burnt earth surface in Locus 171.1726UbaidSpindle whorl from the floor of the collapsed house.1823-Pestle from the foundation of the large stone wall in the eastern baulk extension1824 and 5-Bone tools from the foundation of the large stone wall in the eastern baulk extension1829-Obsidian arrowhead from the foundation of the large stonewall in the eastern baulk extension.1846UbaidBead from the subfloor associated with the collapsed house.1864UbaidBead from the fill on the south side of wall Locus 159, outside of the collapsed house.1865UbaidSpindle whorl from the fill on the south side of wall Locus 159, outside the collapsed house.1869UbaidLoom weight from the fill on the south side of wall Locus 159, outside the collapsed house.1874-Ceramic Figurine from unstratified contexts in the southeast corner of the trench.1881, 20UbaidLoom Weight from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house1882UbaidBone ring from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house18810, 11, 12, 14, 15, 16, 17, 23UbaidGrinding stones from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house.18819UbaidSpindle whorl from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house18822UbaidPestle from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house18821UbaidBone Awl from the Ubaid courtyard wall south of the collapsed house1926UbaidJar stopper from an outdoor work surface below the collapsed house1949UbaidJar stopper from the collapsed house.19410UbaidMiniature bowl from the collapsed house19411UbaidHammerstone from the collapsed house19412UbaidLithic scraper from the collapsed house19413, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, 24UbaidSpindle whorls from the collapsed house19421, 23, 25, 27Ubaid Beads from the collapsed house19424Ubaid Worked shell from the collapsed house&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Interpretation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Excavations this year in D6 uncovered four distinct phases of occupation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li class="body_text_indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Middle Bronze occupations with at least 7 different levels of the street.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="body_text_indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Late Chalcolithic 1 occupation identified by ceramic finds and ephemeral architecture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="body_text_indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;Early Northern Ubaid – represented by the collapsed house and associated courtyard features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="body_text_indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;span&gt;An earlier more ephemeral Ubaid occupation below the collapsed house represented by outdoor work surfaces and a potential hearth.&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Middle Bronze layers are represented by the Loci 84 to 118, with a few exceptions in the northwest portion of the trench (Loci 107 and 114). There were seven distinct levels for the Middle Bronze street however architecture to the east of the wall most likely would have been removed by slope erosion, which is supported by the mixed contexts and soil differences in much of the eastern portion of the trench in the Middle Bronze deposits. Only the stonewall foundations of Locus 87 and 112 provide any evidence for architecture along the streets in the Middle Bronze period.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Late Chalcolithic occupation is discerned best as the two parallel walls in Locus 117 and Locus 131 in which no connecting architectural remains were uncovered, and by the burnt surface in Locus 124 and 129, as well as the lithic concentration below them in Locus 147. The Late Chalcolithic 1 period is defined as Loci 120-153, with the exceptions of several loci in the extreme eastern portion of the trench that contained mixed contexts (Loci 127,134, and 137). The walls in Locus 117 and Locus 131 may have been ephemeral courtyard or outdoor walls for an associated complex elsewhere on the mound, or may have been connected but highly affected by erosional processes. One peculiar note is that the Middle Bronze streets directly sealed the LC1 deposits, with no evidence of Early Bronze occupation on this portion of the mound (with the exception of Locus 170, which may represent the foundation of the EB city wall uncovered in other trenches at the site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Early Northern Ubaid occupation is represented by the collapsed house and associated courtyard features found in Loci 159, 167-188, and 193. Wall Locus 159 forms the southern most wall of the house that extends into Trench D4, where the western wall runs into the baulk, suggesting that the southwestern corner of the building and the series of associated western rooms are located in the western baulk of D6. Wall Locus 159 runs east to west into the eastern baulk of D6 where it formed the southeast corner of the building and connects to the walls uncovered in Trenches D8 and D5. The collapsed house provides an unprecedented look into the life of people in the Ubaid providing evidence for both the production of clothing and the production of body adornments in the form of beads and pendants. The presence of large concentrations of burnt seeds should be able to inform us more of their subsistence and agricultural practices upon further analysis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text_indent" awml:style="Body Text Indent" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally the earliest occupation discovered in Trench D6 is Ubaid in date but with only ephemeral outdoor surfaces and one hearth in Loci 188-192. The exposure here is limited purely to the area of the collapsed house and a larger exposure may yield evidence of earlier architecture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-6-2007-07-03-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/3166FFD7-0E8E-4A05-D947-2BF27E09D791</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-6-2007-07-03-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F3166FFD7-0E8E-4A05-D947-2BF27E09D791</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830535</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813647</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/3166FFD7-0E8E-4A05-D947-2BF27E09D791">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 6</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>3166FFD7-0E8E-4A05-D947-2BF27E09D791</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:46:06-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:46:06</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
