<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="316AB86A-7DEF-4B88-5880-52A96E1AF3C1" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>E-2-2005-06-023-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>28E6FA74-3C47-4738-8EAF-8E40B070EF83</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/190E49F3-A269-4B34-94DF-F931736406E4">190E49F3-A269-4B34-94DF-F931736406E4</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-23</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
              <oc:name>Area E</oc:name>
              <oc:id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:E-2-2005-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area E, Trench 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. Henecke&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench E2 is located half way up the southern side of the tepe, facing the Tigris River. In 2000, a 2 x 1 meter sounding (E1) was excavated in this area, and during the 2004 season, the sounding was enlarged to 5.8 x 4 meters. The trench lies in close proximity to area D, and although the area between them is disturbed by numerous pits (see D10), it may be possible to use E2 and D8 for comparisions. In the previous season, the excavators discovered a thick deposit from a 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millenium road, which most likely runs around the tepe, and at lower levels, the excavators uncovered Ubaid sherds and concentrations of chert and obsidian lithics. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I began the season by expanding the southeastern baulk by 2 meters (L41), and the trench now has the dimensions of 5.9 x 6. Our goal this season was to bring the entire trench down to the sounding level (about 586.35 meters above sea level), and by enlarging the trench, we hoped to gain a large perspective into these lower levels. The sounding produced quantities of decorated Ubaid sherds and obsidian flakes, and by reaching the sounding level, we hoped to reveal more of these Ubaid levels. My starting elevations were: W 587.60, N 587.74, E 587.46 and S 587.72, with a datum height of 590.01. My first action was to identity and renumber old loci from the previous season. This included the fill in the western corner (old L32, new L48) and fill in the center of the western half (old L36, new L47). I was able to identify mudbrick wall L35 and 37 from last season (new L42 and 43), but I combined L38 – which was thought to be a mudbrick wall – and 39 into a single fill locus (L46). I also combined the pebbly area (L2 and 10) above the sounding into a single locus (L44). Although the last day plan from last season showed features within the old sounding level, I made it a single locus (L45) because the surface appeared very weathered. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our initial efforts at the beginning of the season were designed at clearing away old topsoil and features from last season. We removed the baulk (L41) very quickly, and although the topsoil was removed, the fill beneath this (L49) was also heavily disturbed. It was not until May 22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, when we uncovered the group of pottery (L55) against wall L43 that we could be certain this area contained uncontaminated contexts. Erosion off the tepe has been a major factor in mixing the fill, and the erosion line is clearly visible in the northeastern and southwestern baulks. Until we excavated beyond this line, the entire area was predominatley mixed contexts. In addition to the effects of erosion, weathering throughout the year had damaged many of last year’s features. Walls L43 and 42 crisscrossed the trench, but unfortunatley, they were too partial and disconnected to reveal anything significant about architecture. Therefore, I quickly excavated them to reveal fresh surfaces beneath. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The first week of excavation was useful for highlighting two points that would be continous throughout the season. Natural erosion and human activity – namely, pits – contributed to the mixing of large portions of the trench, and the identification of these forces was very useful for understanding the trench’s stratigraphy and layout. Secondly, although the trench had been enlarged, it was very difficult to correlate features across the site. As with walls L43 and L42, many of the surfaces and walls we uncovered were partial and/or isolated, but a grasp of the cause of these disturbances may elucidate the missing gaps in the trench’s picture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Upon removal of L42, which is visible to a height of 8 courses in the southwestern baulk, we uncovered sealed surface L50. After scraping L44, we uncovered a similar surface. The surface had been blownout, and the two did not directly touch except in the baulk. About 20 centimeters below this level, within the subsurface soil (L52) was a stone wall (L53), and this wall may have blownout this pebble and sherd encrusted surface. The wall is composed of medium sized stones, and there is a door socket near the northwestern baulk. We also found a stone with similar alignment beneath L48, and I believe this wall stretched across this area. I took a HAP sample (L51), a soil sample and sifted all material, and although it was sealed, the pottery is a mixture of EB and Ubaid. Mudbrick wall L42 above it, however, was from the Chalcolithic, and it can be assumed that L53 is a later intrusion into this architecture. However, on the surface of the L44 subsoil (L54), we found a small row of mudbricks. This may be mudbrick slump off the wall, which would place the wall in an earlier period that the surfaces.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rather than removing L43, I began to clear away L49 in order to see how far the wall extended into the southeastern baulk. The wall did not seem to be effected by erosional activity until the extreme eastern end, and this may indicate the extent of the erosion during this period. Several interesting features emerged during the excavation of L49, including evidence for an oven installation with a small pebbled surface nearby. We discovered a few pieces from a tanoor oven (KT 14) along with ashy soil, and the pebbled surface (L56) was also too partial to connect with other features. There was also an incomplete human burial (L62) near the eastern corner. The burial pit had most likely been dug into the side of the tepe at a later period, and only a jaw, leg and a few ribs remained. Pressed up against the join between the southwestern baulk and L43, we found a group of 5 pots apparently in their original position. The pots are largely whole (KT 5-12), with the soil preserved in 3 of them. They appear to be from the EB or Late Chalcolithic, and touch both the wall and a packed mud surface (L60). The surface is burnt in the western corner, and the fill above it contained ash and carbon. I took a HAP (L57) and sifted all material from this floor. After removing the pots, a corner in L43 is visible, and we believe that both the pots and the wall continue into the southwestern baulk. Later in the season, while we were waiting to take plan shots, we excavated a 2 x 3 area (L82) in the southwestern baulk in an effort to find the remainder of this feature. Unfortunatley, we only had time to remove about a meter of topsoil – in which we discovered the same 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millenium floor – and excavation will have to wait until next season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;An interesting connection between various features at this level is visible in the baulks. It appears that the line of L50 and 44 may extend across towards L43. This would place these floors concurrent with L60 and the pot grouping in L55. Further, it seems that the line may also run across toward L56, which would connect this partial surface with the rest of the trench. I believe the features at this level are connected and can be viewed as a whole.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the removal of both these walls and the L43 subsoil (L64), the number of loci collapsed, and the trench was divided between the large mixed fill L65 and the area to the northwest of the sounding level (L58). The area was marked by a distinct grayish soil, which continued into the deeper levels of the trench. L58 was cut by a small ash pit (L63), which may have been associated with or related to the pebbled surface L66. The pit seems to have at least cut through this surface. L66 is the first in a series of floors (L81, L94) that have a similar position and dimensions. I took a HAP (L67) from this small area, which only had a volume of 36 L, and removed its subsurface (L68). After the removal of L69 – grayish fill – the area was naturally divided by clefts in the soil, which were intially thought to indicate pits or walls, and further split by the L94 surface. L86 and 101 abutted L70 and contained a series of ashy lenses and ashy deposits directly adjacent to the wall. This seems to indicate some activity on this side of the wall. L84, 87, 102 and 104 in the northern corner were a generic gray compact fill with little cultural material.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our first significant feature emerged at the end of May. Within L65, a wall composed of medium to large stones, emerged with approximatley the same position and alignment as L53. This wall formed the boundary between the expanding grayish soils of L58 and 69 and the light tan fill to the north (L71). At the same time, mudbrick wall L72 appeared across the southern corner, leaving a small section of fill (L73) in the corner. The fill between these two areas was very mixed (L71 and 76), but beneath this L78 contained a scattering of pebbles across the entire area. The scatter was low density but had the appearance of a street surface. It is our belief that L70, 72 and 78 was a street with bounded by two structures. When we finally removed L72, it was apparent that the pebbly surface abutted the wall and did not pass beneath it. The grayish soil to the north of L70 (L69), may have been the interior of this structure, although no cultural materials were found to confirm this. We took a plan shot of this feature, and I also took a HAP (L83) and soil sample, in addition to sifting the entire L78 surface. The sherds from this surface are predominatley from the Chalcolithic. L70 extended fairly deeply into the surface -- about 3 stone heights – and half was removed on 6/1 and the remainder on 6/8. It was also difficult to find the bottom of L72, and I cut away a .5 meter section along the southwestern baulk to find it’s limits. The wall in this part only had a single course, while there are three visible in the southeastern baulk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I divided the area – formerly L65 – to the southeast of L45 into a northern (L75) and southern (L77) half. I wanted to ensure that if the extreme end of the trench was still being effected by erosion, these mixed contexts would not contaminate other areas. It seemed that the continuation of L72 mudbricks into the baulk suggested the soil had not been disturbed. We excavated ash pit L74 from the eastern corner, cutting L77, and at the bottom found a row of small stones (L92). Stretching diagonally across L77 and 75 was a mudbrick wall (L79), although it did not extend beneath L78, and was probably disrupted by the mixed fill and pits beneath that area. The wall did not extend as far as originally thought, and later in the season, I removed L91 as extra soil to the east of the actual bricks. This was was fairly insubstantial and may in fact have only been a pile of mudbricks. When removing L91, we found traces of organic pseudomorph that suggested a surface, but there was no evidence of this beneath the wall. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This entire area of the trench – about 2.5 x 2.5 meters – was so small that it was only after excavation that we were able to identify several features. I excavated L77 as fill, and I initially attributed mudbrick debris and organic pseudomorph to mudbrick slump from L79. I now believe that there may have been a surface in this area, perhaps connected to the evidence in L91 and associated with L79. We discovered a mortar stone and weight ? (KT 4 and 5) resting upright and in a line, which may be more evidence for a surface in this area. L75 also seems to have contained more than mere fill. I dug the locus in 15 centimeter chunks, but after its removal I noticed a dark line in the wall of L79. This may have been a burnt layer or a differentiation in the fill, but it did not appear in our excavation. I assigned L80 to the area to the east of L75 because there was a distinct line in the soil between these sections. It is possible that L75 was a pit that cut through L80, which why it does not appear in other areas. L80, 85, 88 and 90 are a series of ashy fill deposits and flat lying pot sherds and lithics. The area was so small – 1.5 x 1 meter – that it was impossible to tell if any of these levels were surfaces, and I believe L85 may have been several layers of floors resting atop one another. These levels maybe present to a larger extent in the northeastern baulk. It is impossible to connect these loci with any other surfaces or walls, and there is no evidence for them in last year’s day plans. At the bottom of these layers was a pile of stone and lithic fragments – including production material, cores and flakes – and this may be the remains of a lithic production area (L106), and this feature was in contact with L92. As I reached the sounding level in this area, I made each section part of L100, which was even with L45.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;When I finally reached the sounding level, the trench was divided into L101 and 104 in the northwestern half, L103 – a very mixed fill, cut by ash pit L105 – in the western half and L45 and 100 in the eastern half. At this point, I cleaned and renumbered the loci. The trench is now divided into roughly equal halves along the east-west diagonal. After removing the thin L45 weathered surface, the northern half contained L107, 108 and 111. This area is clearly distinct in color and texture from the rest of the trench, being more gray and compact. Two sections of mudbrick wall (L116/114) span the divide, and though cut out by pits, the wall seems to be a continous structure. To the south, L110 and 112 are fill and L119 is a stone wall cut by L105. This entire section of the trench, specifically near L112, seems riddled with pits, which explains much of the mixed content of the fill loci (65, 98 and 103) above. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A plastered surface, with decorated Ubaid sherds and lithics (L118) emerged from L108, and soon spread across the entire area to the north of L116/114. The plaster clearly abuts L116, and in fact, indicates a row of bricks no longer preserved on this wall. I believe that this surface is the predecessor of the series of more fragmentary surfaces discovered above it (L66, 81 and 94), which may have been blownout by later accumulations. Beneath this surface was a thin subsoil that contained evidence for lithic production (KT 7 and 8). The surface beneath this L134, was very similar to L118, although the plaster was more poorly preserved, and it contained further evidence for domestic activities, including a beer strainer and mortar stone (KT 4 and 11). I took HAP samples (L126 and 135) from both surfaces. Initially, we thought that L118 may have been an interior surface -- associated with L116/114, 120 and 119 – but it now seems that this area was the exterior while the southern half is the structural interior. This is further indicated by the architecture (L143) discovered at the end of the season. These areas are clearly in Ubaid context and will be very important for understanding domestic activities from this period. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;All these levels are associated with the L114/116 wall. L114 is a well preserved mudbrick wall with three rows, while the L116 section is only preserved in two disjointed rows. There is, however, Ubaid sherds wedged into L116 that are essential for dating this wall (KT 1). Pits L117, 115 and 124 cut into this wall, and L114 -- the complete wall – is visible beneath these pits. Clearly, the pits are of a later date than L114. On 6/20 and 6/22, I removed the standing portion of L116 and closed this locus, combining the entire wall into L114. While removing L116, I noticed that L134 passes beneath a section of this wall, which I believe indicates and addition or modification of the wall rather than the presence of a different wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L119 is a stone wall running almost parallel to L116, and it was originally thought that these two formed another street feature. However, the excavation of the area between these walls (L110, 120 and 132) gave no indication of a street surface. It is possible that the street was an interface rather than a true surface. The fill in L120 was much more pebbly and loose near L116 and more compacted by L119. I believe the scattering of pebbles in L120 is the best possibility for a street surface. Evidence for erosion in the northwestern baulk suggests a different interpretation of the relationship between L114/116 and areas south of L119. There are mudbricks visible in the northwestern baulk, and although L116 does not physically extend this far, I believe they are the same. Above these bricks is a dark gray line, which may indicate the line of erosion off the tepe. In this case, all the material south of L119 may have been effected by erosion and impossible to associate with L114/116. Depending on where the erosion line falls, L119 may be of an entirely separate context that L116/114. South of L119, were two small pebble surfaces (L122 and 133), cut by various pits (L105 and 123). L122 in particular may have been associated with the street feature, but it did not touch L119, which maybe a result of erosional forces. I took a HAP sample from this surface (L125) and sifted and sampled all L133.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, in the last few days of the season, we found the outline of a single cell room. L114 is the northern wall, and L143 is the west, east and south walls to this room. Within the room (L137) was organic residue, possibly evidence for the cleaning out of grain storage, in addition to a large pot burial carved into L114. The burial contains an adult skeleton, possibly female, with porous holes in the skull. On either side of the cell room is an area of indistinguishable mudbrick (L144 and 142). I believe L144, which extends into the southwestern baulk, is a corner of another cell room that may be filled with mudbrick debris. L142 may also have been another cell room, which was cut by pit L147. The entire structure probably extended to the south, but was cut out by pits and erosion. This structure is very interesting in view of the architecture in D8, which has an entire Ubaid house with similar cell room architecture. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the season, the trench has only begun to reveal Ubaid levels, and there are numerous indications that much more lies beneath the surface. For example, the L134 subsoil (L145) contains a concentration of stones, which seems to indicate the arrival of another surface. Also, there is a burnt line beneath this level visible in the wall of pit L124 and evidence for another surface at the bottom of this pit. Next year we should continue to excavate in this area to find more information about the cell room structure and earlier Ubaid levels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: E-2-2005-06-023-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/316AB86A-7DEF-4B88-5880-52A96E1AF3C1</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+E-2-2005-06-023-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F316AB86A-7DEF-4B88-5880-52A96E1AF3C1</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830333</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813539</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="contained" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
        <oc:source_name>Area E</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:53:46-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:53:46</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
