<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="33947A1D-1CB1-470C-BC80-08FF24295C63" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-1-2000-Journal</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">31A138EB-DB5C-4E78-1354-336F68577C36</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/31A138EB-DB5C-4E78-1354-336F68577C36">
        <oc:name>Trench 1</oc:name>
        <oc:id>31A138EB-DB5C-4E78-1354-336F68577C36</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-1-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 6, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This is a new Trench!  We decided to excavate this new trench, which is located on the east side slope of the tepe (close to facing Tigris), about 15 m down from the top of the tepe.  This side has a steep slope, but the area D is somewhat flat and sticks out, like a small bump.  The initial thinking was to find a earlier occupation, such as Uruk period.  The location of the Trench 1 was chosen randomly and Trench 2 is made at the North side.  Because of the steep slope, it was difficult to set-up a stright trench.  After we have the total station, we could be more accurate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1000	This locus represent the top-soil and washed/eroded layer.  The east side of the trench is about 1.5 m lower than the West side.  North-South does not have much angle.  Because of this slope, there will be deep zone of disturbance in top area of this trench.  The purpose of this locus is to create a leveled ground.  However, I did not wanted to level the entire trench in one shot, so decided to divide the trench into East and West half.  I put the line across 2 m from the East and made the workers level the East half first and the West half later.  This will create an arbitrary step at the center of the trench (ideally 75 cm high wall).  In this way, I could see the profile at the center and decide rather it will be a better idea to excavat the entire trench at one time.  If the west half of the trench is in disturbed area, I should level the surface and keep on excavating.  However, if I find some kind of undisturbed area, I have to devise a new plan.  In any case, dividing the trench, I think, will be a safe-guard against distroying an area of occupational level.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This locus had many pot sherds, mainly from lower elevation (not near surface), and some bones.  Found several flakes, so it might be an indication of earlier occupation (but pottery does not suggest that idea? mainly Hellenistic?).  There was a concentration of several large rocks at the SW corner of the trench (about 25 cm from both south and west) , but it is most likely a random concentration of rocks.  It does not follow any shape; it is placed irregulary.  We found no large rocks at the East half of the trench, and we leveled the East half today.  We will be working on the West half tomorrow.  Anyway, West half seems to contain more large rocks, I do not know why.  Also, at the near end of the day, Ihsan found concentration of the large fragments of pot sherds and some large rocks.  It does not seems to represent any surface or non-disturbed area, but I will clean the surface and see what is going on around.  It is too close to the surface so my suggestion is to just go deeper!  In first several levels, I will try and push myself to excavte faster and deeper (but try not to destroy any cultural levels); the answer lies below!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 7, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1000	Still working on the layer of disturbed zone.  Now concentrating on the west half of the trench.  In this west side, we found more pottery. lithics, and bones.  Especially, we found many worked stones.  I found a stone bowl (mortar), and stone fish-net weight?(circular grind-stone with hole in the center.  Also, several flat, rectangular round edged stones.  I do not know why we are getting these materials from this level.  pottery seems to be Hellenistic in nature, but lithics and other finds looks like a neolithic site.  there were some soil variation in the locus.  Andy thinks it is just a baked surface since it is too close to the surface.  We have been seeing the same soil everywhere in this site, the hard compacted silt-like soil (almost like a mud-brick).  I took out the pot-smash as oone KT number (KT 1011).  I decided to close this locus; no definate reason to close, I am seeing some soil variation and it might be a good sign for getting close to the surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1001	This locus is the west halsf of the trench.  The purpose is to level the entire trench into flat surface.  But if we find something, I will close a locus and make a different locus.  Basically, the materials that coming out from this locus is same as locus 1000.  Many grind0stones and pottery.  I found several large rocks, especially concetrarted arond South side of the locus.  Later, we found out that there was a stone lined wall sticking out from the West balk.  This wall sticks out from the balk for about 30 cm and it ends there.  It probably the end of the wall.  This wall is made by piling up stones about 3 or 4 rows.  It is only a small portion that is exposed at this moment, so I must clean it up tomorrow and see what is the relationship withe the surface that I am seeing now.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today, we had a TV crew came to visit our site, and we came back from the site later than usual.  I tried my best to write a journal, but I might add some more tomorrow, since I am tired.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 8, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1001	  Today was kind of slow day.  Anyway, we strated out by scraping and brushing the surface of the 1002 (end of 1001).  when we were clearing, I found two posible pits, one at the Southest corner of the locus (south-central part of the trench) and another smaller pit at the North side, abuts to west balk.  At this point I assigned a new locus (I had an idea to change the locus from yesterday..)    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus  1002	These pits had darker soil and loosely compacted (crumble).  Also, soil was more sandy (fine sand).  The hard compacted area is white and silt.  Basically, about the same type of soil variation as in Area A trench 1, and possibly other areas.  The pit was about 1 m to 1.5 m.  Since this locus is still close to the surface, I decided not to make a new loci for these pits.  However, I gave different KT numbers for the artifacts.  (KT1033 KT1034 KT1035 KT1036).  The pit were farly shallow, about 10 cm deep.  Bottom of the pit was same as other compacted area.  We took a photo after excavating the pits.  I think these were just a deep area and disturbed zone.  Now, all the soil in this locus looks all the same, except for the wall that sticking out from the west balk.  I decided to take the locus down to the finishing level of the locus 1000 at the east side.  we start bashing the soil from the south-side.  Ihsan found some large rocks near the possible wall.  I have not cleaned the area well, so I have to wait for tomorrow, but the rocks seems to be just a collapse.  we did not find any large rocks on the East-side (locus 1000).  About KT 1039, this was kind of wired find.  It looks like a brick.  But it could be a piece of pottery?  It is kind of square in shape but curves up at the edge.  Also, surface seem to be grinded down.  It could be a pallet?  It actually reminds me of the incense burner from Oman that was discovered in Oman.  I don't know what it could be.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	I'm not sure why today was unproductive day.  Workers were complaining about the not having the tent, and we took about an hour or so to take a picture, and some other unknown factors.  Maybe I got used to bashing 1 m a day for last two days, so I'm just feeling this way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 9, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1002	Since we did not finish Locus 1002, our purpose for today was to bash Locus 1002 and start working on Locus 1003, which will be a flat surface!   We took the South East portion of the locus and proceed to Northern portion of the locus.  Today, my two workers were somewhat slacking.  Perhaps, I should make them work more, or get a new worker.  Anyway, I cleared the possible wall.  The soil around the wall seemed lettle compacted than around the area, but as we clearing the Locus 1002, it tirned out that the whole SW section of the Locus was somewhat compacted.  Also, Deeper part of the Locus were compacted.  It seems to be just a variation in the soil (from erosion?).  Does not seems to represent any definate cultural levels; no boundary of soil variation, just gradual change.  I think (and also Bradley) that this layer is just disturbed sub-topsoil.  Although the pile of rocks seems to be in line, only a small section of them are in my trench.  If I could dug into the balk, I could know this structure better.  The wall was made from piling up the rocks, smaller and round rocks on bottom, and flat and bigger rocks on top.  Smaller rocks is about 15 cm in diameter, and larger rocks is about 20 - 30 cm in diameter and app 10 cm thick.  Only one pot sherds were discovered while destroying the wall.  Since we have a photo, it should be OK to destroy this wall.  It seems that Phill got a similar structure in his trench.  The wall was about 15 cm in height, and 25 cm wide.  The front seems to round up a bit, but several rocks that I found around this structure is probably a fallen rocks from the wall, so the actual shape of this is in mystery.  After excavating few levels, we will know more about this wall by looking at the section.  Speaking about section, when I was strightening the section, a balk right below a rock seemed somewhat softer and had a brownish color.  Near the end of excavating this Locus, I found small pile of rocks sticking out from the North balk (again too close to the balk).  This structure was near the ending surface of Locus 1002, so only few rocks are exposed.  There seems to be no large rocks are used, but only a pile of round rocks.  We will excavate around this structure? tomorrow as Locus 1003 and see the extent of this possible pile of rocks.  Other than what I mentioned above, there were no interesting feature from this Locus.  I put my workers to stright the balk, since I had a terrible balk.  Now the balk looks good.  Actually, ihsan is good at making stright wall.   We found some sherds while cleaning the balk.  I had them put in one place, but it seems like workers took them up to the dolmush.  I can not find them... I hope it is not mixed with other pot-sherds.  I did not had any tag or bag for those sherds.  It was my mistake to leave them out.  This Locus was kind of unproductive; I found less materials than Locus 1001.  There were no grind-stone and pile of small finds from this locus.  I found few shells, and possible? Ninevh 5 base.  The shape of the base seems to be N5, and color is light-greenish, and it is thin and well fired.  I want the result of pottery reading soon, if I could get them.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1003	After cleaning the surface and cleaning the balk, we started out bashing the surface of Locus 1003, from the North East corner.  I told them to bash the entire trench for 25 cm.  But they only took 10 cm or so.  It was close to the end of the day, so what I can do.  Once again, this locus 1003 is the first time that we leveled the entire trench.  We will dig this 4 m x 4 m, flat surface tomorrow.  I wish something happens tomorrow.    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 10, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1003	I'm writing this jounal a day after the actual day of excavation since we went to the week-end trip.  This is the first time I wrote the journal day after...  So, my description may contain some misleading remarks.  I decided to remove as much dirt as possible today.  As I mentioned above, this is the first time that the trench was leveled.  We started excavating from the East side and dug all the way to the West side.  The east side is still in sub-topsoil, but the west side could be in occupational level.  after clearing the surface, there were gradual line, but definate difference between the soil from west to east.  Conveniently, the soil seems to be divided just about 2 m line.  It was probably not a good idea to combine the west side of the trench and the east side of the trench.  After the bashing has fiished, I brushed the surface and see if there is any sign of occupation.  On the NW cornaer and SW corner, the soil seemed very compacted; almost like a mud-brick, especially on the North side.  The texture is silt, white-grey in color.  In the central part of the West side, soil was somewhat loosely cimpacted, and had some pebbles within the soil.  It also appeared brownish.  The soil on the North and West did not had any pebbles.  There was a definate difference in the soil (something is going on!).  Some soil of the NW looked like a mud-brick.  However, the bashing crew did a horrible job of making a flat surface, and I really could not tell what was going on.  The surface had many bumps and low spots.  I told them to make the West side more flat.  Also, the West side was much higher than the Eat side.  We finished our job for the day while flattening the West side.  So, tomorrow, we will make the surface nice and flat, and see the surface.  there might be a mud-brick surface!  About the east side, I will divide the trench into half (I don't like digging with two completely different levels) and excavate it deeper.   This is only my thought, but in the past, the area where my trench was the edge of the mound.  All the east side is just piled up erosion layer.  Dividing the trench seems like I am excavating two trenches in one trench; it will be more work!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 12, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Continue flattening the surface of 1003 on the west side.  This time, workers did better job.  We brushed and see the surface.  There was a definate line between loose soil and compacted soil.  East side is loose, gray, sub-topsoil.  I draw a line following the division of this transition.  I made the east side (loose, sub-topsoil) as locus 1004, and west side (compacted) as 1005.  While the workers took down the 1004, I excavated (destroyed) the pile of rocks that was floating at the North balk, about 1 m from the west. This structure waas made from several flat rocks of about 2 -5 cm in thickness, and rounded, about 4 - 6 cm in diameter.  There were several layer of this rocks, but not in particular order, but it was all layed flat.  But few rocks were round, or layed sideways.  This rock pile finished around 1002 and 1003 transition in profile, or little deeper.  The soil had no significant difference, it was not a mud-bricjk or mortor.  I found two pieces of teeth, probably horse in the rock pile.  The soil around the teeth seemed brownish in color.  I gave different KT numberes (1055 &amp;amp; 1056) for pottery and bones.  I gave them Locus 1002, since this structure was in that Locus.  I thought about assigning a new Locus, but the rock-pile did not seemed that significant.  I am not sure it was cultural or not.  Also, I took down another pile of rocks at the SW corner (1 m from W &amp;amp; S).  This pile was not layed on levels.  Just a conglomorate of 7 large rocks.  Soil around the pile seemed compacted and color looked brownish.  This pile did not had a flat rocks, and shape and the size of the rocks were irregular.  This, I doubt to be cultural.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1004	we took several cm down, but found almost nothing.  We will take down more tomorrow and hope to find some cultural layer. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 13, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1004	I sent in some bashing crew, which was not perfect, but did a good job, today to excavate this Locus on the East side of the hill.  Told them to bash 50 cm, or until find something different.  There were not really any interesting feature, but at one point, soil gradually became harder.  (about mid-way, I don't know the exact elevation).  The soil had variation, some area were hard (but not as hard as the soil in Locus 1005), and had some deep loose soil.  I could polk a trowel into some areas easily, but it dis not follow any definate shape, so it was not a pit; cause by washing down of the soil.  AFter a while, we reached the white, compacted, silt-like layer, which is almost exactly looks same as the soil of Locus 1005.  It was strange that the difference in soil followed the line that I made.  I thought the white soil will have a gradual slope, but the loose soil seemed to went down in straight line, except for one area in the center where there is a divot.  This was probaby some variation in the soil.  The white layer seemed to gradually filled this space as we excavte deeper.  I think that thiis could be a trace of ancient land-shape, or caused by mud-slide.  The white-compacted soil did had a little slope, but it was not a gradual slope at all.  We closed the Locus when we reached the white compacted layer. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1005	I first thought about excavating the whole West half as I did in Locus 1004, but Andy took a look at D2 and found a possible mud-brick wall at the SW corner of the trench.  Since my trench is just south of the D2, this is just 1 m away from the possible mud-brick that I found in NW corner of my trench.  So, I decided to scrape off the surface (again) and see what is going on.  Last time, the workers did a horrible job on strightening the surface, so I told then to do a better job and I scraped the surface by myself.  We took off about 5 to 10 cm or so.  There still does not seems to have a mud-brick, although it kind of looks like it in some area.  There are grooves in the hard-mud that is filled with loose soil, in stright line, but one here and there.  Also, I found a strange discoloration of the soil.  When I brush, it looked like a pile of ash, but when I scrape, I found a bluish-gray color.  This color is about 10 cm thick and follow a circle.  It starts from the edge of NW corner, than curves to south, and curves back to the west balk.  It could be a top of an oven, but it is hard to tell at this pint.  The soil inside this circle seems to be harder than the soil outside.  We ran out of time when I strat seeing this shape,  I will see this closely tomorrow. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 15, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1005	Well, yesterday I had a fever and did not go out to the site.  So, today, I'm not feeling that great but I did my best.  Day before yesterday, I found a dark-bluish discoloration in the NW corner of the trench.  Today, I tried to define what this is.  I excavated arond and inside, but it seems to be just a variation in the soil.  The soil seems to be burnt, since it had some small frag of charcoal within.  It did not follow any definate shape.  I found same soil arond it when I dug deeper.  I thought it could be an oven, but the soil was not ashy.  I found a flat-compacted mud below these discoloration.  But, this too had not distinctive shape, and had many animal holes around them.  Found no pottery, lithics, or bones around.  Before I began excavting this area, I thought about giving a different Locus number, but I decided not to.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Now, we began bashing the rest of Locus 1005.  We first excavated about 20 cm and see what was there, but it was taking longer than I thought, so I decided to knock the whole thing down at once.  I lost 1 day, and the days that is left is short, so I must hurry up and level this trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 16, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today, I slept in for a while in Bismil and came after the breakfast.  Workers were bashing before I arrived.  I was feeling better, but not in a perfect state; I had approximately 76.38021 % of my average strength today.  I was drawing a section of the D3 and did not concentrate on what was going on at the trench 1. I hope they were doing a good job.  There are still some soil left to dig tommorow.  We will finish this trench.  Level the whole trench, stright the balk and I'm out of here!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;TRENCH SUMMARY OF AREA D TRENCH 1 (before pottery reading)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The purpose of this trench was to reach the early occupational level of the site since the area D was located at the lower part of the site.  During a survey, we found some pot-sherds from early period (Chalcolithic, Uruk, etc).  Area D is located at the east side of the Tepe below a steep hill where there is relatively flat area like a hump that sticks out from the Tepe.  We did not achieved our purpose in this season.  Because of the deep disturbed top and sub-top soil, it took us a week to excavte to reach the possible cultural level, and we began excavte this area during a last week.  We have not looked at the pottery in detail, so I am not certain about the age of the Loci that I excavated.  Although I am not a pottery expert by any sense, most of the pottery appears to be from the Hellenistic period.  Lower levels seems to be earlier.  We must wait for the pottery reading.  However, this area still looks promising for next season.   Trench 3, which is located 1 m West (1 m uphill) of Trench 1 had multiple layer of surfaces and possible Hellenistic wall, or a path.  When I walked around this area, especially below the area D, I found several fragments of early pottery, even possible Ubaid rim-sherd, many lithics, such as obsidian.  Also, from this trench, and Trench 2, which is just North of this trench, seems to produce more lithics and grind-stone than other areas.  Since we finish excavting the disturbed zone, if we given several days to excavte, there is a great possibility that we could achieve our original purpose of this Area. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;LOCUS 1000  (E 85.34-85.22  W 86.76-86.05)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This Locus is the top-soil and heavily disturbed.  Because of the steep slope, I expected to have a deep top and sub-topsoil.  Interesting enough, I found many worked stone artifacts, such as stone-bowl, possible weight (circular shape with a hole in the center), and others; for more info look at the KT 1003,1005, 1007, 1008, 1010, 1013, 1014, 1015, 1017, 1018, 1019, 1022, 1024).  First I thought this could be the indication of the early occupation of this area.  Near the North balk, about 1 m from the west balk, I found a concentration of the pottery.  It appears to be a pot-smash, but it is too close to the present surface (KT 1011).  I found a hard compacted layer of the soil below this potsmash, and gave a new Locus 1001.  Because of the slope, I decide to assigne locus 1001 for only west side of the trench.  We did not excavte much in the east side; as I mentioned above, West side had a compacted soil, but East half was still in top-soil.  I divided the trench in half, and made a arbitrary steps at the 2 m line.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1001 (West 1/2    86.05-85.86) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The purpose of this Locus was to level the entire trench flat, unless we reach a possible cultural layer.   There was a possible stone piled wall (86.13) at the SW corner of the trench, and found  2 possible pit, so I closed the Locus and gave Locus 1002.  We found several large rocks around this possible wall; probably fallen from the wall.  The soil arond the wall seemed somewhat compacted, but did not seems to be much of anything.  The wall was made of piling up the flat and round rocks for about 30 cm in height.  In this locus, above and below, I found sevral brick fragments, those could be Hellenistic in age.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1002 (West 1/2  85.86-85.63)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Since we found 2 possible pit, and soil was more compacted than locus 1001.  First I thought that this could be a cultural surface.  The stone lined wall finished in this Locus.  Also, we found a pile of rocks in the North balk.  A possible pit were located on the South-centarl section of the trench, irregular shape of about 1.75 m in length and 1 m + wide.  the another pit was smaller, and it was located on the west balk, on the north side, about 1.25 m in length.  I excavted both pits, and found relatively few pot-sherds, bricks, lithics, and bones.  (chech KT 1033, 1034, 1035, and 1036).  These pits seemed to be just a variation in the soil.  The shape of the pit was irregular, and did not have uniform depth.  I decided to make the whole trench flat.  The pile of rocks that I found near the North balk was constructed by flat-rocks, and found a possible equid teeth.  (KT 1055 and KT 1056).  In general soil seemed to be somewhat vary in nature and disturbed, it could be still in the sub-top soil, especilly in the Eastern side of this Locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1003 (85.63 - 85.20)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This is the first time that I had a flat trench!  Strange enough, there is less worked stone in lower levels.  I found a pile of rocks about 1 m away from the SW corner of the trench. However, this did not look like constructed by human.  Soil was same as inside and around the rocks.  Some rocks were layed flat but many rocks were on side.  I excavated for about 30 cm, and found a line between loose and compacted.  This line roughly followed the 1.5 m line from East balk.  Loose soil to the East is probably still in the top-soil but the west side could be in cultural level.  I decided to excavted the loose soil (Locus 1004) first and than compacted soil (Locus 1005).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1004 (85.20 - 84.75)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This Locus is the East side of the line which is loose soil.  I thought that the Compacted soil will gradually slopes down, but it more or less went down straight.  One area at the center had a slope of compacted soil.  About 30 - 40 cm below, we found a compacted soil, which is similar to the soil west -side.  I think at this point, it is below the top-soil.  There were some pottery and lithics.  Found obsidian fagments and several pieces of bricks from this Locus.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1005 (85.20 - 84.84)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This Locus is the west side of the trench with the hard compacted soil.  This Locus started out with a promise of discovery, but turned out to be little disappointment.  In Northwest corner of the trench, I found a hard-compacted soil that looked as a mud-brick.  We tried to make the soil flat and see if there is a mud-brick or not.  There were few several lines, but were not stright and the soil looked disturbed.  In the same area, I found a band of dark soil that seemed to be in circular shape.   First I thought it could be an oven; the size and shape of the dark soil was similar to that of A1 Locus 1018.  This dark soil contained chrcoal.  I excavated and tried to define the shape.  When I start excavating, it turned out that the shae was irregular and had more dark-soil below.  I decided to bash this area and make the trench flat.  So that next year, when someone comes back, they will have a flat trench.  Found grind-stone and Obsidian from this Locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	For this season, the Area D trench 1 resulted in some disappointment, but for next year, there is a great chance of discovery of this Trench.  From this season, we basically removed the thick top-soil that was washed down from the steep slope.  For next year, we should reach the earlier ocuupational levels.  We found many grind-stones, lithics, and Obsidian.  All pottery seems to be from Hellenistic age, but still wait to be seen.        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-1-2000-Journal</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/33947A1D-1CB1-470C-BC80-08FF24295C63</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-1-2000-Journal&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F33947A1D-1CB1-470C-BC80-08FF24295C63</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830706</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.8137</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/33947A1D-1CB1-470C-BC80-08FF24295C63">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 1</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>33947A1D-1CB1-470C-BC80-08FF24295C63</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:37:43-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:37:43</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
