<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-1-2000-08-17-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>27C7E1FC-4D84-4CCE-F5F6-B8902A4A7936</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/D9939E6E-D2B2-432E-09CC-96270B334D9F">D9939E6E-D2B2-432E-09CC-96270B334D9F</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-08-17</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Concurrent">1C7474B8-C05A-4714-FB5A-AD72D5FE79FB</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Next">8DD7AF00-D57F-40D3-AE81-F79C54F06A7E</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">C1BAA068-5C69-4B54-738D-81B41D8D08DF</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/C1BAA068-5C69-4B54-738D-81B41D8D08DF">
        <oc:name>Trench 1</oc:name>
        <oc:id>C1BAA068-5C69-4B54-738D-81B41D8D08DF</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/1C7474B8-C05A-4714-FB5A-AD72D5FE79FB">
        <oc:name>F-1-2000-08-17</oc:name>
        <oc:id>1C7474B8-C05A-4714-FB5A-AD72D5FE79FB</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Concurrent</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/8DD7AF00-D57F-40D3-AE81-F79C54F06A7E">
        <oc:name>F-1-2001-07-14</oc:name>
        <oc:id>8DD7AF00-D57F-40D3-AE81-F79C54F06A7E</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Next</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-1-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 7, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I began by digging 10cm in L1000 which was top soil.  That was too cautious it seems to be all top soil, so I told them to dig another 10cm.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At 20cm we came upon a lighter grey soil that was harder  packed with finer grain.  Most likely this is just sub top soil but I changed locus anyway to L1001.  I dug another 20cm down finding some large and beautiful possibly Hellenistic pot sherds in the North East corner of the trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy came by to warn us that we were digging in a heavily plowed zone, which would account for the mixed soil and the presence of modern debris. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are two large roots at the North Baulk and North East area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After going 20cm down L1001 we saw some soil that was a darker reddish brown and was a finer grain.  I changed locus again to L1002 and decided to go down another 20cm looking for more stuff.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unfortunately when I made this decision I didn't realize that it was so late in the day, so I just had everyone clean up the trench.  All the KT#1006-1008 have been canceled.  While cleaning the workers found a very small piece of jewelry with some bluish/green paint on it.  I labled it a small find.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We spent the rest of the day playing hackey sack waiting for the TV crew to leave.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 8, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We opened L1002 and found a lot of very soft soil at the south part of the trench because I had decided yesterday that the soil was a darker reddish brown color.  I orginally asked them to dig about 10cm but the soft soil enabled them to go almost 25cm without obstruction.  I thought I might have a pit so I told them to leave the harder parts of soil for me to inspect.  The soft soil might be due to the large roots in the area or because we're probably still in the plow zone.  We found a few large pot sherds and a handle. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I'm also watching F4, the sounding on the south part of the slope, but there doesn't seem to be anything going on there.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The workmen are constantly complaining and they think I'm crazy because I told them to dig 25 cm in the whole trench.  Those harder spots of soil I inspected ended up being the same as the rest of the trench which indicated that we didn't have a pit.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It took all morning to move all the dirt from L1002 but towards the end we came upon a concentration of bone at the NE corner of the trench.  Andy said that most of the bones were broken in antiquity or plowed thru because they are so close to the surface.  Before we found the bones imbeded in the soil we bagged the bones that we had disturbed in KT 1012.  I also decided to sift 2 buckets to catch the smaller bits of bone, but we found only a potsherd and a few scraps of bone.  We changed locus to L1004.  I troweled around looking for a pit as Andy instructed.  I doubt there is a pit in L1004 because all the soil felt the same as I was scraping.  Andy thinks the bones are human but he's not sure.  I spent the rest of my time articulating the bones.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While I was working on the disturbed burial, the workmen finished cleaning L1002 and began to push down 5cm in the new Locus L1003.  I changed locus because I saw that the soil had gone from a dark reddish brown to a light reddish grey.  The workmen uncovered a cobble and pebble surface about 5-7cm down which is very similar to the cobble surface in the sounding F4 just south of my trench and at about the same level as my surface accounting for the heavy slope at that side of the plateau.  There are also flecks of white plaster/limestone flecks strewn throughout the surface.  I also found some at the base of L1004.  These flecks can also be seen in a section of F4 directly above the cobble surface.  The workman were able to clean a the rock surface about 3m long and 1.25m wide.  This does not appear to be the extent of the surface and we plan on finding the rest tomorrow.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the very last minute Drew took a photo of the burial in L1004 and Andy grabbed the bones and bagged them.  I guess L1004 is closed now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 9, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;First thing I did today was sift the last bucket from L1004 from yesterday.  It was more like a 1/2 bucket and I was able to get a few scraps of bone out of it.  I closed that locus yesterday but didn't have time to sift that last bucket.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The workers are now trying to level the trench on top of the rock/pebble surface which appears to be concentrated in the centre of the trench heading East to West.  On the south side of the surface we are finding a very hard clay-like surface which may indicate a floor.  We cleaned and measured the newly leveled surface then took a photo.  We changed to the following locus numbers:  L1005 is the fill North of the rock surface, L1006 is the rock surface, L1007 is the fill south of the rock surface.  We began by digging a small sounding about 1/2 meter long at the western end of L1005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of course, while cleaning L1006 for phots we found yet another burial.  It is lodged in the eastern baulk on top of the rock surface of L1006.  There is a definite pit around the skeleton and the skull appears to be crushed.  We have uncovered a lot of upper torso such as the ribs, skull, teeth, and arms.  We articulated it as best we could then photographed it.  Hopefully we'll box it tomorrow. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile the sounding in L1005 was being dug about 5cm deep.  We were trying to find the next layers of the rock surface in L1006 there appear to be few stones continuing, but that might just be tumble.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also began digging in L1007 to see what was on the otherside of the rock surface where we found a very hard clay-like surface that felt suspiciously like mudbrick.  The soil close to the baulk was a darker grey while the soil away from it was the same as the rest only it was harder packed and had orange and black spots indicating burnt clay.  Bradley decided it wasn't a mudbrick and we chopped through it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last we screened all the dirt from L1008 and cleaned up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 10, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I checked my measurements for L1006 this morning, they seem to be fine.  We only have 2 workmen today so I've set them both to digging in L1005 and L1007.  I'm still trying to see what is under the rock surface by coming down another 5-10cm along either side of it.  The burial in L1008 will stay as it is for now, hopefully Andy will help me take it up today.  I want to cut a section out of rock surface today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I spent the morning articulating the burial in L1008.  We took up some bones and took some photos.  About 10cm below the rock surface L1005 we came upon another rock surface.  This surface is devoid of pottery/bone/cultural debris indicating that it might not have been made by humans.  The pebbles and cobbles are smaller in size than the surface in L1006.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We cleaned and photographed the surface in L1005.  We are now chopping a section in L1006 at its western end along the baulk to see if their new rock surface continues under the 1st rock surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L1008: The Burial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We found a small bone near the skull that was in the position a clavicle should be in but it is actually a broken ulna for a very young person.  The rest look like they belong to one person but that particular bone screws things up.  There are more bones still in the baulk.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 12, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I (Elvan) started to run this trench and we found a pit in the SE corner L1010 under L1007 or may it may cut L1007.  We are continuning in L1007, we tried to find some rocks from L1009.  But it doesn't seem to continue so we are continuing as L1007 in the southern part of the trench. The trench seems to be cut by something at the Southern part.  And before I started writing, they took off L1006, the bigger rocks. There weren't many left when I came. Only in the Eastern part of the trench in the middle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the West corner of L1007, there is a harder part but I didn't change the locus, I will check it after digging 10cm more.  Next to L1010 on the West there is a big rock between the pit and L1007 (actually in the pit L1010, Because the loose soil continiues around the rock.).  We screened one bucket from the pit.  There are some bones under the hard material in the Southwest corner.  There was always hard material here, in this corner. I remember that they were talking about finding amud-brick in this area but theree were no lines and there aren't lines now so it might be mud-brick debris or a mud brick wash. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We found a skull in the Southern quarter of the trench next to the Westen baulk but when we were digging we broke it.  Now we are waiting for Andy and screening.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kt1053 of L1007 is the part from the possible burial but we didn't change locus yet so it will be part of L1007.  After we found the burial we took 3 buckets of dirt but it is mixed with the soil from L1007.  The burial will be L1011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are now cutting the baulk and we will clean it after taking elevations and some measurements.  We will take a photo and we will remove the possible burial good.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 13, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started articulating the burial.  And we started to remove the rocks in L1009 from the East side.  Yesterday when we were leaving, we found a pot in the Southwest corner.  It is probably related to the burial.  And we found a spindle whorl, kt1056. This might be a burial good. It is located at the East of the burial near to the feet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are collecting the small bones together in kt1057 and we are saving all the soil in buckets.  We will screen them and then I will take a soil sample from the screened soil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are still articulating the bones L1011.  We couldn't find the feet and  the legs are broken.  There might be more than one person.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are trying to remove all of L1009 and the soil South of the burial might be another locus but I didn't decide yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Under L1009 there are some reddish parts, but to identify them, we have to sweep the trench and we don't have enough time today.  I decided to change the locus to L1012, but we didn't dig anything in this locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 14, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I think all the stuff under L1009 and a part of L1007 are made of the same material.  That will be L1012.  The soil at the Southwest corner will be L1013.  The pit is still there (L1010) and the burial L1011.   We started by sweeping the trench.  In L1012, there is a loose part (might be a pit) near the rocks in the middle.  It is only 2cm and doesn't look like a pit.  I didn't open a locus for this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;And in the Northeast part of the trench there is an ashy part with clay (reddish soil) L1014.  I started digging there to find out the borders and they found some kind of oven brick.  L1014 material is packed, ashy with clay.  Its color is reddish with gray and black.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;But there is the ashy part so L1012 is the soil except that area (under L1009 and some part of l007).  Now we are digging L1012 which is loose, medium sand mixed with silt.  We will level L1012 and we will try to find the continuation of L1014.  I screened all the soil from L1014 (ratio 1:1).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are some bricks in the South of L1014.  They seem to not be in the locus, though there is a chance they might be.  We hit them when we were digging from the South side of the trench.  For now they are part of L1012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There might be a wall in the Northern side of the trench near the South of L1014.  So we are now scraping and sweepping.  That is something certainly different and I will call it as a wall.  The wall will be L1015.  We didn't mix the bags at the South and North of the wall because we started digging from the South of L1012 and we were aware of the color difference in the North of the trench.  So I will keep the loci as it is now.  I won't change them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;So the North side of the trench (according to the wall) will be L1014 and the South side will be L1012.  But the pit (L1010), the burial (L1011) and the soil at the South part of the burial (L1013) are still there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;And the rocks in the middle of the trench seem to form a circle but they are now floating.  So I don't think to give them a new locus number.  But this is the part that I started as a pit.  So I made a mistake.  But there wasn't any pieces of pottery, bone or lithics at that area.  For tomorrow we are planning to cut a section in L1015 to identify the bricks.  And we are planning to work on the burial.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 15, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We cut a section from the South in L1015 (the wall).  Now we are trying to find the borders.  So I decided to go 5cm to the wall in L1014 (N of L1015).  Wee dug L1014 for 5-10cm and now I am planning to dig the wall to the same level and check the baulk section.  We are now leveling L1015 with L1014 and we will spray to see the lines again.  If there will be no lines I will close L1015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I saw some lines at the southern edge of the locus. So L1015 is still open then I decided to go 10-15 cm more in L1012. We started from the South-Eastern corner but after that I had to go to the hospital so I closed my trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 16,2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are digging 1012. We started that yeaterday but we couldn't finish that. This soil is hard and workers had hard time with this soil and the color is brownish gray.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are almost at the elevation of the L1010.Now we are sweaping so I will see if there is anything different.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We removed the rok in L1010 and the lowest is 47.77 and the rock is 45cm*50cm diagonally. Now here is a hole in L1010 because of the rock. It was almost standing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I removed the other 3 rocks that were forming a circle at the end of the wall L1015. We sprayed the ground in the North half of the trench. Because I thought that there were some lines. But I cannot see them anymore. Now one of the workers is cutting the baulk. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We found a bone at the lower part of the Southern baulk. Over L1010I will put this into a bag. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now I am planning to dig 5 more cm at the Northern half of the trnch. At that point I will change the locus. Because the burned mud-brick seems to end at that elevation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We couldn't find the end of the mud-brick so I decided to level the northern part of the trench with L1012. Then I will change the locus. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We closed the loci 1012, 1015, 1014 and opened 1016 which is the dirt under everything. The color seems like light brownish gray.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I dont want to remove the burial today so the loci around the burial 1011 is still there L1013 and a small part of the 1012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 17,2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I decided to level the rest of the trench to the bottom level of the pit 1010. ( I was planning to level L1016 with L1010 and leave the burial L1011 and the soil around the burial L1013)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started digging from the South -Eastern corner next to the pit 1010  and we broke a skull at that area. So there is a burial under the pit and the skull was under the rock.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;So we searched for other bones at the northern side of the skull but we couldn't find any. According to the bones (we found the piece of the forehead)Andy thinks that is a child. We are now screening the soil from that area and I will put the pieces from the screening to the same bone bag. It is interesting that thay placed the skull under that huge rock. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;So the burial will have the locus #1017. Probably we cannot find the borders of the burial because it is the last day, so I will seperate an area for this locus arbitrarily. I will use the borders of the pit L1010 because I think that the pit and the burial are related. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After that we decided that we won't destroy any more bones at the northern side of the trench so we started digging through that direction (1016). We leveled the trench ( L1016) and cut the baulks and took the closing elevations. But may be we will go and take the bones from the burial 1011 this week if we can find enough time. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-1-2000-08-17-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-1-2000-08-17-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.8313405</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.815388</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 1</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:16:35-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:16:35</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,600 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3600</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 1</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>351261B6-E34F-4239-E8B7-870394B5F205</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:45:47-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
