<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-4-2001-08-19-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>9E27D9F8-5DF8-44C1-F3D8-D3BFC2440970</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/BF8BE676-E41B-4EA7-738D-899E0E4DA70C">BF8BE676-E41B-4EA7-738D-899E0E4DA70C</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-19</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Concurrent">01E1019C-6AF5-4A97-D144-1F806449E537</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">DC0629AF-9667-4831-5484-665F77EBEC84</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/DC0629AF-9667-4831-5484-665F77EBEC84">
        <oc:name>Trench 4</oc:name>
        <oc:id>DC0629AF-9667-4831-5484-665F77EBEC84</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/01E1019C-6AF5-4A97-D144-1F806449E537">
        <oc:name>F-4-2001-08-19</oc:name>
        <oc:id>01E1019C-6AF5-4A97-D144-1F806449E537</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Concurrent</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-4-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench F-4 Final Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavated by Dawnell Somerville Moon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	I excavated trench F-4 this season which was a continuation of a trench dug last season. It is located on the lower mound on the riverside side of the hill, literally dug into the hill The trench was already around 2 1/2 meters deep on the hillside baulk. The oven L 4023/4027, the dominating feature of the trench, had already been exposed last year. It is interesting to note that there was a smaller oven eroding out of the hillside at a higher elevation that the oven. The baulks had to be cut back due to off season erosion making the trench 3.27 m wide by 3.47 m long. The trench was created from sounding which in addition to the baulk cutting contributes to its odd size. The baulks presented a small problem as the upper elevations were impossible to straighten due to their height and increasing crumbliness. We straightened what we could but there were no perfect straight corners or hard lines there. There was another hillside trench dug last year, F-5 whose presence helped give us a guide to stratigraphy and when to expect virgin soil.	&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	I excavated over a meter of soil in the trench. The trench was semi-closed mid-season as I had reached virgin soil in 3/4 of the trench. It was dug somewhat fitfully after that and was finally closed for the season when the sounding we placed in the trench hit virgin soil. Although there were days when the trench was not excavated most days someone was in there drawing or photographing or cleaning up all the dirt that flies in there so we could dig when we needed to. I believe this has a bearing on the final elevations I calculated for the trench. All the elevations on the final plan are a few centimeters lower than the day plan when I last took elevations. For many days in kept using the same elevations on areas I didn't excavate. I believe all the activities taking place in the trench account for these missing centimeters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The most outstanding feature of the trench would, of course, be the huge oven L 4023 and L 4027. This feature was still visible from last year although courses of mudbrick had eroded off the wall. The actual mudbrick wall of the oven was 4027 and the ash/soil depositions inside the oven were L 4023. The wall itself was made of mudbricks about 13-18 cm wide and 7 cm high. When a section was cut on the wall mortar lines about 1-2 cm thick were revealed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The matrix inside the wall was very impressive as well. It was a huge ash deposition filled with animal bones. The ash deposits did have bands of clay present occasionally, but the ash was very consistent through the whole locus. This consistency is the reason it was excavated as one locus instead of attempting to subdivide the various ash lenses. The lenses themselves curved up against the oven wall beautifully so it was easy to follow the line accurately. The general practice was to divide the oven in half and take down first one section and then the other half. I screened about 1/2 to 3/4 of the soil that came out of the oven. I also saved floatation samples and large pieces of charcoal suitable for carbon dating. Despite the work of screening all the soil most of the spectacular small finds did not come out of the oven.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The hope I had of finding a surface associated with the oven did not come to fruition. The trench consisted of the oven, a few pits, and fill. This is possible because the oven would be such a huge heat source people may not want to work or live in such proximity to it.  Despite the lack of surfaces the trench did produce a large number of small finds which will be discussed in conjunction with the loci in which they were found.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	One peculiar small find in the oven was large 10-12 cm worked stone, KT 4153, that for lack of a better name we called a digging spade. This was not so remarkable until a second, KT 4220 and a third, KT 4254, turned up. This same type of item was also found in F-9, F-1 and F-7. Their function is unknown, but their high density in the area may suggest some significance. Other finds included grindstone fragments and loom weights ( KT 4159, 4161, 4162). There was also a bone awl and some pottery fragments with red pigmentation/ochre on them (KT 4133, 4135) suitable for chemical analysis. There was also a flat based mudbrick item KT 4225 that conclusions vary concerning. Debate ranges from a pot stand/ andiron to anthropomorphic figure as it was found near sheep horns which could have been inserted into the hole in the upper portion of the item that was deliberately placed there. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The general assumption for these items and the deposition in the oven was that the oven ceased to be used and its function became that of a trash pit. Analysis of the animal bone fragments concluded that the patterns by which they were cut reflected not meal preparation, but dismantling for trash. Many of the bones were also burned, supporting the idea that they were burned as trash then the ash and bones dumped into the oven. The locus L 4023 and L 4027 ended at virgin soil L 4042.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The wall of the oven was not seriously studied until the end of the season. Due to its fragile nature and the fact that the soil inside kept getting lower and making it harder to get in, we left dirt from the surrounding loci up against the wall to brace and stabilize it. After extensive photographs we knocked out a 60 cm section of the wall down to the virgin soil it was sitting on and got more information about brick size them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	When excavating the soil inside the oven we had to do cleanup from soil fallen in over the off season. I marked several KT bags as contaminated as opposed to changing the locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The whole trench had to be cleaned due to erosion dirt filling in from the off season. The baulks were cut back before I arrived, but I still had to remove the erosion in the trench. L 9022 was the cleaning locus whose KT bags have mixed context. After picking through 20-30cm of fill I closed this and opened three new loci. We generally used the hand-picks when we picked in the trench. There were 4 people in a 3 x 3 trench so there was no room to swing a big pick.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We closed this cleaning locus because the northeast began producing a dark gray soil which was present last season, but not finished. This was L 2024. This locus was later redefined as a pit and began what was a series of pits in the north west corner of the trench This pit was ashy as were most of them in the area. The lines of this pit began expanding and it became L 4033 which was less ashy than L 4024. This pit stopped when we reached virgin soil L 4036, although I dug in it another 20 cm to confirm it was actually virgin soil. From L 4036 in the north west virgin soil began to slowly creep across the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	There was another pit system in the trench in the south east. This series of pits began around 30cm below the other system and both of these systems were dug fairly close to the oven wall. It is unclear if they had any connection to the oven, but although they were ashy they never produced the large amounts of bone fragments that the oven itself did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This southern pit series began with L 4034. This had ashy soil in it. This pit was found right away as it was sealed by an area of mudbrick slump/hard clay L 4028. Once this was removed it was a very clear soil change so there was not worry of pit contamination at its beginning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This pit produced some great pieces for carbon dating , but it also exhibited some interesting yellow streaks in the soil. These were saved for chemical analysis and some floatation samples taken as well. This pit was not excavated correctly however. The pit line narrowed rapidly after its initial opening and I did not catch this fact until I looked at the section more closely. Therefore about 30cm of the north ends of L 4035 and L 4040 were dug through as a pit. This may be a larger problem as these loci in section look like they were part of an earlier pit which was then cut by pit L 4034.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	There was one other pit in the trench located in the south west corner. This pit popped up as a surprise in my quest for virgin soil. It was named L 40344. Due to finding this pit we kept digging in the trench that would otherwise have been closed. This pit was not fully excavated and was closed due to the end of the season. The majority of the pit L 4044 was excavated because at the end of the dig we decided to put a 1m x 1m sounding in the south west corner which took up most of this pits boundaries. This sounding was L 4048. We dug roughly 15cm and then we changed bags. The sounding purpose was accomplished after a mere 30cm and we had hit virgin soil. At that point most of the trench was at virgin soil and it was ready to be closed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The constitutes the major loci of the trench. All the others are fill layers. However, many wonderful small finds came out of these fill layers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After the topsoil/erosion layers were cleaned off, the trench was divided into four quadrants. The oven, the north west of L 4024 which was defined due to its grayer soil and L 4025 and L 4026. The area of L 4024 was actually smaller than originally defined. Its dimensions shrunk when I found L 4029 a clay layer emerging south of the pit and L 4030 a small band of softer soil south of the pit and abutting L 4027, the oven wall. These loci were in turn reduced in size a the big pit L 4033 cut deeper into the area than L 4024 had. After removing all soil and closing these loci the area became L 4037 which was the virgin soil continuing further south into the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The south half of the trench had some interesting soil changes and was the area where most of the spectacular small finds were found. After removing the erosion layers the south half of the trench was divided into two loci for easier control. The west was L 4025 and the east was L 4026. The soil of both these areas was a crumbly clay that was also like L 4029. The best find from the trench was found in L 4026 about 15 cm deep in the locus. A cylinder seal KT 4132 was found. It had geometric designs on it and was broken on one end. The break looked fresh, but no pieces of it were found in all the dirt we screened. A pestle was found only a few centimeters away, but there was no concrete correlation between the two. These items were found right when a new locus was being opened up. We found them in L 4026, but right after this dirt w cleaned up there was an area of hard mudbrick slump below which became L 4028. This area was taken out and sealed a pit. Then L 4026 was closed and the area renamed L 4035 in case a surface was associated with the top of the pit. This was not dug, but later renamed L 4040 when a possible wall appeared.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	L 4026 also produced its share of small finds. Found on the opposite side of the trench 3 cm below where the seal was found was a bronze pin, KT 4160. 15 cm below that a small green bead (KT 4180) and two loom weights (KT 4181 and 4182) one with incised lines (KT 4181) were found. These were all found right together.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	A reddish area appeared in the center of the trench dividing it into L 4031 and L 4032. These loci were not dug, but were redefined when I created L 4041 which I originally thought was a wall. The area had good lines, first this red one and then a thin white line both of which I was able to follow into the baulk. But although they were present they did not amount to anything and the area was merely fill. L 4041 reached virgin soil and was subsumed into L 4037.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The far south end of the trench was split into thirds L 4038, 4039 and 4040. These were all fill. L 4039 did produce a beautiful potsmash we were able to reconstruct (KT 4246/whole KT 4300). No surface was found to correlate to this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After the ash pit was found in the corner below L 4038 and part of L 4039 I combined the left over areas which were exhibiting the same soil into one locus L 4045. This area was closed due to the end of the season, but it was becoming a more pink color and beginning to have some of the small pebbles so it may have begun pulling up virgin soil soon. The area in the east under pit L 4034 became L 4043. It seemed this soil may have been part of the larger pit cut by the small ashy system of L 4034. This area was also closed due to the end of the season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The other two loci were not excavated per se. L 4046 was a cleaning locus for the north baulk so we could enter some slag into the database. L 4047 was a step we cut into the hill east of my trench to try and catch more courses of the 13 course mudbrick wall that is present. (Excavated last year.) There was some pottery and slag so this area got its own "east baulk" locus so it too could be entered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Because the east baulk was so impressive with this wall present it was drawn as well as the north baulk with the oven deposition. Most of the loci show up in these two baulks. In fact only L 4029, 4030, 4025, 4031, 4032, 4041, 4038, 4039 and 4044 don't show up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Overall the trench was bands of clayey soil that had been cut and recut by pits. This may be because the oven was a trash area, and so other ash was dumped in pits in the area. If the area is industrials evidence of this does not reside in this trench. This trench was basically one large entity with nothing else, no floors, architecture to connect it to. This trench has been left at a standstill. There is not much point to continuing to excavate when there is a section about 2m by 1m that isn't at virgin soil. The sounding indicates it will all be there in about 30 cm. The best answer would be to look to the excavations in F-1 which are reaching the elevations of F-4 and has produced a large circular oven and huge dark ash layer in these last few days of excavations. Perhaps the key to production or living space will be found in a nearby trench as it was not discovered here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-4-2001-08-19-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-4-2001-08-19-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.8312865</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.815421</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 4</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:22:43-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:22:43</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,600 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3600</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 4</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>4C600815-178C-4A66-EF3E-4284EA0FF62C</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:48:19-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
