<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="5901F774-8389-4E8A-1552-738BC9E128D9" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>A-1-2000-07-021-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>B424991A-9D35-4741-0F4D-F8ED6DD83A00</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/3ECB2B5B-BE2D-43F8-83BE-828A7CE5EF89">3ECB2B5B-BE2D-43F8-83BE-828A7CE5EF89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-07-21</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">CBB4EC07-DF79-499C-6E8D-701B224049D8</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/CBB4EC07-DF79-499C-6E8D-701B224049D8">
        <oc:name>Trench 1</oc:name>
        <oc:id>CBB4EC07-DF79-499C-6E8D-701B224049D8</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59">
              <oc:name>Area A</oc:name>
              <oc:id>F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:A-1-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 21, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Set up 5 x 5 meter unit with 50 cm bulk.  Removed top soil using pick and shovel.  Leveled the surface.  Started at East half of the unit and dug until 15 cm from surface on south side, 25 cm from surface on north.  At this point a new surface (new locus) was exposed.  Found loose soil on east wall, but at this point we don't know what . . . possibly a pit?  made new KT number for pottery and lithics in west half of unit, but kept same KT number for bone throughout the enitre locus.  Found some possible mud bricks, but they might just be compacted mud because they were randomly dispersed, not in order (disturbed).  The actual topsoil was about 5 cm, but there was no reason to change the locus and kept excavating until it was uniform depth with east half.  Found several flat sherds concentrated on northwest corner of the unit.  Possibly reached a surface.  We assigned a new KT number for this area's pottery.  (KT 1007).  Tomorrow: clean the surface and go on to next locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 22, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finished the NW corner of Locus 1000; cleaned the surface and took a photo.  Measured the elevation of the original surface and the final surface of Locus 1000.  Measured small finds and took elevations for them.  Drew a plan view.  East side of the unit was mainly loose sand; west side was compacted sand and silt.  We therefore decided to divide the trench into two Locii. East side was assigned Locus # 1001 (loose soil).  West side assigned Locus #1002 (compacted layer).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1001 was thought to contain several pits, but decided to excavate through and see if definite shapes would emerge.  Found an obsidian fragment at the center of the trench (KT 1015).  Picked up the bone in the northeast corner and assigned it KT# 1016.  We leveled the locus at 40 cm below the original surface.  After exposing the surface, it was obvious that the loose soil had been created by animal activity.  This completed Locus 1001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After determining that there were no pits in Locus 1001, we decided to excavate Locus 1002 (Western portion) and level it with the completed 1001.  Picked up the concentration of small pottery as a small find (KT 1019).  Used pick and shovel to take down the rest of Locus 1002.  The northwest corner revealed a row of straight mud bricks.  Looks to be a wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 23, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;     Since David was sick, I had to do all my work by myself, so if things start to make no sense, this is the day that all begin.  Anyway, I started out by cleaning the surface of both Locus 1001 &amp;amp; 1002.  Exposed the possible mud-brick wall, but it was cut off near the west wall (Possible two mud-brick in line).  There were several large rocks in locus 1002, and seemed to be in line, from N-S, near the North wall.  (However, there were no large rocks in locus 1001).  Elevation of these rocks and mud bricks were between margin of 2-3 cm difference.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;   After finishing lcus 1001 and 1002, I decided to divide the trench into 4 corner. East side (2m x 4m) as locus 1003, SW (2m x 2m) as 1006, and NW (2m x 2m) as 1004.  We did not excavate 1004 and 1006 today.  Locus 1003 was excavated by using pick and shovels and approx 15 cm of soil was removed.  There wa a flat lying rocks below 1003, this might be a wall, or possible cover for coffin.  After cleaning the surface, possible pit, lined by (possible) Mud-brick was found. This pit was directly below the possible pit in locus 1001 (check KT 1016)  Assigned locus 1005 for this possible burial. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;     I tried to follow the wall of the pit to excavate the pit, on East side of the pit, the soil was more loose and easy to define, but the soil of west side was not clearly distinguishable from the wall of the pit.  Within this pit, We found several pieces of bones, animal and possible human, and pottery was scattered throughout the pit.  This indicate that if this was a burial, it has been disturbed; or, I have not dig down deep enough.  We screened approx 80 % of the soil to see what's in the burial.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July, 24  2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	It's second day without David, I think I can handle this....  Begin excavating Locus 1005.  Took out the intact bone (KT 1031), and made 2 L of soil sample, I tried not to include the soil on top,  then excavating further down with brush.  I found this method time consuming but turned out to be a excellent choice.  Loose soil could be removed by brush, but the compacted soil will remain there.  Continued worked for this pit, and found a straight line of compacted soil (Kind of split the pit into two, running along the middle).  First I thought the pit was narrowing down, but the line was straight, it turned out to be a pit inthe pit!   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While I was cutting down the west wall of the pit (Locus 1004 wall), I found a hard soil in a shape of a pipe.  It looked like a pipe, but it may be some animal hole.  When I tried to measure the diameter, the accident happened; the possible pipe was destroyed.  If I could find the similar "thing" somewhere else, I will try to be more careful.  For the second pit, I assigned a new KT # for the finds.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While I was workig on the pit, I made the workers take down Locus 1006 &amp;amp; 1004.  For Locus 1004, We first left the line mud-brick intact.  In Locus 1006, we found some human bone concentrated on one area (KT 1034), and nearly complete bowl (KT 1036).  Also, found 2 large rocks.  In locus 1004, we found concentration of pottery and one bone close to the mud-brick.  The soil showed some variation on surface.   The wiggling shape locus (1001 &amp;amp; 1002) that we made seems to follow the general looseness of the soil in this trench; this indicate that the soil is disturbed, or we might find several pits here.    The mud-brick, seems to me that it is some kind of oven, but the surface is not burnt, so I do not know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	About locus 1005....  We found burial, within the smaller pit in the pit.  It tuurned out to be the outline of the pit above was too small, and we have to knock down the wall of the pit.  It seems to be a multiple burial.  One person was nearly intact, and could follow the outline clearly.  however, there was one femur, lined in opposite direction, and found several pieces of bones above.  It could be a mass grave site!!!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 25, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Sorry, I will be sloppy writing this journal today.  David is in hospital.   To see the wall of the burial, and make it easy to excavate the burial, we decided to excavate small section south of the pit for about 30 cm.  We made 1.5 m x 1.5 m section from NE corner, and assigned Locus1007.  Rest of the NE corner will be called Locus1010 (mainly the balk, L-shape unit).  While workers excavating this unit, they found several rocks (approx round 10 cm x 10 cm), since the main purpose was to look at the profile of the pit and to knock it down, I ignored these rocks; also I was busy.  Anyway, these rocks turned out to be some feature.  I found more rocks lined across the balk, and it was part of the "stone ciecle," or a wall.  I took down the wall of the pit, and it seems to be composed of mud brick.  The surface of locus 1007 seems to be a surface, or a floor, and can see some mud bricks.  However, this is much lower than the rest of the locus (and lower than the stone structures), so must be left unexcavated for a while.  I have not checked the elevation of the floor, but it might be close to the elevation of the pit in the pit.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While I knocked down the wall of the pit, workers excavated the locus 1008, which is the South half of the trench (below 1003 and 1006).  They found two semi circular structure of rock lines, amazingly, this line of stones somewhat follow the loose soil area that I found above in locus 1003 and 1006.  They also found more large rocks around the SW section.  Also, there seems to be a definate pit near the large rocks in SW section.  tomorrow will be a busy day....&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today, I destroyed the mud brick that was laying out for two days.  Nothing was in this thing, and we still don't know what this is.  However, I found a possible N5 sherd (or Islamic?) imbeded on to this brick; it was slightly green-gray, and seemed to be burnt in high temp.  After removing this "thing," it still continued on the surface, this could go more deeper, and it could be a part of something larger.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 26, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today, I begin working with taking off the balk of 1010.  I found some hard compacted mud-brick.  It seems to be following the rocks.  The workers excavated the locus 1009 (NW section).  They found some bones scattered around, and found a skull directly below the mud-brick that we found in 1004.  The skull was small and thin, possibly a baby or an animal.  also beside this skull we found possible human finger, not related to the skull (finger was for fully mature adult).  Also, foud a mandible of some animal that seems to be baked (was black color).  Also, we cleared the locus 1008 (South half of the unit).  The pit that we found previously was more clearly defined , and compacted sand was a mud-brick.  It probably represent surface.  We had to make several new locus.  See plan map for detail.  The rocks, within the rocks, pit, floor area, and also an oven near West wall.  The soil contained dark ash, some red bricks and burned bricks.  We decide to make this oven locus larger, to include the ash layer.  The soil was loose at the SW corner, and found some animal bone, this will be another locus.    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;     The NW section gave me a hard time to clearly define the limit of the floor or a pit.  There was a clear line of possible mud-brick surrounding the skull.  The finger bone south of the skull was in loose layer of sand.  At the center of the unit was some orangish soil, also, there seems to be some pit around this discoloration.  The burial pit extends to this locus, but had the mud brik line above this.  We will scrape this area more carefully and see what's going on to make more new loci!  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 28,   2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This morning started out with brushing the surface and cleaning to make a photo (for a plan view).  After taking several photo, I put Ihsan and Azeez to work on locus 1011 (SE corner of the trench, within stone circle;stone circle is 1012).  Also, baris worked on the pit at the SW cornar of the trench (locus 1017).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus 1011  I told the workers to excavate about 5 cm, very carefully.  Azeez found some bones after few minutes, and found some teeth that looks small, but looked like human, possible child burial.  We decided to screen at this point for all soil.  At the east balk, the soil seemed little compacted, in one area, but it was not a mud brick.  Whithin that hard soil, we found the human child teeth (TK 1064).  We later assigned new locus for this area on the east balk 9Locus 1025, we will excavate tomorrow, hopefully)  Also, near the south balk about 80 cm west from the east balk, we found human skull.  Workers smashed a piece out of it...  The skull seems male because it had a somewhat rigid brow ridge.  We also found some intact bones around it, to these bones around the burial, different TK 1070 was given.  I did not check the difference of the soil in this pit from another areas, I should do this next day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus  1017	This is the locus near the SW corner of the trench.  We found some bones near (under) the large rocks (locus 1016).  The soil was very loose and little darker in color.  First I thought it was a animal bones, but it turned out to be a human.  Very little pottery was found from this pit, but Baris found a worked stone flake.  The bones were scattered, and some were broken, and it was disturbed and did not seemed to had a proper burial or it may have been dug up and reburied.  So far only several long bones were found.  This pit seems to extend further down and east, under the large rocks.  We should remove the rocks on top and see the relationship between the rocks and this pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Locus  1015	This locus was the most obvious burial pit.  The pit followed the general coffin shape, round near head and straight at the feet, about 2.15 m in length and 50 cm wide.  There was a clear line of loose soil, but one mud brick (about 40 cm x 40 cm) was covereing this pit in about mid-way.  Under the loose and darker soil, somewhat ashy?, there was a hard, but very fragile layer of soil (Approx 99.67) Beginning elevation for th pit is 99.75, and we found a burial, fully extended, directly below this later (99.63-99.56).  This hard soil resemble the soil of locus 1014, which could represent a soil below the mud-brick surface.  This seems to me that the pit was dug during the occupation of locus 1014 period, and mud-bricks were layed after.  Than, the problem is to determine when was the stones were layed.  We have to dig to see....   The head was directed towards SW, and it was layed on side, looking south.  Bone were preserved well, but it seems like hand was missing?  Bone seems to be fragile than that of locus 1005.  There were several sherds associated in situ with the burial.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 29, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1025	We made this new locus in order to see if there are any difference in soil, bones, and artifacts from surrounding area, since we found a human child teeth from this location.  This locus is about 25 cm x 25 cm, connecting to East balk at 25 cm from South.  The soil seemed compacted around this area, and had some orange mottle within.  I was not paying much attention to the soil for past several days, so may be I should check more carefully.  Anyway, there were no small pebbles in the soil of Locus 1025, compared to west side of Locus 1011.  However, we found only few pottery and no human bones, but a animal teeth.  I would straighten the balk and below rocks(locus 1012) to see if there are any characteristics in this locus and locus 1011.  Since we found no interesting sign, We closed the locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1011	We excavated the rest of the locus to create a flat surface (there were some unexcavated area close to West side).  Nothing seems to draw my attention except there was possible mud-brick below the rocks.  This mud-brick is very loosly compacted and may not be a nud-brick, it has a dark color and very pores.  I would consult with Andy sometime later.  To determine the history of this pit and burial and the stones, I tried to see the soil differences.  There were many variation in soil in this locus.  As I noted above, I will examine this tommorow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1015	We continue articulate the burial.  The bones were still fragile, but since I am getting better at digging around the bone, it seemed less fragile.  I might be a bone digging expert at the end of this excavation!  When I was cleaning the surface of the right leg bone, I found a possible chewed mark ( by rodent?) on it.  Andy suggest that this person was left outside after his death for a while, and someone reburied later.  If we can determine rather this is a real animal tooth mark, or any indication of wounds or cause of death, we can draw interesting scenario.  This person could be killed in combat and left alone, or died alone and the family found it later.  The one thing that I noticed is that all burial so far (except for 1015) is dug fairly shallow.  It's hard to tell how deep that they dug, but it is certain that it was less than 75 cm or so.  Because we found these pits or stone circle and finds burial right below it.  The skull is under the large rocks (Locus 1016).  This indicate that the rocks were layed after the burial pit was dug.  It is now odd, that there was one mud brick was sticking out in the burial pit.  It seems that burial pit is cutting through the mud-brick surface, except for one point.  Dr. Bradly mentioned, while noticing the mud-brick floor, that the mud brick surface might be a some kind kind of large structure of Hellenistic era; but we must see if the pottery reading indicate this.  Another thing I noticed is that these burials seems to have a grind stone made out of volcanic rocks.  in Locus 1011, we found two fragment (KT 1087), near the skull of Locus 1016 (KT 1060, although this seems to be far from the skull), and this burial.  We found no other dark soil in the burial pit today, I think I collected most of the dark soil yesterday; this dark soil might come from the oven?  Andy and I will examine the bones tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1026	Since the loose soil was larger longer than the hight of the buried person in Locus 1015, we excavated the rest of the pit.  As soon as we start digging, Ihsan found some bones.  But, it was a bones from different individual.  The bones were broken and smashed, and disturbed, some from tree roots.  But further excavation revealed that the skull was smashed.  and body might extend to east.  This suggest that burial of 1026 was earlier than that of 1015.  The best scenario that I could think is that people of "Locus 1015-age"  tried to dug a pit, but found a dead body under the ground and smashed the skull.  But for some reason they did not wanted to dug a new pit and just buried the corpse there. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Also, today, we took a photo to create a detailed plan view.	 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 30, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1010	There was one area that was not excavated in Locus 1010 (the floating rocks). we took down the rocks and large frag of pot sherds from it and leveled the surface, no interesting artifacts or features were found.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1011	Clean the surface and profile.  Found a mud-brick lining at the surface, below the rock circle, runnib parrallel to it.  The question is to determine the relationship between the mud-brick and the rocks (locus 1012).  Also, found a line of soil changes between the fill and the burial.  Looking towards east, you will see, from your left (North), line of stones with mud brick under them, loose soil fill, and darker pit soil.  It seems that the pit was small for the burial since between the wall of the pit and skelton i only about 1 cm.  It is as if someone wanted to bury a person quickly and did not care about the size of the pit; just dug a hole and put a dead person in the pit!  However, this does not explain the stone circle and the mud-brick lining, if there is connection with this burial.  In the profile of the east wall, I found several area of pits and loose fill; see profile view for detail.  There were small pit dug for the burial for a baby(?) about 40 - 60 cm below the present surface.  The surface of this locus is approx 75 cm from the present surface.  Also, there was one area thet clearly had a loose soil.  It is only about 15 cm width, and can not tell any detail only from the profile.  South wall was heavily disturbed from tree root action.  I might have to take a look at this profile later.  No one had the Monsul color chart that day, so I will plan on finishing my profile sometime later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1018	OVEN I  Oven is located just west of the burial pit 1015.  Found some ashy layer and fired clay(bricks).  I put Ihsan and Azeez for this task.  They seemed to excavate well, and we found a oven intact, and had a circular structure, about 45 cm in diameter.  We might have to excavate more to see if the oven extends further or not.  It seems the pit 1015 cuts through the oven.  The dark soil within the burial could possible be a inclusion of the oven.  The structure is visible and amazed with the preservation of the feature.  Some animal bones and possible human were found.  The soil on the surface showed many discoloration, some white, orange, and dark (burnt).  The relationship with the pit 1017 and this oven must be make clear later on.  Some bones were found at the southern edge of this oven close to the bones on pit 1017.  We must define the limit of this oven and the limit of the pit.  If we know the relationship with the large rocks (Locus 1016) and the pit 1017, we could make interesting scenario about these features.  I would look at the characteristics of the oven later on, such as the size of the bricks, among other things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1024  OVEN II	   This oven is located on the central part of the NW 1/4 of the trench.  Some orange discoloration was present on the surface, but seems to have a pit at the center, and even some mud-bricks.  It was hard to define the limit  of this oven from the surface, and it turned out to be hard to define the limit of this oven.  We found some frag of oven, circular, but only about 1/3 of the circle.  the north side of this oven was a loose fill, and workers and i could not find the hard surface as we did in the OVEN I.  However, on the south side, we found a thin ash layer, and found a hard surface below, but it was similar to that surrounds this oven, and I was having a hard time figuring out what was going on in this area.  Also, North side of the loose fill caused me some problem.  The orange discoloration was found here too, and the loose soil was sourounding it.  However, the soil seemed to show more than 4 variations within small portion of the area.  Looking towards North, you will find mud-brick like compacted soil, orange colored soil from oven, loose fill, and crumbled white soil (seems like decayed mud-bricks?).  I think I need some help determining this mess.  All I can think of is that someone dug a pit directly above the oven.  I will try and cut through some section and see the soil in profile.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 31, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1015	Andy and I examined the bones with close up today. As I noted above, Head is place in SW direcion, and face is looking south (showing left side of the face).  Left hand is crossed and put on the pubic area.  Right hand is twisted.  Both legs are extended and feet are looking towards south.  Eli worked on articulation of the skelton, and she was perfect fit for the job!  I dug for years, but she's better than me...  I feel like shit, it's her 1st time...  I guess some people are better doing things like this.  Here is some result of examination; we worked on long bones today and we will be working on other bones tomorrow.  From today's result, it seems like this individual is male? (i think), about 30 years of age, and possibly died and exposed for a while and reburried.  Also, the burial under his feet poses many intersting question; why didn't they change the location of the burial?  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Examination result from burial at Locus 1015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; (July 31 &amp;amp; Aug 1, 2000)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Tibia mid-shaft on anterior found a rodent chewed(gnaw) mark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Tibia 36 cm long, proximal end smashed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Patella smashed, missing? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	left Tibia distal-shaft smashed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	left Tibia 35 cm long, proximal end smashed, found weathering or decay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	left Patella intact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	left Femur, found pre-mortum break? distal-shaft found 2 sharp indentation (chop mark).  40 cm long distal end smashed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Femur heavily weathered, found gnaw mark, 40 cm, distal end smashed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Humurus 30 cm, strong mascular attachment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Radius 23 + cm, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	right Ulna, can not be measured.  Possible artherites?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	left Ulna found weathering on proximal shaft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Iron deficiency?  porous skeleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Cranial structure (left side, suture closure)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 1   midlamdoid               &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 2   lambda                   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0 or 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 3   obellion                 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 4   anterior saggital   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 5   baegma                   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0 or 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 6   mid coronal              &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 7   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;tarrion                            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 ?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 8   spheno frontal           not visible&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 9   inferior spheno temporo  not visible&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 10  superior spheno temporo  broken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Cranial structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	 1  Nuchal Crest                     1 or 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	 2  Glabella                            2 or 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	 3  Supra-orbital Margin        1 or 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	 4  Mental Emminence            1 or 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	 5  Gonial Angle                     3 or 4 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pelvis &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	 greater sciatic notch        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4 or 3 ?  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;    Upper left molar find behind Zygomatic bone, crown facing upside down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;    found (right) knee, (right hand ) fingers, rib bones, and vertebrate within the skull, these were all missing from the skelton.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 1, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1015	Today, I articulated the skelton; the torso area, pelvis, and foot.  Exposed spinal cords.  After finishing, begin to box the baby.  By tomorrow, all the bones should be taken up.  One strange thing that I noticed today was that his right hand was almost completely missing, except for one finger.  The right hand was where Ulna and Radius was crossed (twisted).  This, I think, occured before his death.  At least, I hope this to be the case.  When I was digging around his right finger, the soil was compacted and hard.  There is no possibility that his finger was destroyed from excavating.  We should analyze the bones carefully to see if there is any indication of pre-mortal injury.  What I am thinking is that some animal chewd away his finger; this explain the missing finger and the twisted arm.  Although the finger bones coud be easily misplaced after burial, I like my idea better.  Some pieces of vertebra collum was missing, but those bones probably decayed, since those bones are fragile.  By he way, we named this skelton Cocaine Joe.  For references, the elevation of the skull is 99.70, pelvis at 99.60, and foot at 99.57.  I have not checked the elevation of the skelton in 1026, but it seems much higher than the skelton in 1015s  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Locus 1026	While I articulate the bones from 1015, Ihsan took down the burial pit of 1026, which is directly East of 1015.  This skelton was layed sideways facing south (so the left shoulder of this person is close to the surface), fully extended (legs are in the balk).  This burial is oriented East and west, head is at the West, and slightly tilted towards North.  I should check the angle of all the burial with a compass.  So far, all burials that I uncovered, 1005, 1011, 1015, and 1026, head is placed on West side.  However, angle is all different.  This poor person, as I noted above, lost his/her head when the pit was dug for 1015.  It is now obvious...  We should articulate this baby and put them into the boxes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Some consideration about the burials.  Since this trench is ancient necropolis, I will write what I think about these burials.  1- it is all close to surface, so it is possibly Hellenistic in age or earlier, but I have to wait for the pottery reading.  2- burials 1005, 1011, 1015, 1026 are all extended  and somewhat oriented towards West.  I am not sure these indicate any relationship.  Ancient people had an idea that West is a place for death because the sun sets on west.  3- so far, I found possible 3 burial goods on 1011, 1015, and 1009 surface (about 1 m away from the baby skull).  All of them were volcanic rock grind stone, that is shaped flat (I will check the measurmet tomorrow).  4 - Elevation of the burial 1011 and 1015 is about the same 99.69 and 99.79.  However, 1026 is higher and 1005 is lower.  Well, I'm getting tired and sleepy, I would write more later, i can't think now... &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Aug 2, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1026	Today, I articulatedthe skelton and exposed femur and rib bones.  The soil of this pit seems more compacted and more silty than burial 1015.  Locus 1026 - 2.5 Y 6/2 silt, some pebbles, but smaller than 5 mm.  locus 1015 - 2.5 Y 5/2 very fine sand to silt, some pebbles, some pebbles more than 5 mm, and find more number of small pebbles in 1015.  Near this person's right femur, several fragment of bones were sticking from a wall.  According to Andy, it is a fragment from mandible.  The bones of this individual are more stable and thicker than that of 1015.  We will hopefully examine this individual tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1015	We try to lift the skull of this individual today....  Well, we examined the skull, and it now appears to be more femal than male.  When we were lifting the skull, I found two fragments of finger bone stuck in the skull.  Also, later find out that the skull was full of bones, such as knee, vertebrate, and ribs.  The skull was full of these bones.  What it appears to be is that these bones were missing from the skelton.  Probably, this person was killed, or died alone, and chewed by some animals.  Later, some one picked up the pieces of this person and stuffed them into his/her skull.  The occipital bone?-- (I don't know the name, but the bone of the skull that is flat and lay directly below the sinal cords, where the foram magnam (The hole for the spin) is-- was missing.  This seems that people stuffed the skull with bone either removing, and chopping the skull, or it is possible that the skull was already smashed and people stuffed the bones from there.  It is also possible that they stuffed the bones from mouth, since some teeth were misplaced and within the skull.  I don't know what is going on, but many intersting scenario could be drawn from these finds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Aug 3, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1015	Today was a lab-day, but Andy and I decided to go to the field and pick up more bones!  We decided to take a skull with the soil and fingers intact.  It seems that more bones were stuck into the back of the forehead area, some fingers and teeth were piled up in that area.  This, for me, is to suggest that the bones were stuffed from the bottom (more to back-side) of the shull.  Also, somehow the mandible were stuffed way up in the skull.  We took C14 sample for dating; several ribs, both left and right were taken.  I try to dig up some new pieces rather than using the exposed parts of the bones.  Also, I used the dental pick and spoon (both metal), to pick the sample.  Put them in the Aluminum foil, which I did not tuch the inside.  I payed extreme caution for these samples, for there should be no contamination from this excavation.  There could be a contamination from other causes, such as tree root activity, or A-Bomb test.  As for yesterday, we took soil sample from each area of the body as we articulate the bones.  We separated the samples from within the skull, around neck and the body, vertebrate area, ribs, and right femur area.  Because the bones were soo fragile, we simple put the broken oiecrs of bones in the soil sample bag (ribs and vertebrates are in the soil bag and did not seoarately bag them).  The head of the right femur were about 5 cm, and that seems to be little large to be a female.  Gonial angle was 3 or 4 (examination from the mandible angle).  Tomorrow, we must pick the rest of the legs and the pelvis.  Hope we could know the sex of this person, either it will be Cocaine joe or Jenny. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;KT 2000   Area A Trench 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;font-size:14pt;font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Brief summary from the pottery reading (Locus 1000 to 1010)  (July 23, 2000)  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;font-size:14pt;font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;*Must read update from Aug 19, 2000 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; Level 1	(100.50 - 100.30)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1000   heavily disturbed zone, some Hel, EIA, and N5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	# This is the layer of top-soil and directly below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  Level 2     (100.30 - 100.15)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1001   IA and Hel mixed and showed no consistency, still in the zone of disturbance	 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1002   Mainly Hel in nature, and a possible N5 sherd.  But some evidence of disturbance &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	# This level was probably occupied during Hel and later.  East side shows the heavy mixing of materials. for some unknown reasons; the slope of the tepe may had some affect in the past.  West side of the trench shows more stable soil and less disturbance.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  Level 3     (100.15 - 100.00)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1003   Hel and IA mixed, still shows some disturbance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1004   possible N5 and EIA, shows little disturbance, clearly IA occupation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1006   possible Iron age occupation, but not enough diag to specify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	# This level was occupied in IA to Hel.  Shows some disturbance in South and East of the trench.  Since there were some soil variations and this seems to correspond with the pits and burials at the lower levels.  NW corner of the trench represent clear IA occupation.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  Level 4     (100.00 - 99.80)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1008   It shows some late pottery, and not enough evidence to suggest a clear age of occupation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1009    Several sherds from Assyrian, EIA, shows clear occupation of Iron Age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1010   Locus was too small to reveal any significant evidence of diag pottery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus  1007  Clearly shows Hel occupation, possible it was a pit; it's a Hellenistic slump.  Found a large possible pit above the locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	# This level seems to be occupied durring IA.  However, for one section in NE, under a pit shows clear Hel materials.  This pit was visible from Locus 1003.  Also, some disturbance in the south is from the burials; this might suggest the age of the burials (Locus 1011, 1015, 1026, and 1017), but we must wait for the pottery reading for those loci&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  Burial (Locus 1005)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	# From the pottery reading, this area represt clear IA burials, such as Pale-ware (Type I), Cor. Bowl, and possible N5 sherd.  Although this burial is located directly north of the hellenistic slump, the pit was protected from the mud-brick lining.  The questions to be asked is rather the deep pit within the pit represent differnt level than the one above.  At this point, there is not enough evidence to suggest.  Wait until the full pit is excavated and examined.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Aug 5, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Today, I removed some loose dirt out from the burial pit 1015, articulated some more, took up the pottery near feet.  That about what I  did in this trench this day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	I will be opening up a new trench in area D, east side of the tepe, down the hill in somewhat flat area.  Anyway, the decision was made because, there are just too many burials and I am not a burial specialist; I  wish I had more knowledge of osteology.  So, we will close this trench because we want to get more accurate information from the burials other than my own (and Andy).  We will be excavating this trench next season, if there are a bone specialist.  Before I completely close this trench, I have to make some point clear so that next year someone would not have trouble excavating the trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Right now, I exposed several new loci that never put my hands on it.  Also, Oven I (locus 1018) and Oven II (locus 1024) is incomplete at this moment.  Burial at locus 1011, 1026, and pit (possible burial) at locus 1017 is nearly completed.  I will list, and make a brief description of all the loci that appears on the surface at this moment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	All loci up to 1010 has been excavated and finished completely (and does not exist anymore... good bye my friendly loci...)  for those loci information check this journal (Pottery reading summary, Aug 3)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus 1011	The burial at the SE corner, a burial in the South balk.  Found a mud-brick line on surface under rocks(Locus 1012).  This Locus is completed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus 1012	The circular line of rocks sourrounding locus 1011.  Mud-bricks is under the rocks.  The purpose of the excavation of this locus will be clarifying the relationship with locus 1011(burial), locus 1013/1020 (surface), and the mud-brick underlining the rocks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus 1013	The mud-brick surface, same as locus 1020, but assigned this locus to south side of the burial pit (locus 1015).  The purpose is to clarify the relationship between locus 1012, 1019, and 1016 (lining of rocks), and possible day the surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus 1014	Suppose to be a loose fill area between locus 1012 and 1019, just East of the burial 1015.  However, this area was changed to burial (locus 1026).  Now the Locus 1014 does not exist, make a new locus somewhere!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus  1015	Needless to say, it's a famous burial near the center of the trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus  1016	Line of large rocks at the SW area of the trench.  This locus abuts surface 1013/1020, pit 1017, Oven I (locus 1018).  The purpose of the excavation is to see rather the pit 1017 extend below this locus; we found some human bones in locus 1017, and seems to continue down into the rocks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus  1017	Pit at the SW corner of the trench.  Found human bones, crushed into pieces, possibly extends to Locus 1016.  Relationship with Oven I (Locus 1018) and mud-brick surface.  Try to reconstruct which locus cuts which locus.  this locus is completed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus  1018	Oven I, just north of large rocks(locus 1016) and west of burial 1015.  Burial 1015 probably cuts the Oven I.  relationship between Oven II (locus 1024) must be clarify.  Oven I and Oven II could be considered as one unit, but at this it is hard to determine.  This locus is nearly complete but the oven (layer of soft ash) might extend further.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus  1019	The somewhat circular lining of rocks just north of burial 1015.  Similar structure to locus 1012.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus  1020	Mud-brick surface, same as locus 1013.  The north side of the burial 1015, but could be considered as one unit.  Mud-brick does not appear clear at the north side of the trench.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus  1021	The hard compacted silt layer at the NW corner of the trench (somewhat circular, 1.5 m diameter).  Found a skull of a baby? in this area.  Interesting to see the relationship with Oven II (locus 1024), and mud-brick surface.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus 1022	The extension of the pit from burial 1005.  Loose soil seems to follow a pit from east side.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--#Locus  1023	A loose soil that seems to surrounds the silt layer (locus 1021)  Found a human finger.  The extension of this locus is hard to define since it is cut (or cut by )many loci: 1021, 1022?, 1024, 1020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus 1024	Oven II.  This area was difficult to excavate since many loci meets together and all of them seems to submerge, without any definate limit.  This Oven seems to be cut by a pit in the middle.  You will see some Oven frag, and flat surface on the south and dug out surface to north.  The north of the oven had a loose soil and seems to continue further down.  But to the south, somewhat compacted layer continues, but edges with mudbrick surface was not east to tell.  I have not finished this locus but seems to be a better idea to leave at this moment.  This locus requires time and care to excavate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus  1025	This is locus is completed.  It was thought to be a burial pit of a baby, within the locus 1011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;--Locus 1026	Burial pit next to 1015.  This person's head was smashed by pit dug by 1015.  We may or may not excavate this person at this point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;---I hav not assigned Locus 1027 and beyond (Locus 1014 is not assigned)  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  # loci that not has been excavated &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;font-size:14pt;font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;UPDATE OF THE SUMMARY OF POTTERY READING  (AUG 19, 2000)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;     There are several points that I must make correction from the above summary since the last pottery reading.  Rather than go back and fix my original data, Idecided to mention here.  Now, we know more about pottery than before and I must make that clear.  All the possible N5 pot-sherds turned out to be a Hellenistic in age.  Also, what we call type I (pale-ware with red paint) is also of Hellenistic age.  This will suggest that almost all the loci are of Hellenistic in age.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The burial 1005, is not an Iron age burial &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;and it is Hellenistic.   Locus 1009, which seemed to be a clearly Iron age occupation is in doubt.  From KT 1051, I found Type I which is Hellenistic, but KT 1054 seems to be in Iron age (Assyrian nipple base, COR. bowl etc)  KT 1054 is the only KT that is in Iron age and others are Hellenistic. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1011	This Locus is the Burial at the SE corner of the trench.  surrounded by lining of rocks.  We found a skelton in the south balk.  The skelton was oriented towards west (direction of head), and the hand was crossed.  The age and sex has not been determined.  Below the stones, I found a mud-brick lining, possible following the rocks above. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  Type 7 and Type 65 (Jar with rolled-over rim)  both Hellenistic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1015	This Locus is the burial at the center of the trench.  The pit was dug through the surface 1013 and 1020.  Head was oriented towards Southwest.  We excavated this individual with extreme care.  During the excavation, we found ribs, knee bone, and finger bones in the skull.  Also, some gnaw marks were apparent in the right Tibia and Femur.  We think that this person was left out after the death for a while.   Then, he body was picked up by someone, all the fragments of the body was stuffed into the head and buried.  Interesting enough, when the pit was dug, a burial right below the feet (East) was cut through (Locus 1026).  It seems that Locus 1015 cuts Locus 1026, and the head of 1026 is smashed.   There were only few pottery from this burial pit and not a definate diagnostic sherds were found, but it seems to be from the Hellenistic.  I found an outline of this pit above the surface of 1020 (found loose soil at Locus 1008).  The Locus 1008 dates to Hellenistic.  So, this burial must dat to Hel or later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1017	This Locus is the pit that is located at the SW corner of the trench.  We found several smashed pieces of human bones, and the soil was loose so it was a good possibility to find a burial here.  We do not know the precise shape of the pit since it was too close to the balk and it seems to go under the rocks at Locus 1016.  This suggest that pit is earlier than the rocks of 1016.   The pottery from this Locus seems to be of hellenistic, but we only found few frag of Red-Brown wash ware.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1018	This Locus is the Oven at the SW section of the trench.  It has a circular shape.  Ashy soil was on top of a compacted mud.  The Oven seems to extends further north and could be connected to Locus 1024 (Oven II).   Several bones were found scattered arond the area.  The burial 1015 seems to cut through the oven.  I found dark ashy soil below the large rocks(Locus 1016).  The relationship between the pit(1017) and this Locus has not been determined.   Found Type 7 pot-sherds and seems to be from hellenistic age. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1024	This Locus is the Oven at the Northside of the trench.  This oven was not well preserved, and seemed to have a pit at the center.  The soil was loose and deep on the North side and ashy soil was shallow at the south side.  Both of the oven L1018 and L 1024 has not been fully excavated, we must define the limit of the oven.  We found red-brown wash and type 9, purly Hellenistic assembly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1025	This Locus was assigned since we found child teeth within the Locus 1011(burial).  The soil that looked different and loose were pedestled to be excavated.  We found little differnce, but probably a pit.    Found hellenistic incurbed rim bowl.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;	Locus 1026	This is the burial that is located just east of the burial 1015.  The skull of this person was bashed when a pit was dug to bury a person (L 1015).   Pottery reading has not been done for this Locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:'Geneva'" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: A-1-2000-07-021-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/5901F774-8389-4E8A-1552-738BC9E128D9</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+A-1-2000-07-021-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F5901F774-8389-4E8A-1552-738BC9E128D9</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830613</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813189</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5901F774-8389-4E8A-1552-738BC9E128D9">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 1</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>5901F774-8389-4E8A-1552-738BC9E128D9</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:38:23-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:38:23</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
