<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="660D9283-6AAC-4A3F-F944-73F18786CC39" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-19-2005-06-22-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>BBF0F744-B58C-4A2F-8179-8B12EB10B8C3</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/2118701C-0FD6-46D1-FE56-4105B41D7E18">2118701C-0FD6-46D1-FE56-4105B41D7E18</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-22</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Previous">1BF1B933-0850-4C06-3876-15C47EBC68EF</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">705A0E1B-D73A-4B29-4EDC-E45964F6F5EA</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/705A0E1B-D73A-4B29-4EDC-E45964F6F5EA">
        <oc:name>Trench 19</oc:name>
        <oc:id>705A0E1B-D73A-4B29-4EDC-E45964F6F5EA</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/1BF1B933-0850-4C06-3876-15C47EBC68EF">
        <oc:name>F-19-2005-06-19</oc:name>
        <oc:id>1BF1B933-0850-4C06-3876-15C47EBC68EF</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Previous</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-19-2005-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary Year 2005 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;June 22, 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;M. Baldi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After some discussion as to where to place the next trench on the tepe, it was decided to open a new trench in area F close to two previously excavated trenches. One of these, F 1 was excavated last time in 2002 and a number of interesting features and information were obtained, that trench was dug clear to virgin soil. Likewise trench F 4 was excavated in 2000 and at the time there were questions concerning the edge of the tepe and the possible use of this area by earlier inhabitants of this picturesque location on a bend of the Tigris River. Features of interest of those trenches such as the thick layer of ash, the provenience of collapsed walls, cobble stone layers (roads or floors?) posed a number of questions and contextual possibilities that it was decided to excavate F 19 contiguously East of F 1, and South of F 4. Additionally, a major research question for this area of the Kenan Tepe deals with documenting the extent of the lower town and the relationship to the main mound. Was this a habitational area, or an outlaying production center? Perhaps a center of both commercial and production uses. After examining the thick layers of ash, indicative of a large-scale conflagration one may additionally inquire as to the reasons for its location, and causes; was the area burned down intentionally? Perhaps these were houses that burned? Was this caused by accident, or did an attacking force intentionally burn it down. Being this close to the river, this area would have been one of the first areas to suffer invasion and destruction. By excavating F 19 we seek to answer these and many other questions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because of its precarious location, F 19 was originally marked as a 4 meter (N-S) by 3 meter (E-W), but was enlarged on 3 separate occasions to the current 5.80 meters (N-S) by 3.90 meters (E-W) at their widest points. It is not a perfect rectangle by any means. Additionally a small division was left between F 19 and F 1 but these were quickly added to the area of F 19, causing the two trenches to meet at the Western end of F 19, also the Southern edge was also expanded to meet the Northwestern edge of F 4. While it was very useful to have these "open" baulks to loot at during excavation, the fact that 3 of the walls are non existent decreased the possibilities for a particularly drawable section, which in fact occurred as the North wall is not a very indicative baulk. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Originally we had workers clear the area and remove several top layers. All of these layers were designated as Locus 1. Systematic excavation began at about 0.75 meters below the original surface at its highest level. Obviously collection of cultural indicators was not begun until Locus 2 a surface made out of small (most 5x3 centimeters in dimension) river cobbles. Since we had decided earlier that this surface was not a main area of interest we quickly removed it using the small picks. Nevertheless, this cobble surface appeared to have been constructed of only one row of stone with very little pottery used as construction material. As we removed the surface, the locus was changed to Locus 3 and a bag of subsoil was collected for possible analysis (Locus 3 KT # 2). This light fill was found to be about 0.20 to 0.25 meters in depth. As Locus 3 was being excavated we unearthed a burial pit near the Southwest corner of the trench and next to an area where we thought a wall would appear as excavation continued which in fact it did later (Locus 10). I now believe that the burial cut through not only Locus 3 but also Locus 2 and possibly some of the upper layers. The first bones to appear were the skull bones which were noted to be in particularly bad condition. We would come to realize that much of the skeleton was not there, and that it appeared to have been a secondary burial. The bones were collected as one KT (L 4 KT # 1). The contents of the pit were completely sifted using a fine 2-millimeter mesh and additional fragment of bone were located by this method. A small metal ring was located towards the bottom of the burial pit, and consequently labeled as a small find (L 4 KT # 3). It is unclear what metal was used in its manufacture but it may be copper. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;One of the things we knew about this trench before excavation was begun, was that there would be a lot of collapsed bricks. Earlier excavations in both F 1 and particularly in F 4 (refer to notes for these trenches) had shown these as certain possibilities, and so we were expecting them. One of the early proposed ideas was that a massive wall had come down from the South side of F 19 or from inside the area of F 4, we were looking for indicators of where that wall fell from, what were its markers, direction, thickness, and relationships to the other nearby trenches. By the end of this season’s excavations we can say that the wall foundation (Locus 20), was the original foundation to this wall and that its plastered bricks did definitely fall towards the north, possibly hitting another wall running East to West and bouncing back towards what ended up being roughly the middle area of F 19. Additionally, it’s apparent from its signature that the wall proceeded in a North – Northwesterly direction. I am unclear at this juncture as to how far into F 1 or beyond it would have laid.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were days due to worker issues, or while I was excavating other nearby trenches, or even while enlarging the physical space that work on this trench did not proceed as smoothly and as coordinated as it could have been. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As bricks began appearing we began articulating them, it was clear from the start that they were in quite a jumble as if they had fallen from different directions, or possible a second floor could be considered. A later addition to these notes should include mention of a short section of a wall 0.50 meters thick coming off of the North baulk and heading South for about 1.25 meters before turning East for about 0.78 meters. The jumbled mess of the earlier days led me to believe initially that this was not a wall but collapsed bricks. It is a lot clearer now, and it makes sense to believe that this was definitely a wall, or that at least we should keep track of it and make mention of it in these notes, for it may coordinate with another section of architecture at a later excavating time. I will assign to this wall an interim number as Locus 21-B. Nevertheless it was noted that many of the bricks are made of a light clayish material while others are made from loam soil. An idea proposed for this is that bricks made from lighter clay were manufactured higher up the mound where it was plentiful, while the more coarse bricks, often containing pottery and rock, were manufacture using river mud, or sedimentary layers found closer to the Tigris. I made a decision to ascribe to the jumble of bricks one locus number (Locus 6) as I had expected them to continue for quite some time. This turned out to not be the case. The material of the bricks perhaps became redder, their wall signature on the last portion of the remaining East wall of F 1 indicated a large quantity of the red bricky stuff, with the apparent change, which it may turn out to not be so consequential, I change the Locus to # 8. Looking back at the excavation, I would propose that Loci 6-9 might be considered as one locus as I had originally expected it to be. There were variations that prompted these nomenclatures, but hopefully further investigation may confirm this one way or another. I may also add that some of the markers created plenty of differential characteristics. It must be mentioned that Locus 9 took us to the level just above the burned surface. Upon reaching this level we popped the burned brick and collected lots of material. Some of these materials may enlarge our base of knowledge concerning the manufacture and plastering of bricks. While a more notable mention may relate to the characteristics of the fire, its cause, and direction; and answers about the habitational markers at the time of the blaze. It was noted that as the brick was removed, its white plaster faced down, and so it was protected from the burn by their falling. I believe that the brick were plastered and they fell on to a plastered floor. Very likely that the white-yellowish (Munsell: 10 YR 7/2 Light Gray) plaster material used is the same. Here began the thick ash layer, much of it was collected for floating and sampling when those are more available to us. These and other testing may supply better connections for the contemporaneity of the surface (Locus 14) and the mass of bricks on top of it. It also provided a nice sealing to those materials that laid on the surface (L 14 KT #’s 1-18). Additionally the very top of the surface (Locus 12) yielded a lot of pottery some of them with good diagnostics probabilities. From and on site read at the site many are characteristic of Second Millennium EB, Chalcolithic, and possibly even a painted Chalcolithic, or Ubaid sherd was picked up right off the strewn surface. The already mentioned surface below all of these materials (Locus 14) and the subsequent subfloor (Locus 15) were completely removed using the Household Archaeology Protocol, all of the contents of a 0.50 by 0.50 meter square were removed for HAP sampling, 2 litters from the middle were removed prior to sifting for HAP float, while the remaining contents of the surface were sifted, this accounted for a full day’s work and 756 litters of sifted materials, collection was done from the sifted soil. The subfloor yielded an additional 220.5 liters, and the same protocol was employed throughout. In an effort to see if the surface extended East I opened Locus 17, while the plastered surface seemed to continue, the potsherd, stone, and bone material was not found on top of it. This leads me to believe that there was a physical separation between the two surfaces. One piece of pottery we did find on L 17 was very nicely decorated and indented Chalcolithic sherd.           &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The good results on the East side of the trench prompted the continuing excavating of the area which showed us a wall (Locus 18) which was followed North but not terminated due to time constraints. Next season’s work should endeavor to terminate this wall (L 18) and to possibly establish a connection to Locus 5b, the wall Locus 10, or the stone foundation (to Locus 10) known now as Locus 20. The fill above, rather the bricky material above the stone foundation (Locus 20) was assigned Locus 19. One interesting characteristic of L 20, is that the stones appear to have a Northwesterly direction with a section of 6 stones appearing to jut out in a Northerly direction; it is unclear as this point if they continued below the current surface (L 15) or if they were only used as a way to buttress up the wall. This also can be looked up next season. Better definition of L 10 and L 5b is desirable in order to establish better relationships with other architecture and features within the trench, and to help us in connecting the trenches in a systematic and purposeful manner. Interestingly, other than the burial pit (L 4) only one other pit was located in the Northeast quadrant and assigned (Locus 16), this pit, which contained one small subdivision towards the West, did not contain a lot of good pottery. It was notice that a small area on the bottom of the shallow pit was full of very small pebble, I believed by looking at the pit’s wall that it was deposited there along with some ash from the upper ashy level by the erosional forces of water.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It can be said that F 19 was an exciting and interesting trench to dig. As usual I wish I had done a lot of things differently and better. Despite this, a lot of good information was obtained which help us to better look at the usage and habitational patters of the lower town of Kenan Tepe. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It can be surmised from the excavation that most of F 19 laid within and enclosure with a plastered floor and flanked by plastered walls on the East, the South, and the Northwest quadrant area. Additionally there was a wall running East – West (L 5b) which may be intercepted by the East wall running South – North. The continuation of walls, especially those going West help us make some assertions about their relationship with those trenches dug nearby, mainly F 1, but also F 4, F 22, F 20, F 8, and F 9. It is clear that many levels of habitation through time can be documented; additionally we can establish a contemporaneous existence at the time of the large fire. Hopefully a more extensive and close read of the pottery and the HAP material will help give us better clues as to causes, and usage. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p/&gt;&#13;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-19-2005-06-22-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/660D9283-6AAC-4A3F-F944-73F18786CC39</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-19-2005-06-22-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F660D9283-6AAC-4A3F-F944-73F18786CC39</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.831335</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.8154335</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/660D9283-6AAC-4A3F-F944-73F18786CC39">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 19</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>660D9283-6AAC-4A3F-F944-73F18786CC39</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:37:57-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:37:57</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
