<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="66DE072A-47FA-4644-1C6A-73E40FD05FD3" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>C-2-2005-06-026-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>5CEF3D15-27AF-42CC-C4D5-77A592EC8EB5</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/D86F8A70-C7F9-4B28-0A8A-6468DDC7C619">D86F8A70-C7F9-4B28-0A8A-6468DDC7C619</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-26</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C">
              <oc:name>Area C</oc:name>
              <oc:id>48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:C-2-2005-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary, Year 2005 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sounding 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;June 26, 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This arbitrary 1m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; sounding was sunk into the southwest corner of Trench C2 to investigate the extent of occupation through time on the western side of the tepe. The datum point is the C4 southwestern corner and is 597.16m above sea level. While the 5x5m C1 trench appears to be late 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;rd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium BC, we wished to explore whether or not earlier occupations, such as the ‘Ubaid and Late Chalcolithic found elsewhere on the tepe, also exist here. This sounding has been excavated by two people this season, Jeanne Nijhowne and myself (Marie Marley). I began the first locus (2163) of the sounding, Jeanne took over for her last week and then I took over again from her. The sounding was started at the final depth of C2 after the 2003 season, which was 595.84 meters above sea level. The final locus (2182) is 592.33 meters above sea level, and therefore makes the sounding approximately 3.5m deep.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavation of the Sounding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sounding locus 2163 was removed as a cleaning locus since it was directly below the plastic laid down at the base of C2 at its closing after the 2003 season. JN then took over the woundng and the following is based on her locus sheets for loci 2164 – 2171.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A mud brick wall was uncovered in L2164, but there is no other information about it relating to height or courses. Further information from baulk drawings is necessary to establish accurate dimensions. L2165 contained a great deal of ash and ashy deposits. Some cultural material was also recovered. L2166, 2167, 2168, and 2169 were generall fill loci. L2167 contained a small bronze pin (KT C.2.2167.7). In L2170 there appeared to be a change in soil consistency and an olive green brick was recorded. The soil is very wet in the sounding, so it was difficult at times to notice consistency changes during excavation. L2171 consisted of more general cultural fill. This locus was not finished by the end of JN’s final day of excavation, so I took it over halfway through and then finished the excavation of the sounding on June 23, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Due to the confining nature of the 1m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; sounding, the only tools able to be used for excavation were the small pick and the hand trowel. The small pick was generally used for the purposes of loosening the soil and then the trowel was used for articulating features and scraping down loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;During the removal of fill locus 2172, a single course stone wall was uncovered. Through further investigation, this stone wall was determined to be a stone boundary to a tricolor mud brick wall (L2173). After examining the southern, western, and northern baulks, it was found that the wall had cut through the western side of the sounding on a roughly north-south axis and had been preserved to a height of approximately 1m. In the western baulk, it is also evident that the wall was cut by a pit. The wall is comprised of three colors of mud brick: green, brown and red. This is similar to a tri-color mud brick wall found in Area I. This wall (L2173) is thought to have been associated with domestic usage rather than functioning as a city wall. The stone boundary (2174) based on its limited height, but also the stones were aligned in such a way as they were made to create a relatively smooth line on the western side abutting the mud brick wall (2173) and a rougher outline facing away from the wall. Also associated with this stone boundary were smaller stones and pebbles balanced on top of the medium sized cobbles. The earth directly over the stone boundary was a deep red color, similar to the red bricks and this could have been in place over the stone boundary to help keep these smaller stones. Further excavation of this feature in the C2 trench is necessary. On the eastern side of this mud brick wall and stone boundary was fill (L2175). Also associated with the wall/boundary combination is a small pebble/pottery surface (2177). This surface was only present in this sounding to a small extent and was therefore not able to be sampled using the Household Archaeology Protocol (HAP). In the southern baulk it is evident that this surface ran up to and stopped at the L2174 stone boundary.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Below the stone boundary/mud brick wall combination (L2174/2173) was a thin layer of fill, that might have been a mud brick layer since two green bricks were noticed beneath the stone boundary. Below that layer of fill was a four course stone foundation (L2176) that covered the majority of the base of the sounding. Below 2176 was the fill locus 2178 and within 2178 a secondary single course stone feature (L2179) was uncovered. L2179 is directly aligned with the third course of the stone foundation (L2176) and with the original single course stone boundary (L2174).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The final three sounding loci (L2180, L2181, and L2182) did not reveal any other architectural remains or significant cultural fill. L2180 did have a good amount of charcoal flecks in the matrix and there was an area of pebble buildup in the eastern baulk, but there was not enough present in the sounding to determine if this was a pebble surface or not. That could be explored more in the future through excavation of trench C2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The western baulk of the C2 sounding was drawn, but has not yet been evaluated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interpretation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The main focus of the interpretation of this sounding is on the stone boundary and mud brick wall (2173 and 2174) features and their construction. We believe that this wall (L2173) is related to domestic structures as opposed to being a part of the city wall, which is significantly larger and located approximately 10m down the hill from C2. The single course stone feature (L2179) as the earliest architectural structure uncovered in the sounding is not yet understood in the larger context of the trench. The stone foundation (L2176) is easier to explain as a foundation for the mud brick wall and stone boundary. The surface (L2177) was related to this structure and based on the surface abutting the stone boundary, suggests that this could have been the internal area of the space being divided. Further excavation in the trench would be necessary before other hypotheses could be made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Future excavations of this trench will hopefully be through excavating the larger C2 and therefore most of the problems of excavating a sounding, namely the small nature of the exposure created, will be solved. It would also be helpful to get a better recording and understanding of the mud brick wall mentioned in L2164. Otherwise, every locus described here continues into either the northern or eastern baulks which are within the C2 trench area. The southern baulk moves towards C3, which also has been unexcavated since 2003, and the western baulk leads towards the western base of the tepe and the sounding containing the city wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: C-2-2005-06-026-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/66DE072A-47FA-4644-1C6A-73E40FD05FD3</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+C-2-2005-06-026-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F66DE072A-47FA-4644-1C6A-73E40FD05FD3</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830723</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812647</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/66DE072A-47FA-4644-1C6A-73E40FD05FD3">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 2</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>66DE072A-47FA-4644-1C6A-73E40FD05FD3</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:06:20-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:06:20</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
