<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-7-2001-08-22-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CAE379A0-075A-4956-AB55-332F39747C3A</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1D3885D1-4832-4332-E0A6-75A8E8B9895C">1D3885D1-4832-4332-E0A6-75A8E8B9895C</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-22</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Previous">3609DA34-D259-4A51-BC1B-98433DAE58A0</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Next">A54D84BE-033E-4547-36FF-5CA37E6E34E4</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD">
        <oc:name>Trench 7</oc:name>
        <oc:id>D6B9114A-A32C-48A6-7F28-46B4B9A661BD</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/3609DA34-D259-4A51-BC1B-98433DAE58A0">
        <oc:name>F-7-2001-08-18</oc:name>
        <oc:id>3609DA34-D259-4A51-BC1B-98433DAE58A0</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Previous</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/A54D84BE-033E-4547-36FF-5CA37E6E34E4">
        <oc:name>F-7-2002-07-02</oc:name>
        <oc:id>A54D84BE-033E-4547-36FF-5CA37E6E34E4</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Next</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-7-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area F Trench 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 22, 2001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This year I opened Trench F7. This trench is located in the lower north-eastern part of Kenan Tepe and was a 10x10. This trench is bordered by two 5x5 trenches: on the East by F2 and on the South by F9. One 5x10 (F8) lies to the southeast of trench F7. F7 was opened specifically as the result of last years excavations in F2. They found a cobbled surface in the baulk that continued West. This is where F7 is located. This year we encountered the first level of occupation. We moved about 1 meter of dirt in the western half of the trench and 1/2 meter in the eastern half. The difference between the two is mainly due to the natural slope of this area. The trench was practically level when it was closed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavation this year can be summarized by dividing the trench into 3 main areas: the eastern half, the southwestern corner, and the northwestern corner. The eastern half can be characterized as an area of many surfaces, occupational debris, and two burials. The southwestern quarter was mainly topsoil with some rock features that may have indicated surfaces, but if so these surfaces were poorly preserved and not found in excavation. This area is also characterized by a mud-brick structure that extends into the northwester quarter of the trench. The northwestern quarter of the trench can be characterized by 2 pits, one partially preserved surface, and a portion of the mudbrick structure. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started excavating the eastern half of the trench by assigning the topsoil visibly disturbed by plow furrows as topsoil fill L7000. We pushed through this layer of topsoil fill in the northeastern corner, and then decided to open a 2x2 sounding level in this corner in order to find the cobbled surface as soon as possible. We assigned the fill between the topsoil and the surface as L7003. We found the cobbled surface we were looking for about 30 cms. underneath the topsoil. This surface was one of 5 that were found in this half of the trench.  In excavation it was found that surface L7005 was partially sealed by a later surface, L7040, and both L7005 and L7040 were sealed by surface L7010. In excavating these surfaces, we took flotation samples of L7005 and L7010. We also took soil samples from various areas of the surfaces for possible future chemical analysis. All of the chemical soil samples that were taken on August 14, 2001 and August 18, 2001, the days we removed these 2 surfaces, are plotted on supplementary dayplans. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parallel to these surfaces further south in the trench, there was one area that was marked by many layers of pottery debris lying on a surface. These pottery debris layers, which include loci L7009, L7018, L7023, L7025, and L7026, were characterized by significant amounts of hard-packed, flat-lying pottery. It was only after excavating L7009 that we realized there were many layers of this pottery debris. The excavator would peel one layer off and find the next layer directly beneath it. This was consistent for 5 layers, and then we finally found surface L7030. There was another surface that fits this profile that was found perpendicular to L7030. This was assigned as surface L7024. A direct connection was not found in excavation, there was a space of about 10 centimeters between these surfaces, however both surfaces were characterized by a large amount of flat-lying pottery and they lay in a 90 degree relationship to one another. Both of these surfaces were excavated on August 14, 2001. Flotation soil samples and soil chemical analysis samples were taken and plotted on supplementary dayplans. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After all of these surfaces were excavated, we opened their subfloor fill loci. For L7010, it was L7036, for L7030, it was L7037, and for L7024, the subfloor fill was L7038. L7036 partially covered surface L7005 and completely sealed L7040. After excavating L7040, no subfloor fill layer was assigned as surface L7005 lay directly beneath it. After excavating L7005, subfloor fill L7045 was named. This subfloor fill was left on the last day of excavation. Special attention should be paid to this area as it was a datable, sealed portion of the trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A human cranium was also found in the northeastern corner of the trench. It was assigned as locus 7006. This burial cut surface L7005 and so we had to excavate this area a little differently in order to extract the burial. We had to cut into the eastern baulk by 25 cms and the northern baulk by 75 cms. In order to bring this as of yet unexcavated portion of the trench down to the level of the burial, we had to name a topsoil layer locus L7011, a sub-topsoil layer locus L7012, and finally the fill around the burial as L7013. We also had to take a portion of the cobbled surface out earlier than the rest, so a 1x1 area of L7005 was renamed as locus L7016 and taken out. The subfloor fill layer to L7016 was named as locus L7017, which is equal to subfloor fill L7045. Also, photos were taken of the complete surface excavated to that point with total station points. On the other side of L7005 we named a fill locus of L7007. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The burial L7006 was actually excavated by Amy. The burial was a child that was situated on an east-west axis. It took her 3 days to completely extract the burial. The skeleton was KT'd as 7178. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We kept taking down elevation in the eastern part of the trench and went through arbitrary fill layers L7020 and L7035. We found a few more things in the southern end of the trench as a result of excavating the fill layers. In the middle of the eastern part of the trench, on the last day of excavation, we found a very large circular pit. It was assigned locus L7043 although it was never excavated. We also found an area that had a very large concentration of redeposited virgin soil. It was thought that this may have been some sort of structure, so we assigned it as locus 7039 and sectioned it to see what it was. We found nothing to suggest it was a structure, so the last day of excavation, we leveled the entire locus and closed it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The only other thing to note in this area of the trench was the discovery of another burial. It is located in the far southeastern part of the trench towards the center. This burial was assigned as locus L7028 and was not excavated this season due to the abundance of burials and not enough time. There were a few fragments that had broken off of the cranium that I collected at the end of the season. They were KT'd as 7315. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The southwestern quarter of the trench was not characterized by much in the first part of the season. We pushed down elevation in topsoil fill layer L7001 and we found what we thought might be a surface in a cluster of rocks. We made it locus L7002, but excavation did not turn up an associated surface. Either it was a surface that was not preserved, or just an anomoly. We named a sub-topsoil fill layer as locus 7004 and kept pushing down elevation. We went through another fill layer without finding anything substantial. The fill layer was locus L7019. In pushing down all of this elevation, we inadvertently pedastled a small group of rocks. They were not associated with any surface, or anything else for that matter. We assigned it as locus 7027 so that we could level it and KT whatever we found in it. We also found an area that was composed of one large rock conglomerate and a poorly preserved surface. We named this area L7014. This locus continued to stay in the southern part of the trench while we named another fill layer, L7032, and continued to push down elevation. When we pushed down we realized that there was a soil change in the middle of this area. It was reddish in color, and ran in a linear fashion parallel to the western baulk. We scraped the area and found a linear feature that was perpendicular to the original reddish area. It was determined that this mass was a wall, and probably an entire structure. We pushed back L7014 to uncover the other corner. This group of mudbrick walls is very faint. It would be easy to miss, but it's exact location and elevation is plotted on the final day plan. Once we figured out it was a wall, we cut a section right through the center of it. This section encompassed the wall and the surrounding fill. This was locus L7034. We also dug a probe in the fill next to the northwest corner of the wall. This was to try and see if we could detect any mortar lines or individual bricks. We went down 10 cms but had no success and closed this locus at the end of the season. This too, is plotted on the final day plan. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The northwestern corner is the last area to discuss in detail. We pushed down elevation with the same fill layers as the southwestern quarter...L7001, L7004, L7019, and L7032. Early in the excavation process we uncovered what was a cluster of rocks and pottery that seemed to indicate a surface. This was assigned as locus L7008, but excavation did not turn up anything else to indicate a surface. We found two pits in this area of the trench. These were assigned as loci L7021 and L7022. We excavated both and they appeared to both be rather shallow, so I closed them during the season. As we continued taking down the elevation, it became apparent that we had not full excavated pit 7021, so we reopened it as pit L7042, but by this point there was no time for further excavation. Pit L7021/7042 cuts a surface that we found against the north baulk. This was surface L7029. It extended east, and there seemed to be a tenuous connection with surface L7005 in the northeastern area of the trench, but nothing concrete. The fill between this surface and fill L7007 in the northeastern part of the trench was assigned as L7031. L7029 was excavated, but no soil samples were taken as it was not a sealed surface. After the surface was taken off we found what looks to be the beginning of another surface. We assigned this locus as L7044. This would be a sealed surface, so attention should be paid to this area. It is also cut by pit L7042. Both are unexcavated, but on the final dayplan. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;During excavation this year I found 10 grindstones, 8 of which were found in fill, and 2 within surface L7005. I found one obsidian blade, one glass rim, one spindle whorl, one half circle of basalt, one metal pin and one possible stone tool in fill loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This year of excavation allowed us to encounter the first occupational level in F7. It was characterized by many surfaces littered with pottery debris in the eastern half of the trench, pits and poorly preserved surfaces in the northwestern quarter, and some sort of mudbrick structure in the southwestern quarter of the trench. I feel like I am dealing with some sort of outside occupational area in the eastern half of the trench and the northwestern quarter of the trench. I am not surprised to find what looks to be a mudbrick structure in the center of the southwestern area as nothing was ever found in that region of the trench. Hopefully next year we can come to a clearer understanding of what the context of F7 is as we push down into earlier occupational layers.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because we did not move a significant amount of dirt this season, there is not a lot in my baulks. We did not draw any F7 sections this year. Right now they show a lot of varied topsoil fill layers. Many of the features in my trench were in the center and therefore do not show up in the baulk. Surface L7005, L7030, and L7029 all intersected the baulks, but only left a few cobbles as reminders of their existence. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the season, all of the major surfaces were removed. What was left to be plotted in the final dayplan included the sealed subfloor fill layer L7045, pits L7043 and L7042, burial L7028, surface L7044, and the mudbrick structure...L7033. A mudbrick structure showed up in F9's northern baulk, which was drawn, which may extend to the southwestern area of F7. If that is the case, we are only a few centimeters above where that should take place, so the next excavator should be aware of that. The last locus number used this year was L7045 and the last KT# was 7317. I feel as though this trench was successful for an exploratory first year with many possibilities for next year. Good Luck to the next Excavator!!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-7-2001-08-22-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-7-2001-08-22-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.831542</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.815434</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 7</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:24:49-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:24:49</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,600 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3600</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 7</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>77097222-9F4A-41B7-AFEA-A9B776D132A3</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:51:07-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
