<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="84FD9C54-8360-4358-A2BC-2D1CA1651F4C" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>G-10-2005-06-023-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>28E6FA74-3C47-4738-8EAF-8E40B070EF83</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/190E49F3-A269-4B34-94DF-F931736406E4">190E49F3-A269-4B34-94DF-F931736406E4</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-23</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">45CCC0CF-A2BC-46F9-3F5E-B659D044A25F</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/45CCC0CF-A2BC-46F9-3F5E-B659D044A25F">
        <oc:name>Trench 10</oc:name>
        <oc:id>45CCC0CF-A2BC-46F9-3F5E-B659D044A25F</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/CB5EB7DE-B106-48D5-CA00-EDBDF7D93BB6">
              <oc:name>Area G</oc:name>
              <oc:id>CB5EB7DE-B106-48D5-CA00-EDBDF7D93BB6</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:G-10-2005-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area: G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench: 10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;June 23, 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;                                                                                               Diana Backus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trench G 10 was situated in the middle part of the Eastern hillside of Kenan Tepe,            below G 1-6 and about 50 m below G 9. It was entirely new trench with length 10 m and width 5 m started up on the new spot on May 22, 2005. Originally there was idea to place the trench following Andy’s radiographic pictures showing up so called "busy" places indicating approximate remains under the top soil. Later on Bradley decided to open the trench following one line below G 9. The main reason of starting up this trench was to ensure the possibility of occupation of this part of the tepe. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;           From that point the excavating in this specifically spot became very successful. Over the course of this excavating season we went 2 m below the top surface, at the highest top elevation 574.14, and the lowest elevation at the end of the season 572.14. Almost immediately under the first 30 cm top soil we came across of great boulder wall foundation (L 2 and L 4). According to the ceramic material found in synchronic level this wall foundation refers to Early Bronze Age settlement. In the North-West corner of the trench, at the elevations a little below the bottom of the stone wall foundation, were uncovered evidences of long term domestic activity (L 7). The proves of this statement is the attestation of definite pebbled floor surface with simultaneous fire place (not designated as separate locus because the main part of it stayed under the baulk), purposely built circle stands (see field photos, L 7), most likely for holding the pots, significant amount of shards, animal bones and a bronze needle (L 7: KT# 3). Along with this feature we came across of stone structure protruding from the North baulk (see the day plan from May 29, 2005 and following field pictures). Synchronically was found a little pebbled patch in the middle of the trench (L 10) that was possibly associated with the floor surface in L 7. At this point is difficult to do any definite interpretations because if this is a complex of some domestic activity its main part is under the West and North-West baulk. After that we removed about 25-30 cm of dirt and debris. Notable was relatively small amount of ceramic shards and two grinding stones (L 8: KT# 4 and L 9: KT# 6). At elevations 572.78 – 572.71 we came across of architectural structure. This was relatively large room, luckily placed diagonally across the trench (L 15), which gave us chance to follow its North-East and South-West corners and the three wall lines (see the day plan from June 6, 2005). In L 16, that is inside of the wall (L 15), we found a fireplace. Simultaneously we found another wall cross of South-East part of the trench (L 19). Both walls were built most likely from mud bricks, although it was difficult to follow their shape. Later on we could see their outlines (approximate length 0.35 m) in the North baulk underneath of the EB stone structure. The mud bricks were more clear outlined after removing L 19. At the beginning of excavating L 19 we thought that we have here another corner of other room but later on it became clear that we can’t really see the corner and all what we had was just one part of the mud brick wall. In this context we had already Chalcolithic transitional ceramics. After removing the mud brick layer from the walls (L 15 and L 19) we went through short hiatus (L 20). Though we found a bronze needle at its elevation (572.55; see L 20: KT# 4). Underneath of the mud brick layer in the North-East part of the trench we reached a solid stone foundation (L 21), which East end was bonded to a very massive grounding stone (seeable dimension: length 0.40 m, width 0.40 m, height 0.30 m). At the same time was found another, but smaller, grounding stone in the South-West part of the trench. Assuming that the two grounding stones should bond one wall we tried to trace eventual remains on the line between these two grounding stones. Fortunately we found part of the wall, or wall foundation (L 27) exactly on the probable line between two grounding stones and this gave us the reason to assert the existence of the wall (although its bigger part was completely destroyed), forming a large room placed again diagonally (North-East/ South-West) in the trench. Two fireplaces (L 24 and L 28) in two following levels, and the plastered floor surface (L 29) were to confirm that this was the room or the house with long term use. Furthermore I think that the last stone wall foundation was reused in later time for building a smaller house, which was L 15, and inside space – L 16. At the level of L 26, related to the Late Chalcolichic Period, we found relatively small amount ceramics and no artifacts (except one loom weight found outside of the room: see L 23, KT# 8), which tells us that this place was in temporary use or left suddenly. After removing the remains of Late Chalcolithic stone wall foundation we were digging very mixed deposit without determinate structure over the course of last two days. We closed the trench under these conditions. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In general we had very little amount artifacts: four grinding stones from the upper levels (see L 6: KT# 14 and KT# 15, L 8: KT# 4, L 9: KT# 6), two bronze needles (see L 7: KT# 3 and L 20: KT# 4), one loom weight (see L 23: KT# 8), and one shell bit (see L 30: KT# 6) and one bone needle (see L 30: KT# 9) from the lowest level of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the excavating season we left no loci in excavating process. We closed the trench at two loci, L 25 and L 30, both as fill. Although we did not have any definite structure I would make some suggestion for next excavating season. In L 25 could be tracked out the bottom of the wall (L 19) and eventual floor surface associated with it. In L 30 is possible pit close to the west baulk (see closing up the trench photo from 6/22/2005). I really think it is worth!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;                                                                                                                                                                                  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;                                                                                            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&#13;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: G-10-2005-06-023-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/84FD9C54-8360-4358-A2BC-2D1CA1651F4C</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+G-10-2005-06-023-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F84FD9C54-8360-4358-A2BC-2D1CA1651F4C</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.831376</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.814601</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/84FD9C54-8360-4358-A2BC-2D1CA1651F4C">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 10</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>84FD9C54-8360-4358-A2BC-2D1CA1651F4C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:51:11-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:51:11</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
