<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-8-2001-08-18-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>AD72AC5D-D01B-41CE-D5D9-0F7C60E93753</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/45E9D409-EAF2-4551-988A-206ADAB882D9">45E9D409-EAF2-4551-988A-206ADAB882D9</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-18</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Previous">85F9BF49-3AF5-4917-67B8-ACA75CA703D0</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Next">9E493194-8779-4A55-A9FF-1C6ECB887F5F</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">F401D38B-28FF-4978-3110-13E1763F1A71</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F401D38B-28FF-4978-3110-13E1763F1A71">
        <oc:name>Trench 8</oc:name>
        <oc:id>F401D38B-28FF-4978-3110-13E1763F1A71</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/85F9BF49-3AF5-4917-67B8-ACA75CA703D0">
        <oc:name>F-8-2001-08-16</oc:name>
        <oc:id>85F9BF49-3AF5-4917-67B8-ACA75CA703D0</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Previous</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/9E493194-8779-4A55-A9FF-1C6ECB887F5F">
        <oc:name>F-8-2005-06-04</oc:name>
        <oc:id>9E493194-8779-4A55-A9FF-1C6ECB887F5F</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Next</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-8-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug. 18, 2001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;KENAN TEPE 2001 Season Excavation Summary and Conclusions for Trench F 8 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Excavator: Marco Baldi (and students of the Choltepe Archaeology School) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This has been a good season in Kenan Tepe. It was also a good although simple season in my trench F8. This piece of real estate that we call F8 is located on a rise overlooking the once &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;mighty Tigris, that famed river of historical and biblical proportions and one in whose banks civilization began. This is a beautiful green spot in the midst of an often dry and dreary land that are the foothills of the upper valleys of Southeastern Anatolia.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;F8 a new trench this year was opened on July 22, 2001. The location of the trench in the "lower town" section of Kenan Tepe allow us an excellent view of the main 60 meter high tell to the Southwest. The trench was initially laid out as a 10 by 10 meter square trench but the restrictions of the terrain forced excavation for at least this season to a limited 5 meters wide by 10 meters long with one half meter of that on each side preserved as the baulk wall. The main problem for the inability to extend the trench lies on the Southeastern corner of the trench which is several meters below on the cliff descending towards the river. The proposed plan for next year will include excavation on the Eastern half of the 10 x 10 trench. The Southeast corner though, might still be out of reach even then.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area F is comprised of several trenches, F1 to the Southwest, F4 to the Southeast, F9 to the West, F7 to the Northwest, and F2 to the North. There is also a sounding F3 to the East on the cliff which was not excavated this year. It is on this latter trench (or very close to it) that my Southeast corner lies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our purpose in opening this trench was to continue researching the continuation of some interesting features found in adjoining trenches of area F. We thus seek to enlarge our understanding of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;those past people who made their homes, streets, and/or structures on this section of the tepe. Our direct aim then is to locate and excavate the architectural remains which signify habitation of the area, for how long the area was used, for what purposes, and perhaps the reason of its eventual demise. This location, if topography has remained somewhat constant, would have been an excellent spot to look over planted fields, to guard the herds from marauding preying animals, and to serve as a look-out point for approaching danger from invaders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Actual excavation has moved fairly quickly due to the absence of major architecture or features. Actual depth of excavation approaches 1.15 meters in the Northwest corner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A short compilation of daily and weekly activities highlighting the major events and finds follows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;During the first week of work a well preserved rough baked clay oven was found sticking out of the West wall about .31 meters below the surface and close to the middle of the trench. This oven was given Locus # 8002. The oven looks in shape and function much as the ones you see for sale today. It would have been buried through other levels but the top of it was still high enough that it was probably damaged during the plowing of this flat area. The oven contains were sifted and two bags of ash mixed with soil were collected as the preservation of the walls would have sealed contents very well. It should be noted that half of the oven lies within the West baulk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The results of the second week of excavation include the finding of two very similar rock formations with one additional like formation on the opposite side of the trench but with some dissimilar characteristics. The first two circular formations were located within the South half of the trench. One is located in what would be the Southwest quadrant, the other in the Southeast quadrant. The last of the three circular formations was located in the Northwest quadrant of the trench. These formations were given Locus numbers 8005, 8006, and 8009 respectively. It was first thought that these formations represented improvised cooking pits, but this idea was quickly abandoned as we realized the absence of the remains from cooking: mostly ashes and/or bones. Since the formations were almost "perfectly" circular and with small stones lining the bottom of the formations (with the exception that L8009 was not lined with stones on its bottom) the thought occurred to me that these formations would have been created with the intention of placing containers in them. I believe that the container would have been large enough that only the lower part would have been within the formation. The process of fabrication of these features would have an individual lining and leveling the bottom with small fairly round stones tightly packed, the pot would have then been deposited and when it was realized that it was not leveled then additional larger and flat stones would have been used to line parts of the "wall" (sides). This seems the case to me as for the most part these lining stones are flatter and larger on two sides and would have been chosen carefully. As mentioned above, the third circular rock formation L8009 did not have a stone lined surface but this was made of dirt and the rocks used as wall were of different sizes and roundness, one was quite large in comparison (it maybe supported the pot on the Northeast side), most of these stones were not at all flat like the ones in L8005 and L8006. One of the stones was a worked piece of basaltic rock. The proximity of Locus 8009 to the oven could attest to a contemporaneity between the two.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is important to note that all three of these features could be contemporary with each other as their bottom elevations vary by only .05 meters. Because of the height of the different rocks used in the constructions of these formations, elevations in the day plans and the locus sheets might appear to be quite different.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also began uncovering a couple of areas filled with pebbles that could turn out to be surfaces, these two areas have locus numbers 8010 and 8011 and are at approximate elevations but are separated by almost 1.5 meters between them. Locus 8010 has a lot of good diagnosable pottery on the surface, one of these sherds was identified in situ as being third millennium type 95 with fingerprint indentations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As excavation continued the scattered appearance of small white pebbles was noted, these pebbles are of a clay like material and are mostly small and quite white when you break them apart. These white pebbles do not seem to follow a constant pattern, but I believe they appear in association to or at similar intervals as the reddish soil does. The white pebbles can also be followed in the baulk not only in these trench but also F1 and F9 to the Southeast and East of F8. The red soil is also not the predominant soil in the trench and could signify changes and/or appearance of walls and or bricks. While it is true that bricks today like at the tepe near by are mostly made of a lighter colored mud, the reddish soil could be the remains of similar bricks made with both inorganic and organic elements which would have -over time- degenerated and given the reddish tint to the soil. The mud brick builders of today may also use one, or a variety of hardening compounds (like cement) of more recent manufacture. While it is quite possibly that similar compounds were used anciently it is also quite possibly that some of these materials would have leached out (white materials that clumped into pebbles?). What remains from either of these processes could be the cause of the reddish tint on the soil. In any case there are clear differences of soil color and texture. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Subsequently to the finding of the two areas of small pebbles mentioned above, additional areas have been located. These are enumerated as Locus 8018 near the center of the trench; Locus 8019 next to Locus 8010 also an area of pebbles itself; and Locus 8020 Northeast of 8011. Unlike the first two areas these new ones are at different elevations. Their composition is made up of small to medium cobblestones, pebbles, and broken pottery remains. Their differences in elevation was at first suggestive of a wall that upon breaking or falling down would have left part of its contents scattered at different heights due to terrain, surface items, etc. The wall idea of course is not supported by the found contents, as walls were not made from these materials. The idea that these cobble areas were part of a surface, suffers from the differences in elevations, that is, unless we can verify some powerful earth moves in years past. These height differences makes it more plausible to think that they are in effect the remains of several surfaces which survived other adjacent and contemporary areas by a number of unknown elements. In other words and as one of many possible explanations, water runoff in extremely wet years could have washed off the remainder part of the leftover floors or surfaces. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;When the cobble surfaces were removed and after the trench was sprayed thoroughly two round areas signifying pits were located, one of these was partially obscured by the oven L8002, Doctor Parker had a thought that these two features could have been associated as an smelting oven facility were impurities would have been knocked off during blooming and then fallen to a lower pit. When the oven was removed though, it was realized that the oven bottom was approximately .05 meters above the beginning surface of the pit. Even so, we were careful in sifting the contents from the pit for salvageable cultural materials. Other than ash and bone no metal was found, telling us in effect that this had been a cooking pit. The smaller Locus 8022 turned out to be quite shallow and devoid of ash or cultural remains. The bigger Locus 8023 pit was dug out and the contents sifted until its termination .22 meters below its surface. It was noted during the emptying of the pit that ashy remains stopped at about .05 to .10 meters below, with little bone and no ash in the remaining .10 to .15 meters. After excavation of the pit was completed it was also noted that soil color change had occurred and two distinct strata were present within the pit. I should have caught that during the excavation but didn't. During the excavation of adjoining fill we went ahead and changed the locus number when we arrived at this stratigraphic change (from 8024 to 8025). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We have played during the last few days of excavation with possible wall that we had hoped was materializing in the Northwest quadrant of the trench. We have had some color changes hard and/or soft soil and what may be better be described as possibilities of patterns that together would have given us a wall, but it was not to be at this point of the excavation and these features eluded us for now. This business of wrestling walls out of soil which has undergone countless changes during millennia is not an easy one to decipher.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;If I may advance a theory for excavators of this trench next year, one should look for more changes as those specified above and look for features found in Trench F7 to the Northwest and also for burned materials like the ones found at deeper elevations in trenches F1 and F9.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The West baulk was drawn and it shows a very clear outline of the pit Locus 8002 with a good amount of ash mixed with soil still in it. The baulk also shows color differences nearer the Northeast corner where red soil is visible, as it contrasts with the white-ish soil next to it. There are also visible layers of the white pebble material mentioned above and their start and stops throughout the excavation. All of this really doesn't tell us much about this trench, but it reinforces some of the peculiarities of near-by trenches. There is some architecture which has just recently been located in F7 to the Northeast and I hope it may also extend towards this trench, even though I have already passed that level. There is also architecture just coming up in F2 at about 0.75 meter deeper than F8 but which unfortunately moves in a direction that would put it outside of my 10x10 meter trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Exciting things are in store for next year. And by the way... we did use at least a trowel, big picks, and small hand picks at some point. But most of the work was done by worker ants which I bribed with gum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-8-2001-08-18-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-8-2001-08-18-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.831447</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.8155105</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 8</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:26:42-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:26:42</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,100 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3100</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 8</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>93F3245D-4058-4548-D330-5B4E4D1A2539</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:50:44-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
