<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="94919645-B93A-4377-383C-051CAC676900" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-4-2001-08-014-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>69A61DD8-F86E-4193-5570-0C02FAF209B7</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/85E4D081-827E-4B3D-113F-0403B5ECF1F2">85E4D081-827E-4B3D-113F-0403B5ECF1F2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-14</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">618BCB52-381B-4263-C3CE-99676745E24D</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/618BCB52-381B-4263-C3CE-99676745E24D">
        <oc:name>Trench 4</oc:name>
        <oc:id>618BCB52-381B-4263-C3CE-99676745E24D</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-4-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 14, 2001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trench is on the east side of the Tepe, that was opened on July 8 and it adjoins the 2'x2' sounding D3. D4 is a 10'x5' trench. D4 is at the west side of D1 and D2, a week later D1 and D2 were consolidated into D5. The trench was 10cm deep when I started to dig (July 9, 2001), and I have closed down August 13, 2001 Monday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It took me six days to get rid of the topsoil (L4000, 4001, 4005, 4006) and subtop soil (L4003, 4004); by the way, L4002 was the rocks that showed up in the north west corner of the trench. This means that, till L4007 (the mud brick collapse) I have mostly used the big picks and very frequently I have used the small picks, and with L4007 I began to excavate with trowels. Because this locus L4007 was the collapsed mud bricks, which were big and seemed to be burned, I decided to dig more carefully.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D is at the slope of the Tell, that's why it was very easy and quick to excavate the first four loci, because till L4003 I have removed top soil and sub top soil, and then till L4006 I have removed slopewash layers. I was almost 80cm deep at the west side of the trench before hitting the first occupational layers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After getting rid of all the slopewash layers I have swept and cleaned the whole trench and opened new loci, because I came down onto occupational layers. My first floor locus is 4009, that I have opened on July 17. It is important because it is sealed by 4001 and 4003 (topsoil), and actually I found the first small find of the trench from this locus 4009 that has the kt# as 4060. It is a small broken ceramic bull figurine. To the east of L4009 lies L4013, this locus is at the south side of the trench, it equals the floor L4009, but because of being at the slope of the Tell L4013 is much closer to the top soil, it is covered by much more erosion dirt and slopewash layer than L4009. On the other hand, the soil below L4007 and L4014 (the collapsed mud brick layers) turned out to be a pit (L4024 and L4028). It was the first pit of the trench, and it was covered by the collapsed mud brick pieces. After we removed the collapse layer L4007 and L4014, the pit's locus number became 4024, because I found a chunk of plaster and an ash layer. Than the pit became L4028 (it is still 4028), because I found a second ash layer and new pottery pieces. The base of L4028 is also the base of the pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This pit (loci 4024 and 4028) is cutting all the surfaces in the trench, like L4025, L4030, L4032, L4041. The loci surfaces 4030 and 4041 are sealed by surfaces 4023, 4026, 4017 and 4018. These two floors L4030 and 4041 are in a way hard packed earthen surfaces, they have got many various types of ceramic pieces.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as Bradley said, the pottery pieces from these two sealed floors (4030 and 4041) are type B2 and B4. Besides these two types I have picked up many Hellenistic pottery pieces.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was digging to find out the mystery and to learn more about the first civilizations of the world, and actually by examining the sounding D3, I was able to see the floor that has been made of rocks, that have the size of 20x14cm. This floor in the sounding D3 reminded me that it might belong to a small yard or to a walk way. I tried to imagine how people in the ancient times lived, I want to know how things were in those days...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The most interesting small find from D4 was the broken hair pin. It is made of metal and it is thin. I found it on July 22, on L4022, its kt# is 4106. L4022 was to west of the pit (L4024 and L4028) and west of the sounding D3. When I began to excavate L4022, I was using small picks, but after finding the hair pin (it was at the top of the locus; the elevation is 88.44), we continued with small picks and trowels. The soil of L4022 was removed 20cm and I decided to take it off by each 5cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Besides these, I found 19 basalt grindstones, a few of them were near to the pit (they were on the south side of the pit mixed in with the collapse mud bricks; L4007 and L4014), the rest of the grindstones came up from the sealed floors 4030 and 4041.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After dealing with many pottery from surfaces 4030 and 4041 on July 31, I have found a road while excavating on the west side of the trench just beneath the fill layer L4034. This road is L4040, and it is made of river stones turned on their narrow edges and are laying parallel to each other. The stones are running in the direction of east-west. On the same day I have found the mud brick wall; L4035, abutting L4040 to the south. It seems that the wall was built first and the stones of the road were placed later, because the edge stones stand up straight against the wall. The (visible) length of the road is 1,40m (the road continues into the west baulk), and the width is 0,65m. The stones around the edges are slightly larger than the ones in the middle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After a few days I have found a pavement, consisting of several stones and large potsherds. This pavement is L4037, and it is clearly abutting the mud brick wall L4035 on the north side. The stones on this pavement various in size, but they are giant (ave. 20x30cm). After seeing this pavement I wanted to be sure if these stones may go beneath the sealed floor L4041, or not. To be sure of this I have firstly used the small pick (for 4cm) and then I have used the trowel. Now I am sure that the stones are going in the south direction of the trench, because the stones run underneath L4041.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At this point I think that the pit (L2024 + L4028), and the mud brick wall (L4035), the road (L4040), and then the second wall that is made of rocks (L4039) which has three rows are related to each other. This part of the trench might be the outside of a house (the pottery pieces that have been found from these part are from Early Iron Age. To have a stratigraphical guide Bradley and I cut 12cm from the west side of the pit (L4028), but we could not see anything. So, we did not use the probe further.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the other hand, when we take a look at the baulks I can say that the north west side where L4022 is located, and the west baulk are very good visual guides for D4, and also the south baulk of the sounding D3 and the west baulk of D3 are very good visual guides for D4. These baulks help me in understanding the relationships between the loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, just before closing down the trench I have opened a new locus for the new pit that is placed on the north side of the trench, that is halfway in the baulk, and it is 6cm deep. Its locus number is 4044. So, in D4, the pavement (L4037), the mud brick wall (L4035), the fill (L4039), the slopewash part (L4036), the river stone road (L4040), the fill (L4034), the stone wall (L4043), and the basin created by excavating the pit (L2024 + L4028) remain in situ as I did not finish excavating these loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the other hand I have to mention L4008, that was hard packed soil with no sherds, and it was located in the south west corner of the trench. Later on I changed locus number here to L4018, because the soil became softer, then I changed again to L4023 because the soil became loose, and then I changed yet again to L4029 because its texture changed again with the soil becoming hard. Then I changed locus in this corner again to the loci 4031 and finally 4036, which are underlying layers of hard packed soil. So, I changed the locus in this corner each time the character of the soil changed. Besides these, L4010 is the under surface of L4009, and L4011 were the rocks in between L4009 and L4013, these rocks were located at the north part of the portion. L4016 is the fill surface just above L4022, and L4016 was abuting L4019, these tow loci were fill, too. L4033 was the second pit of the trench, it seemed to burned and a few pieces of slag came out. So, the next season I will start from the unexcavated loci that I have mentioned above.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-4-2001-08-014-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/94919645-B93A-4377-383C-051CAC676900</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-4-2001-08-014-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F94919645-B93A-4377-383C-051CAC676900</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830637</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813654</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/94919645-B93A-4377-383C-051CAC676900">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 4</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>94919645-B93A-4377-383C-051CAC676900</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:58:13-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:58:13</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
