<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="98180C14-CB81-4593-707D-C589893EEE5C" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>A-9-2002-08-024-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>38FD4DF5-54B0-45FD-B78C-DF2409346248</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7575A054-4130-4112-8F51-A0B2DEA78FC4">7575A054-4130-4112-8F51-A0B2DEA78FC4</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002-08-24</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">D27F0AF8-3A11-43B5-42ED-F5523316A0A1</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/D27F0AF8-3A11-43B5-42ED-F5523316A0A1">
        <oc:name>Trench 9</oc:name>
        <oc:id>D27F0AF8-3A11-43B5-42ED-F5523316A0A1</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59">
              <oc:name>Area A</oc:name>
              <oc:id>F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:A-9-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Final Trench Summary, Year 2002 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Area A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Trench 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 24, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A9 is a partition of the original step trench A2. The trench begins at 25m down the tepe and ends at 41m, which is the bottom of the tepe. The trench is 2m wide by 12m and is located directly below A8 and we share one baulk between us. Hereafter I will refer to sections of this trench as 1-12m not 25-41m. We started in top soil at the beginning of the season at the elevation of 589.52 at the south baulk, our final elevation for the south baulk is 585.26 for a total of 4.29m dug at the south baulk. We moved all of the top soil from the 1-12 meter mark but did not get past subtopsoil in the north 3.75 meters of the trench. We had originally pegged the trench as a 2m x 16m trench but decided to open A10 sounding below the 12m peg in order to reach virgin soil. The goal of the season for the step trench was to reveal the stratigraphy from the top of the mound to the bottom and hit virgin soil at the end. We did achieve our goal in trench A9 when we reached the late Chalcolitic layers because most of the previous steps in A2 had been Early Bronze Age, according to the pottery reading.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This part of the step trench had never been dug before so we broke new ground directly below trench A8 which was the end of where Ellie dug in the 2001 season. The top soil, L1, continued for about a meter before we hit a change in fill color which appeared to be subtopsoil in L2. We kept L1 and L2 open all the way down the trench to the 12 meter peg. We only reached subtopsoil, L2 at the middle step about half way down the trench, the north 3.75m of the trench is still in L1. We reached a layer of very hard red fill at the south baulk which became L3. Later we saw that we had cut through a 1 course 1 row mud brick wall in L3, we could not see an associated features in section. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The large mud brick wall, L7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this wall in L3 we began hitting large layers of mixed fill with dark and light ash mixed with mud brick debris. It was hard to delineate changes in the composition of the fill since everything was so mixed. We opened L5 as the top of these mixed ashy fill layers, L5 later became the top of a tall mud brick wall which was L7. Two cylinder seal impressions were found in a pottery bag during pottery reading, KT 21 and 22. I am not sure if they were found in the same bag, they were given to me after they were discovered.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The fill south of L7 mud brick wall was L6. We screened L6 at a 1:3 ratio and found a small find bone bead, KT 18 during screening. We also found a nice bull head figurine, KT 23, a small ceramic chalice KT12 and a clay disk shaped bead KT 25. We changed to L8 when the mixed had a higher concentration of mud brick debris than ash. We opened L9 at the SW corner of L8 in an area of especially large animal burrows. We later split L8 into L13 and L14. L13 is soft ashy fill with a smaller concentration of mud brick debris and L14 is a very compacted area of mud brick debris. L6, L8, L13 and L14 all abut the wall in L7. We spent a week or so slowly sectioning off each fill locus trying to find some sort surface or foundation to the wall. We finally did find the bottom of the wall after we cut to a layer of ash that began at the south side of the wall at the south baulk beneath the wall to the north another .5m. The continuous ash layer was split into three loci. L13 which had been opened under L14 at the west baulk south of the wall, L18 directly beneath the wall foundation and L15 ash north of the wall. We decided to merge all of these loci into L18 after we finished excavating the wall system. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After we found the continuous ash layer we had to reevaluate what the fill below the colored bricks of the wall was. It was later decided that the wall was built upon a thick and compacted clay foundation, L17, which was a grey color and had no bricks or lines in it. We can see in the west baulk that this foundation layer continues south of the wall and is equal to the hard packed clay in L14. We excavated the wall in three parts, L7 is the bricks, L17 is the compacted clay foundation, and L18 is the ash layer beneath. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also in the SW corner of the trench we found a small area of very compacted clay with lots of river pebbles that was extremely difficult to chop through with a hand pick and impossible to trowel. We later saw in the south baulk section that this may have been the top of a very thin and almost undetectable surface leading directly to the wall. Beneath layers of seasonal deposits of ash and mud brick slump.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;North of the wall in L7 we opened L12 as slope was which we continued to the edge of the top step. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L7 was poorly preserved but it appears that there were at least 2 rows and 5 courses. The wall did not reach the east baulk but there was a layer of fill which we called L17 as well that continued to the east baulk. On the day of excavation I made a top plan of what I think the wall looked like. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After clearing L7 and L17 we opened the entire south 1m x 2m section of the trench to L18. In L18 we found the remains of a white reed impression, L19 which was very similar to the earlier phases of reed impression in Trench A8 and Trench A2 in the upper levels of the step trench. We can see remains of L19 in the west baulk which we drew onto the west baulk section drawing. What was unique about this impression is that it was nestled in an ashy area so we were able to take some good flotation samples. We scraped off L19 and saved a few samples for further analysis. We closed L18 and L19 and opened L20 as mixed fill and L21 as an area of mud brick debris at the SE corner of the trench. We cut a sounding in the East half of L20 and stopped at some very compacted clayey fill which became L22. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Pit, L23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;When we cleared L20 we found a huge pit below which was about 1.75m x 1.2m and about 1m deep. The pit is L23 and was mixture of loose dark ash, very loose almost powder like areas of lighter ash with shreds of white organic material, clumps of clay, mud brick debris, and charcoal. In the early layers of the pit we found a small area of tiny river pebbles, very colorful and a large concentration of clam shell also from the river. When we decided that L23 was definitely a pit we dug it as fast as possible to get rid of any mixed contexts. The fill was so soft we dug it with a shovel most of the time. We finally reached the bottom of the pit and an area of compacted clayey loam devoid of ash which we called L26 and did not get a chance to excavate by the end of the season. L26 may have a surface coming up at the SW corner of the locus because we found some flat lying sherds and a large animal jaw. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We continued digging L22 as the fill adjacent to the pit until we reached a small surface, L29 with some pottery debris, L28 laying on top. The surface in L29 was the same fill as L22 but it had a small ash area that could be a hearth in the south west section of the locus. We picked up some partial pots one fine ware, KT 2 L28 and some cooking pot pieces KT 1 L28. Also in L22 we found a series of large cobbles adjacent to the west baulk that could be a foundation for a wall but they were not very organized. There were two cobbles that were flat and thin that could have been used as a flat work surfaces. In this area we found a lot of obsidian flakes and under one of the cobbles we found our first Ubaid pot sherd. It seems that most of the Ubaid sherds are concentrate in L22 or the fill below this area and not on the north side of the step in the surfaces. It is possible that some earlier pot sherds were dug up in a later period. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We closed L22 and opened L34 as the fill below the level of the L29 surface. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Once we had cleared all of L22 adjacent to the pit we could see in the south baulk a perfect outline of the pit where it touches the walls around it in L22 . It is more narrow at the top than at the bottom and bows out at the very bottom where it touches L26. There is a very nice drawing of it in the south baulk section drawing we did later in the season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Layered surfaces and small mud brick walls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here is a very interesting area of the trench and series of small debris surfaces with some small poorly preserved mud brick walls. All of these contexts occur between the second and third meter peg of the trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began by digging this area as part of L12, mixed slope wash. Went through mixed fill locus 24 and L27 until we reached the top of the first surface, L30. This surface was very poorly preserved and difficult to follow or articulate because it was basically debris stamped into a hard compacted clayey fill mixed with many small river pebbles. We closed L30 and opened the fill below as L31 cleared that area until we found L32 surface which was better preserved that the last one but was only 1m in length but the exact same composition. We picked up L32 surface but did not screen because we thought the fill was too compacted to screen. We did not find any small finds in this surface. We closed L32 and opened L33 as fill below. Excavated to the next surface in L37 which continued all the way to the west baulk but was cut by a pit L36 at the east baulk. It was at this point that this area became complicated. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Before finding the surface in L37 we had seen a small mud brick wall with a cobble foundation, L39 coming up at the SW corner of L33 by the time we had articulated L37 we found another smaller mud brick wall with 2 cobbles associated with it, L38. These two walls are a similar color and composition and they abut each other but L39 is substantially higher in elevation than L38. I believe that these two walls are related as either earlier and later levels of the same wall or a terraced wall. We can see in the west baulk that there was a mud brick wall which has eroded down a slope and ended on top of the current series of surfaces. We have drawn this in our section drawing of the west baulk. The red bricks of these walls are not directly associated with the surfaces but may have been built at alternating levels with the surfaces and the compacted fill above these surfaces may be debris from a previous mud brick wall construction. This is possible because each new surface continues under the level of the previous mud brick debris layer and does not stop abruptly at it, as it would if the surface and the wall were built contemporary to each other. We took down the walls in L39 and L38 and cleared the mud brick like grey fill below them as one entity L41. Then we extended L34 as all of the fill south of L37. We now had a clear view of L37 which had extended further south below the level of L38 and L41. We cleared the surface in three parts, two sections for micro analysis samples to go to Andy and the rest was screened and separated in the correct artifact screening bags. We changed to fill below L37 to L40 and cleared it to the new surface L42. L36 continued as a pit which cuts L40 and 42 at the east baulk. I believe that this pit may extend into the adjacent locus L35 but I wanted to dig down the the level of L35 to see if it was true. L42 is a very well preserved version of the same surface in L37 and the previous surfaces. We did not have time to excavate this surface before the end of the season. The fill abutting this surface looked very much like mud brick. I cut it down slowly and sprayed and scraped around a lot looking for mud brick. I sectioned off an area what I thought was mud brick as L43 and cut it down in sections looking for brick lines. We cleared L43 and opened L44 as fill abutting the surface. This is how we left it at the end of the excavation season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Slope wash and the edge of the first two steps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because of the nature of the step trench invariably the best contexts are to be found very deep and far from the slope edge. We had many erosion layers starting with the topsoil loci L1 and L2. Continuing to L12 as the fill adjacent to the top step, then L16 and L25 as more slope wash continuing further south in the trench. Our goal was to have the entire 1-8m leveled as one step, which we very nearly accomplished. The way I did this quickly was by changing to a mixed locus like L12 and cutting back the edge of the step until I found a change in fill. That way we could get a section on what contexts or fill layers we would be excavating. This is how we found the wall in L7, and the we were able to know exactly when the surfaces would come up in L32, L37 and L42. As we were cutting back more of the slope was in L25 we found an area of loose ashy fill at the south west corner of the locus that contained a small andiron KT 22. We then changed the south meter of L25 to L35 because we had cut past the eroded fill and were in mixed ashy fill layers. In L35 we cut down about 15cm to get a better section on the surfaces in the adjacent step and found that below L42 there is another surface coming up identical to the previous ones, we did not get the chance to reach that level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Things to watch out for next season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In L26 the bottom of the pit we may have surface coming up at the SW corner. In L44 the fill south of the surface L42 there is an Ubaid sherd in situ at the SE corner. There may be some Ubaid contexts coming up. L42 surface has not yet been excavated and will probably not be preserved next year. Luckily under L42 a the level of L35 there is another identical surface coming up. L36 is still a pit cutting the surfaces and fill next to them, it probably continues to the level of L35. The rest of the trench is eroded fill, only L35 may yield some new contexts at the its southern most area. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="bulleted_list" awml:style="Bulleted List" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: A-9-2002-08-024-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/98180C14-CB81-4593-707D-C589893EEE5C</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+A-9-2002-08-024-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2F98180C14-CB81-4593-707D-C589893EEE5C</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830917</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813397</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/98180C14-CB81-4593-707D-C589893EEE5C">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 9</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>98180C14-CB81-4593-707D-C589893EEE5C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:43:05-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:43:05</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
