<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="A66F0273-47E0-4AD1-48A9-58A504652F98" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>E-2-2005-06-019-Weekly</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>FABC613D-55D6-4924-C12A-C8ABDCB92351</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188">6A885F1E-D6A2-40B8-F9BF-37E0A9BB4188</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Weekly</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>2424418E-0A10-4B21-7B7E-C857ACA19EFA</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/FF540762-9F09-40DC-708A-01EFE6106863">FF540762-9F09-40DC-708A-01EFE6106863</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005-06-19</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2005</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2">538EAD8D-6588-44CC-2B51-272173D5B5D2</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2005</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="person" info="Recorded by">B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>071431E0-0143-4CCF-4953-17A033264EC8</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
              <oc:name>Area E</oc:name>
              <oc:id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:person_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C" cite="contributor">
        <oc:name>JW</oc:name>
        <oc:id>B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Recorded by</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:person_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Weekly Trench Summary 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area E, Trench 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. Henecke&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This week was the beginning of a new phase in the excavation of the trench. We finally reached the old sounding level (L45) in all areas, and I began the week by closing all old loci (L90, 92, 100, 101, 103, 104, 105, 106) and opening new ones. Before doing this, I finished excavating ash pit L105, which is now a circular area extending into the southeastern baulk. I also removed the gray fill soil L90, exposing a small cluster of stones (L106), which may be debris from lithic production activities. This cluster seems to abut the small L92 stone wall, which was also removed at the end of the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The sprayer was very useful for identifying mudbricks and pits. Adjacent to L105, we found a series of pits cutting into one another and two sections of a mudbrick wall (L114 and 116). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I began by excavating pit L113, which appeared initially to be a surface sloping down into the soil. I believe, however, that this was the bottom of a pit that had begun in the previous L77 locus – where we discovered evidence for mudbrick debris and organic pseudomorphs. I then excavated L115, a kidney bean shaped pit that cuts the two wall sections, and the small pebbly L117 pit, which cuts a section of L116. L115 contained mudbrick debris, which I believe is a product of when the wall was blown out, and at the bottom of the pit are rows of mudbrick. The excavation of L124, to the north of this pit, further clarified the situation. It is now clear that a section of L114 runs beneath these pits, which places these walls earlier than the pits. It is my hope that later in the season I will be able to connect this section to L116. This entire area – the southern half of the trench – has been a disturbed area for several weeks. It is clear that these pits contributed to the mixing. Beneath L113, I created a L112 fill locus, which contained a group of EB or Late Chalco pots and demonstrates the mixed context of this area. It is not yet clear whether other forces, such as erosion off the tepe, contributed to the disturbances in this area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L114 is a very clear wall with at least 3 courses running out of the eastern corner, but L116 is far less well preserved. There are two disjointed courses in L116, and where one course cuts off the other begins. This wall was very difficult to articulate because there is mudbrick debris on all sides, which made it challenging to identify in situ bricks. Also, the wall seems to be cut off at the extreme western end, although, I assume it once continued in this direction. There were several decorated Ubaid sherds embedded in the wall (KT 1), which provide a date for this architecture. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Emerging from L105, by which it was cut, is a stone wall composed of a single row of medium stones. Initially, the locus on both sides of this wall was the same (L110), but I eventually split the sections when I attempted to find a surface between L119 and 116. In the area to the south of the wall, I uncovered a small pebble and sherd surface, which seems to have been cut by pits L105 and L123. I was unable to correlate this floor with the wall, although this may be a result of the pits and soil disturbances. At the end of the week I took a 9 L soil sample from this surface and plan on removing it in the beginning of next week. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was also unable to make an real correlations between L119 and features to the north. It appears that L116, 118, 120 and 119 may form a street locus between two structures, but I never found a true street surface in L120. L120 is a fill locus between the two walls, and the was very compact next to the stone wall and more loose and pebbly by the mudbrick wall. At a level even with the L118 surface (about 586.20 m. above sea level), there was a more dense concentration of pebbles near L116, but it was too thin and insubstantial to indicate a surface. It is possible that this truly was a street, and the use surface was more of an interface in a fill level. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The otherside of L116 and 114 proved more productive for producing good contexts. There is a clear difference between the soil – which appears gray – and the lighter brown fill soil in the rest of the trench. I began in this area by removing a L45 – a few centimeters of weathered fill. I divided the area into three parts. L107 occupied the area above L101 and 104, L108 rested beneath L45, and L111 was positioned beneath L90 and 106. These areas are probably very similar, but by splitting the loci, I have more control over what may arise in the area. Beneath L108, we found the remains of a plaster surface, with flat lying pot sherds and lithics. There were also two stones – possibly grinding stones – above this surface. I spent the week clearing the suprasoil to reveal the surface. Initially, the floor arose into areas (L121 and 118), but by the end of the week, the two combined and spread across the entire area. There is only a small ashy pit in the north corner (L127) that does not contain this surface. The floor clearly touches L116. We currently speculate that this is an interior surface associated with the L116/120/119 street feature. As with L122, I was only able to take a HAP sample (9L) before the end of the week, and I will have to wait until the 18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; before I can excavate the rest of the floor. The sherds pressed into this floor (KT 3) are clearly Ubaid, and at this point in the season, we have begun to excavate good Ubaid contexts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: E-2-2005-06-019-Weekly</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor href="http://opencontext.org/persons/B8A7ABCA-53A8-4598-4CFA-2D19DBF3F21C">JW</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/A66F0273-47E0-4AD1-48A9-58A504652F98</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+E-2-2005-06-019-Weekly&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.contributor=JW&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FA66F0273-47E0-4AD1-48A9-58A504652F98</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830333</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813539</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="contained" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C">
        <oc:source_name>Area E</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>517D21A5-0632-43F6-74C4-99104D5EEE5C</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T20:53:51-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 20:53:51</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
