<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="A8F77C2A-3CCE-4553-33B0-E10D5F8528BD" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>C-4-2001-08-019-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>9E27D9F8-5DF8-44C1-F3D8-D3BFC2440970</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/BF8BE676-E41B-4EA7-738D-899E0E4DA70C">BF8BE676-E41B-4EA7-738D-899E0E4DA70C</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-19</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">85AC91BF-2978-4211-F6E2-75F999AD5A8C</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85AC91BF-2978-4211-F6E2-75F999AD5A8C">
        <oc:name>Trench 4</oc:name>
        <oc:id>85AC91BF-2978-4211-F6E2-75F999AD5A8C</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C">
              <oc:name>Area C</oc:name>
              <oc:id>48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:C-4-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;C4 FINAL TRENCH SUMMARY &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aug 19,2001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;C4 is a 10 meter by 10 meter trench, located on the high mound at the west slope. Area C has four trenches in the current situation, two from last year; C1 and C2 which are 5 meter by 5 meter trenches. C3 and C4 opened this year in order to have a wider explosion of the area as 10 meter by 10 meter trenches with a better understanding with the information from the last year’s two trenches. C4 ‘s neighboring C1 but also have a lot of similar features with trench C3. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this area the early layers were having Early Iron Age pottery and changing to the Late Bronze Age pottery afterwards so what we were aiming was to understand the EIA of Kenan Tepe better with large exposure of the area as well as investigating the transition between Early Iron Age and Late Bronze Age. Also other interesting thing that we saw in this area last year was the slag pits in trench C2 so we were aiming to identify more about that production that I think we accomplished.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the season I reached 90 cm depth in the SE corner of the trench which was located in the higher elevation when I opened this trench. But we could not go very deep in this trench because of the features that I was always facing and also I was trying to level the trench to this higher elevation part. Because of that we are not deep in the western side of the trench unfortunately because this side of the trench had aids from C1’s baulk. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we started digging I took out L4000 and 4001 as top soil and sub top soil loci where I found 3 fish net weight and at that point I hit my first strata which had a lot of rock features scattered around in various shapes and various sizes. Here I started to dig my trench in four quarters with artificial baulks between them for a few weeks then I needed to take them out because I had to find out the relations between the features in the different quarters. . L4002 was the first rock feature that I hit which was a rock grouping without any purpose that could be figured out. Then we started to hit a lot more of this rock features in this first strata. Afterwards some of them started to have some meanings as L4004 and 4020 were rock features that were used to cover ovens (L4027 and 4031). L4003 turned out to be a pit cutting a wall in the next strata which almost stayed in my trench from the first day to the end. L4007 was a mudbrick collapse looking locus that contains a lot of slag in it so it is possible to associate this with the rock circle L4006 right at NE of it and with the surface 4009 located at the NW of the locus also with the slag pit in the next strata. L4006 was a rock circle as mentioned before that we thought it might be a burial because of the suspicious shape that it had (circular rock structure closed with huge rocks on top) but could not find any bones underneath. We put a frame around this rock circle in order to dig it as a burial and I gave a locus number to that L4021 that I extended a lot later to the whole quarter because there was no separation with this frame and the fill around it. L4015 was a locus that both seem to be a wall or a surface that I could not figure out so this is the locus that I marked as a feature. L4017 was a locus seems like a wall with pot smashes sitting on it goes directly to 4012 that was one of the undefined loci. L4018 was looking exactly like a door opening with doorposts and threshold right in front of it. But it did not mean anything to me until we found the wall 4041 which might be related with this locus. L4008, 4011, 4013and 4016 were the rock clusters that I excavated without building any connection with something else except L4011 was sitting at the corner of the walls that I found out in the next strata (L4030 &amp;amp; 4041) Because of the division of the trench all the fills between these features were separated too and these were: 4005, 4014, 4019, and L4010 where we found a stone ball possibly use for counting. L4022 was a possible surface that might be related with the wall at the NW quarter of the trench which is L4023 and the feature L4025 which seems to be a rock dump in front of the threshold in L4018 but also going below L4018. Also L4024 started to evolve at this first strata when we took off half of the artificial baulk between NE and SE quarters in order to find out the continuation of L4002 which was the first rock feature of the trench. We also found another feature that does not seem to have an aim under the baulk (L4028). But afterwards the locus L4024 extended to S under L4002 and in the next strata it was on top of the wall 4030 and also could be considered as it was cutting L4030. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The next strata was the one that we started to find the two walls L4030 and 4041. The first wall that we found out was the long one which was almost 6 meters in length and 0.8 meters in width and sloping down a little towards N. Also this wall was cut by L4003 and then I changed the locus number of this pit to 4047 arbitrarily because I was at the end of the first course of the mudbricks in the wall. The second one (L4041) was found a little late but it was perfectly perpendicular to the first wall that we found. Then our aim turned out to be finding the bottom of the wall with the surface related to that. But after we identified this walls we found out the ash pit at the E side of the wall L4030 at the SE corner of he trench which turned into a section that we were using as a section to the wall also. (L4032) There was a part at the east side of the 4030 wall and north side of the ash pit which seems to be mud brick collapse was called L4040 and this was keeping the surface 4061 underneath which was the associated surface of the wall that had EIA diagnostics. Also this surface was partially below L4042 which was the softer part at the N of L4040 but after we started to take this off we found out some mud brick collapse underneath it. Also there was the surface L4026 that might be related with the walls especially after we found out about the L4058 which was the other mud brick wall like feature also perpendicular to the wall L4030. To find the continuation of this locus at the E side I opened a new locus for the fill there called L4029 where we found a nice metal needle (KT 4135) and a lithic blade (KT4134). In this surface of L4026 we found out layers and layers of pottery stuck on top of each other with a few small finds as a stone ball (KT4231). After I removed these layers we hit a smooth plaster surface here under a small amount of fill which was named as 4059. This was coming out with flat bottoms as well as it was flat on top so the pottery that we collected from L4026 might be related with this surface (4059) also. The other possibility about the L4026 is the possible relationship with the feature 4037which was right under L4022. The other possible outside surface which might be associated with the wall 4030 was L4034 that we found at the W side of the wall. This was not a very well preserved surface but had some pottery and some pebbles underneath. Under L4029 I opened another layer for the fill because I was finding some more stuff and within this fill we found the rib case of a big animal out of butchering activity and I named this as L4053.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also at the SW quarter of the trench in this strata we found an oven called L4035 which might be related with the slag pit looking features L4048 and L4054. In L4048 we could easily saw a flow and these are composed of big pebbles that are stuck together within some dirt because of high temperature and melted metal. The situation of this oven made me think that there is a relationship because the oven was destroyed by high temperature. Other interesting thing about the oven was that we found some organic material in it. Also the melted pot looking loci L4049 and 4050 with oven fragments and some burnt stuff that was certainly affected by high temperature might also be related with this oven because of the location and the proximity. We have to mention the small one row wall 4046 and feature 4055 in relation to the oven. After the removal of the fill L4045 under these features we found another wall abutting to the oven L4062. This wall was composed of two rows that one of them was touching to the oven. We had the surface here at the level of the oven at the SW corner of the trench (L4036) which also covers the slag pit L4054. (this surface might be cut by that pit but I could not figure it out because of the use of the same kind of material) The fill stratigraphy in this part of the trench is L4021 over 4045 and 4057which was covering the whole S part of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Around the other wall 4041 we had two fills one at the N and one at the S of the wall. S was L4044 which was smooth and soft and 4043 was at the north that we found the surface L4033 where we found a sceptre (KT4168), the surface or feature L4060 and the pile of rocks L4039 abutting to the wall 4041 which might be a related surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also the NW quarter of the trench had the lowest elevation so I could not dig this part deep. But we found a few features there such as the oven L4031 and the rock feature with the mudbrick screen L4038 and the possible wall L4023 and the rock pile L4025 in front of the L4018 which was the door opening. The fill here turned from 4019 to 4051 when we started to take the features off. After we started to dig the northern part of this fill 4051 I saw a color and texture difference at the SE part of the L4051 which was more crumbly and whiter than the rest of the locus and I named it as L4063. Then I found out that this is coinciding with the new wall L4064 that we found out under the fill 4057 so I closed 4057 and open two new loci for the E and the W of the division created by the walls 4062 and 4064 and the W is 4066 where we found some pottery sitting on top clustered in the middle so this needs to be searched for a surface next year. And at the East I combined the levels below 4057 and 4044 and opened the locus 4067.Here we noticed a line on he floor which is forming a circle that I marked as L4069 as a possible pit but next year we need to look at this again after scraping and going deeper little more. The South baulk was cut a few centimeters back and this baulk-cutting locus is named as L4068. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We usually dug this trench with small pick and trowels because there were too many features that we were facing. Although there are exceptions of the large area fills that we used a big pick.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is not very possible to see too many differences in the sections. Only one which is worthy was the east part of the south baulk but it still does not give stratigraphic information very well and because of the shortage of time we could not draw it..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;If we try to put things together; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;First of all we see the scattered rock features in the first strata that some of them indicate that there were some slag production in the area. Most of these features have two rows and the first row was always river rocks and the second row was big huge sand stone like, smooth face yellowish rocks. There are a few loci proves the slag production in the deeper levels, too. Especially the level around oven L4035 with the grouping of the oven and the slag pits with flows visible and melted pot smashes, and the mud brick pieces coming with the oven features. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As another strata we have the thick mudbrick walls (4030, 4041, 4058). The size of the walls indicate that this was an important building. There are a few surfaces that we found out can be associated with these walls. They are: L4034, 4061, 4026, 4059, 4039 and 4060. And these surfaces usually have EIA pottery with good diagnostics. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also had some little stone walls and L4062 is accidentally or no parallel to wall 4030. Also if we consider that this part is lower in elevation, it is possible that 4062 is the foundation of a mudbrick wall that the wall itself eroded away by erosion. Also the surface L4026 and 4059 coincides right into this area formed as a rectangle by these four walls.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other interesting thing relation of the features with these walls is the one between L4041 and 4018, 4025. The door opening like locus 4018 coincides right at the end of the wall 4041 and it is slightly north which makes it even better if we think that you cannot enter anywhere from the wall. L4025 seems to be a dump of rocks used as a ramp to the door opening loci to the threshold looking rock.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We shall note that the oven with the slag production activity around was within this strata although I used these for proving the slag production.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the other strata that I was coming at the end of the season we can correlate the wall L4062 ad 4064 with each other which is separating the E and the W halves of the trench from each other. Actually the components of these two areas were different from each other, too. The W part was having a harder and more crumbly looking face that we started to get in locus 4063 and in the part 4066 we are have sitting pottery that might indicate some kind of a surface related with these walls. Also in this layers the type of pottery stats to change from EIA to Late Bronze pottery. That is a reason that I believe that L4062 is more related with L4064 than it is with 4030, 4041 and 4058.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The other interesting thing that I noticed in the whole of my trench was about the walls. All the collapses of the walls in the E side of the walls which is now uphill side and against the gravity. This is applicable to both small and big mud brick or stonewall. As can be seen in walls: L4030, 4015, 4023, 4046, and 4062. This may indicate that there were a topographical difference, terraces or may be an earthquake although it does not seem very possible because thee seems to be in different time periods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt; So I think in my trench I have a big public building fragment from the Early Iron Age which does not have good surfaces related because they were close to the top soil and destroyed by roots and stuff. But also we could find fragments of surfaces in both sides of the wall. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also in the earlier stage there was kind of a settlement there that I think the stone architecture of the trench goes with. But I could not excavate these layers this year s the associated surfaces and the related features could not be dig.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I am leaving this trench in a situation that I am right on top of a new strata. Which has some stone architecture especially at the W side of the trench which is a lower elevation. Also there is a possibility that there is a surface in L4066 in the next few cms because I was finding some sitting pottery in the middle of the trench. But in the E side I could not find the bottom of the huge mudbrick walls and could not take off the surfaces at the north side of the wall 4041. In the W side of the wall there is a possible pit that I marked as L4069 in my notebook. In the NW side we dug the corner a lot deeper because we were trying to find the surface that we saw in the baulk of C1. But then I changed my plan and decided that leveling the whole trench is a better idea. So that part stayed deeper. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are planning to cover the mudbrick wall and the surrounding because this locus is sealing what is underneath.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The last locus number that I used is: 4069 and the last KT is 4383.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	      Elvan BASTURK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;span&gt;08.19.2001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: C-4-2001-08-019-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/A8F77C2A-3CCE-4553-33B0-E10D5F8528BD</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+C-4-2001-08-019-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FA8F77C2A-3CCE-4553-33B0-E10D5F8528BD</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830874</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812707</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/A8F77C2A-3CCE-4553-33B0-E10D5F8528BD">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 4</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>A8F77C2A-3CCE-4553-33B0-E10D5F8528BD</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:02:37-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:02:37</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
