<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="ACDA9FCB-9FC4-423F-BF6E-E6B7E278B3BD" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>B-1-2000-08-015-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>A9252B4C-F1A7-4931-B9AF-FE0B6310A7C1</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/37F59561-78E1-4AD4-36D6-F7AEF62DA634">37F59561-78E1-4AD4-36D6-F7AEF62DA634</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-08-15</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">F4221B6E-0099-4AA3-8266-90010E253776</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F4221B6E-0099-4AA3-8266-90010E253776">
        <oc:name>Trench 1</oc:name>
        <oc:id>F4221B6E-0099-4AA3-8266-90010E253776</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23">
              <oc:name>Area B</oc:name>
              <oc:id>CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:B-1-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/21/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After a long time we marked off the square.  We dug 10 cm into Locus 1000 an area roughly one third of the square, finding a few bones and some pottery, but no lithics. The topsoil was dark tightly packed soil, with weeds on top. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We let the workers dig about 10 cm too far and too fast.  We did not detect the change in soil color until the workmen had cleared the full third of the trench.  When they began to dig the rest of the square we found a layer of hard packed, grey clay (which we first believed to be mudbrick), this we named Locus 1001.  We spent a few hours clearing the rubble from the trench and scraping the thin dark top soil off the clay layer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;By the end of the day we began clearing the hard packed clay and at the same time trying to level the square.  We managed to clean and "level" 2/3 of the trench, finding numerous pottery sherds in the process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Due to the chaos of the day we were only able to take one elevation at the beginning of the first locus.  We have the opportunity to catch up on elevations tomorrow as the levels have not changed significantly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/22/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We forgot our dig bag this morning but were able to borrow materials from the neighboring trench.  We took elevations for Locus 1001 using the stadia rod method instead of the line level method we used previously.  To remain consistent we recalculated our measurements for Locus 1000 from the baulk. We cleared the rest of Locus 1001 and found several animal bones and pieces of pottery. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Among the finds were a piece of overfired ceramic, which was labled small find KT#1006, it was found in the SE-corner of the square. We decided to close locus 1001 and began sweeping and cleaning it.   Here after we (MS) marked of a sounding area, which was labled locus 1002, along the East baulk (1.4 m) we dug about 10 cm. The finds from this locus were mostly bones (KT# 1008) and many pieces of pottery ( KT#1007).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The dirt was the of the same kind as in locus 1001. Though there seemed to be areas filled with a loser dirt type, but these are relatively small and irregular, they could not be considered pits. Some of the dirt was more massive and hard (tough dirt) which maybe mudbrick-tumble? As we cleaned the locus 1002 we uncovered 7 large potsherds which we thought may be part of several pot smashes.  That was not the case so we plotted, photographed and removed them.  Near the North East Baulk we plotted some reddish clay within grey hard clay that may be a crushed potsherd or clay that had been exposed to fire. We began to clean the rubble from Locus 1002 and prepared to even out the trench.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While sweeping over Locus 1002 a workman swept some more of Locus 1001 and uncovered a small round white body sherd laying flat.  We decided that it was still in Locus 1001 and we plotted and removed it.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We changed to L. 1003, because we thougth there was slight change in soil color.  Most likely we thought that there was a pit or oven somewhere and were concerned about the slight changes in soil composition.  We now know that Locus 1002 and 1003 are the same and we have indicated that on our records.  There were large rocks strewn about Locus 1003 that we hoped would indicate some architecture, as well as more soft dark fill that we had encountered in the previous locus.  After spending a lot of time scraping the floor looking for some architecture we gave up and conferred with our dig supervisors.  We were told that we had nothing and we should just blast our way another 15 cm.    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We opened Locus 1004 on the North East wall of the trench digging about 10 cm and then we dug another 20 cm in a 1 x 1m sounding in the North East corner.  We will extend this to the rest of the trench tomorrow.  So far the soil and contents have not changed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/23/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began to expand the deep part of locus 1004, (KT#1013-1017) so it would fill one half of the trench (2x4m). Seeing no change within the soil, we continued to expand the deep area into the other half of the trench. All hope seemed to be lost, when one the workmen (Asiz) uncovered a series of rocks running from the South baulk towards the West baulk. It became clear to us that this most likely some sort of foundation and we decided to label it as locus 1005 (KT# 1018-1019)( JPP named the wall-foundations "Asiz’s Wall" ). The small area between the wall and the SW-corner became locus 1006 (KT# 1020-1022). After the identification of these loci much of the work was directed into cleaning / leveling the trench. While doing this we uncovered two very small spots of different soil types, one within the wall, which had a yellowish color and the other along the North baulk, which had a grey color very much like the soil around it. These "spots" seem to be made of coarse sand (very much like the sand we today use for concrete) which was entirely different from the surrounding clay.  Adjacent to the East side of the wall foundation, in Locus 1004, was what we thought might be some mudbrick.  We took a sample and labeled it KT 1020, we decided that it probably wasn't mudbrick so we dug through the layer and leveled the trench.  Along the western baulk (locus 1004) we also found large pieces of pottery, which still sit in situ. They appear to be parts of storage vessels. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;07/24/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started the day by taking elevations.  On the advice of Andy on the previous day, who suggested that the material below the wall on either side would be different than the material above it.  We opened three new loci using the wall as a dividing line.  The first was on the south west side of the wall which had previously been part of 1006, we sunk a .5 x .5 meter sounding 20cm deep trying to find another course of rocks that would indicate the size of the wall/foundation in the adjacent locus 1008. We did not find any new layers, but we did find  various pot sherds and bones imbeded in clay beneath the stones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the east side of the wall we opened a 1m wide sounding 20cm deep from the south east corner of the trench directly up to the wall.  We called this Locus 1007.  Adjacent to the wall we found numerous pot sherds scattered like debris just at the surface of the Locus 1007.  We straightened the south baulk closest the wall trying to find more layers of the wall, Locus 1008.  As with Locus 1009, we found only pot sherds.  While trying to level Locus 1007 along the wall we came upon a suspicious number of pot sherds that may have indicated a pot smash.  We decided to dig around those sherds, leaving them articulated and started focusing on the middle of the Locus1007.  We marked off a 1m square sounding for the middle of the trench and immediately came upon a pile of large rocks 10cm below the wall surface in Locus 1008.  We followed the rocks through the middle of the trench hoping to find more foundations.  We spent the rest of the afternoon following them across to the north east part of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While this was going on, Michaelle began straightening the edges of the sounding done that morning on the south east corner, and she came upon a group of large pot sherds and a lot of fired clay lodged about 5cm above the bottom of Locus 1007.   It resembles a large pot smash that Bradley thinks is typical Early Iron Age.   We found a handle and numerous large body and rim sherds stacked on each other in the layer. We began to clean this area immediately while still following the wall in the middle of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here's where it gets complicated.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While digging close to the wall in Locus 1007 we found what appeared to be another smashed pot, more delicate than the first.  We uncovered a handle, body sherds, and a small cylindrical piece artculated along the east side of the wall 5cm below the wall's surface.  Part of the crew was assigned to clean this area as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;All this time we were still trying to find the rest of our new wall.  We finally came upon some softer soil 3m east of the west wall, as well as some ash (which Aziz seems to think is wood ash) and some over fired clay.  We took soil samples of the clay (KT 1032) and ash (KT 1031) which we think were contaminated because of the plastic bags we had to put them in.  (Doh!)  We will take more samples tomorrow in aluminum foil.  We think that these materials indicate a pit of some sort so we decided to dig a sounding to the north of the "pit" to outline its size.  We found lots of large and small bone as well as more clay and ash.  These materials do not extend all the way to the north wall they seem to stop very close to where we originally found them.  We named the fill that we found the ash/bone/clay in as Locus 1010.  When we dig for the bottom of the pit tomorrow we will give the pit itself a locus of its own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We spent the rest of the time cleaning and looking worried because we hadn't taken any measurements due to the large number of finds.  We will compensate for that tomorrow morning.    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/25/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began the day by making a conserted effort to keep up with our notebook. We took bottom elevation on all loci. Then we remeasured the debris of stones/pottery and the west pot smash.We started by digging in the north west area of Locus1007 trying to follow the debris. When we discovered many small stones and some pottery in this area we dug further towards the west baulk and came upon some very soft soil that had no rocks within it. We thought we might have another pit and started a new  KT#1042 for pottery and KT# 1043 for bone.  About .5 m out from the north baulk we found some mudbrick debris so we isolated that area for futher investigation. We changed the locus along the East baulk to Locus1011 ( at this point JPP felt very tired ) JPP had so far been working on the heap of pot sherds in locus 1011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drew came by and helped us prepare the trench for photos, after the photos were taken, we lowered Locus1007 (Easten edge)  5 cm, to search for more of the rocky debris or cobblestone floor. One of the workmen found the time teach us a little Turkish, especially the words small and large.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We continued the search for debris from the west baulk towards the SE-corner. Aziz, while digging, came upon a floor in the NW corner of the 1007-area, and the search began to find more of this floor, we began tracing this (in small chunks) all over Locus1007.  We also found another concentration of pot sherds at the Southern part of Locus 1007 which we half heartedly cleaned because we found it so late in the day.  Bradley-bay came by to tell us that he thought that the pottery and rock debris in Locus 1007 may have occured before the wall in Locus 1008 was built.  This makes sense considering that after we cleaned the wall thoroughly we thought the debris continued under the wall as opposed to being debris from the wall itself.  We decided that our next step would be to thoroughly map and draw the trench as it stood as well as trying to find where the debris ended in the trench.  We want to lift the rocks from the wall and the floor as soon as possible so that maybe we can find the floor surface beneath.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/26/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began the day taking the elevations and cleaning the trench for a publiciable photo. After spraying the remains of locus 1004 to see if it was mudbrick, it turned out to be normal clay after this became clear we closed locus 1004. After hours of cleaning, our most esteemed leader informed us, that we could not take the (damn-) photo. We covered L.1004 with grain sacks and more dirt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then we leveled locus 1011 of, by digging 5 cm on both sides of the potsmash ( now called locus 1013) we also defined locus 1012 as the potsmash in middle of locus 1007, which might be located in a pit because of the soft soil surrounding it.  (Andy doesn't think so but we cornered it off anyway). We ended the day by cleaning, taking elevations and measurments of the loci/features in the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;SUMMARY  7/21/2000 - 7/26/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We had a slow start but we are getting the hang of it now.  Our biggest problem is elevations. There are few loci with out proper elevations. Fortunatly they are the topmost levels of ...... little is ...., of course this no excuse. When wee got the notebook talk from Andyour workload doubled. We had to redo everything, make sure that we described all our soil with the Munsell chart.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As for the loci:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1000 - Topsoil w/scattered potsherds and bone, no lithics. The pottery is a mix of EIA, IA and possible Hellenistic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1001 - Most likely a continuation of the topsoil. Scattered bones and pottery dating mostly to EIA &amp;amp; IA. One striking piece of pottery, was a pale colored sherd with red paint, the date of this peice is still not clear. We found a few cobbles "floating" in the soil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1002=L.1003 - We were so anxious to find something that we haked without taking elevations, soil coloration and such things. We changed locus from L.1001 to L.1002, because the soil seemed harder packed. Then while digging L.1002, we thought we saw a change in soil color, so we changed locus to L.1003. Now we know that L.1002=L.1003, and then we leveled them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pottery was a lot IA stuff, with a nipple base among the finds from L.1002 and some Late/Hellenistic stuff in L.1003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the SW corner of L.1003 we found some cobbles running from the south baulk towards the west baulk of the trench. When we realized this was a cobblestone foundation, we changed loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L.1004 - This is the fill east of the wall above the level of the of the cobbles. We had so much pottery scattered around this locus , that we had to give it 2 KT#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L.1005 - This is the fill above the wall foundation. Lots pottery and bone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L.1006 - This locus is the fill west of the wall foundation, surprizing few finds compared to L.1005 and L.1004. Among the few finds was one peice of EIA painted ware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1007 - This is the fill that started at the level of the Wall foundation (L.1008) and continiued down wards from there. We quickly came upon a more compactly packed layer of pottery, silt and stones (collaps?), we then tried to follow this collaps, making it the bottom of L.1007 (and the top of a furture locus), we then continued the locus beyond the collaps debris, the finds from this continuation got its own KT#s. Just outside the debris we uncovered what could be a pit (L.1010)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1008 - The foundation wall, one course of cobblestones, in 3-4 rows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1009 - A sounding made at the bottom of L. 1006, the idea being that we would be able to get more detailed strata. info.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1010 - A possible pit, but when we got around to excavating it was only a thin layer of soft dirt covering a hard packed soil. Then we closed the locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1011 - We changed to this locus because when we began to dig in this area, we hit very hard silt, containing many potsherds (what later became L. 1013) The soil produced many potsherds and a few lithics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L. 1012 - This could be a bottom of a pit we missed in an earlier layer. It contained a lot of potsherds and basalt stones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L 1013 - This is the potsmash with in L.1011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/28/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began the day with cleaning the trench for our first Plan photo, this operation took the whole morning. After Breakfirst it became clear that Drew was not ready to take the plan photo yet. We then decided, together with Andi &amp;amp; Bradley, that we should start another trench next to B1, primerily this trench should trace L. 1008. So we spent the rest of the day laying out the new square. The special thing about these two, was(is) that they shared a .5m wide baulk. We only opened B3 as a half trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/29/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Damn Diabetes, Jakob was not able to be at the dig today. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After a long talk to Andi last nigth, about the (pittyful) state of our notebook...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After clearing the the trench for yet another final photo, Michaelle spent the rest of the day redoing the notebook, Munselling ect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We did not dig anything today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/30/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A lot happened today. Jakob came back and we began taking up the pottery from L.1014 (KT# 1053,1057,1072) along with a lot of other finds (KT#1054-1056,1058-1068, 1071,1073-1075). Among this were 10 finds of basalt tools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also decided that the baulk between trench B1 and B3 should be excaveted, at least down to the foundation wall. To avoid spill of soil in to Loci (3001 and 1014) we were going to take soil samples from and sift later. We decided, with advice from Andi, to make small buffer zones/miniature baulks, 10cm wide, that later would be taken down as well. The Northern part, where we wanted to protect L.1014, became Locus 1016 and the southern part, protecting 3001, became Locus1015. Apart from working on the baulk-loci, we also sifted the dirt from L.1014, looking for artifacts. And with great success, many small potsherds and bones. After this we took soil samples.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In L.1016 we did find a continuation of the cobble foundation wall, found in L.1008 and L.3002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the end of the day, we hadn't been able to complete the digging in the baulk. But this happen tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7/31/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today was tough in Trench B1. We opened 5 new loci and used over 30 KT# to hold th finds. We began the day by lifting all the debris from L.1013, the potsmash by the East baulk. Consisted of nummerous large potsherds and a few animal bones, There wasn't any soil to sift, and very little for the soil sample. While L. 1013 was taken away, work was continued on the rest of the west baulk in L.1015 &amp;amp; L.1016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jakob was told by Bradley, that the burial had to go today, so he spent all his time working on L.1015, where we found the burial/pit, which became another locus L.1019. In the north end of the West baulk, where the large cobbles were situated we finished excavating.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now we were able to see the entire wall foundation, which seems to be sloping sligthly upwards. After this we cleaned the entire series of cobbles for a photo. After this we opened a small locus (L.1020) on the East side of the baulk, by cutting through L.1016, to the level of L.1014-L.1017. This was done to study the strata under the foundation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L.1014-L.1017:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yesterday we closed L.1014, the debris east of L.1008. Today we opened L.1017 as a surface/floor locus of the debris and began systematically looking for a floor layer. We began articulating some soft spots around the floor, which migth be other floor levels. Along the border of the debris we came upon some unusual soft dirt, thinking it could be a pit we gave it L.1018, just in case. Instead of one pti we found numerous small animal (mouse?) holes/tunnels, that went very deep below the hard surface, this was disapointing to say the least.We left the mice to their own doings and continued digging L.1017 in hope of finding another floor level. We started in the southern end, going 5 cm down, seeing no surface we continued going another10cm, here we hit a hard surface, near L.1008. Tracining that, we moved to the middle of L.1017, Just after digging 10cm we discovered a great deal of burnt clay and black burn marks, 2-3cm beloow the surface. The abundance of burnt clay and burn marks surgest there was an oven sitting dirrectly on the floor. We also found several flint flakes (some of them had a pinkish tone, sugesting exposure to high temperatures) Aziz's theory that these stone flakes were used to cut straws in the fields. We diecided to skip the oven surface for the fine ? and concentraded on the rest of the floor. Very closeto the suface (2-3cm) we found a hard floor, spreading to the rest of L.1017 revealing ever more debris such as large potsherds and pebblesas well as cobbles fill from the previous level. While leveling L.1017 we ? potsherds from L.1012 at the soutern end of the trench. We bagged all the of the pottery, a few bones and all the (very heavy basalt) small finds, and saved the rest of the dirt as a soil sample. Our trench looks rather barren now, with only the wall and a few scattered cobbles lying about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/1/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We opened the by looking at the trench in dismay. What were we to do? We have a hole lot of rubble and some floors, which seem to be endless, but contain nothing useful. We cleaned L.1017 for a last photo of the surface, before we could chop further. While this was going on we named everything East of L.1008 and L.1017 (L. 1023) for L.1021. We started digging at the western most point, where L.1008 and L.1021 meet, digging from there towards the west baulk, turning north when we reached the western baulk. We did not find another floor/surface10 cm down. Up on reaching the North baulk, we did find a pit. Which contained vastly looser soil, so decided to define its edges rigth away, hoping that it is not animal holes again, but we found some bone spilters, scaring the living daylights out of us (Did we accidently ploug through another deader?) Instead when we defined the pit L.1022 we found to be 30cm deeb, all dirt was sifted and there were taken samples of it. At the bottom we found another pile of thrash (potsherds and bones), this was left there. As there were more "important" (can't remember why?) work to do... We made sure that in L.1021 we sifted 1:5 buckets of dirt, because we didn't want to loose all the important small finds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we began to dig the bottom of L.1017/the top of L.1023 we sifted all the dirt (WE DO NOT LIKE SIFTING, it's boring). Ofcourse we ende up finding something cool 1/2 hour before we should leave. As Aziz was cleaning L.1023 (sweeping) he found a nice little stone bowl, just a few cm below the surface. We noted its possition, but left it standing, because it could be standing on a surface, which we hadn't uncovered. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/2/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The morning began with our usual elevation argument. (What locus is that? ect. ect.) We began to level L.1023, chopping about 5 cm through the middle around the rocks on the North baulk.We were trying to find out what kind layers  there were bellow the floor (more floors?) We began to bring up more the the overfired clay and ash. We came upon some small circles of ash surrounded by a ring of overfired clay. As opposed to the usual sporadic occurance of the material near the rocks. We took a carbon sampleof ash and charcoal and conferred with Bradley on what the circles migth be. He said that they were the bottom of destroyed oven. We then articulated those areas of burnt ash and leveled the rest of L.1023. We still were sifting every peie of dirt in L. 1023, which slowed us down considerably. While working on L.1023 we also finished articulating the middle part of the foundation in L.1016, so we could get the last photo.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are dying to chop up the foundation in L.1008, it's been around long enough. We also removed L.1006, so only L.1009 is the only locus at the west side of the foundation, to find the rest of the strata. We found the same mix of stuff, as we last itm we dug in this part of the trench (nothing), but a few sherds. The debris doesn't seem to continue on the west side of the foundation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Back to L.1023, we are not sure what's going on. We found another group of potsherds, on the western most point, which we atticulated, thinking it migth lie on a new floor/surface. That is yet to decided. ???? 5 cm below the surface of the rock group by the north baulk, there doesn't seem to be anything burnt clay and ash under the stones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;About L.1020:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We opened a sounding at the east side of L.1016 in the baulk that separates B1 from B3 and called it L.1020, because it representates the material below the wall surface. We found a few large cobbles and a potsherd laying flat. This is probably tumble.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/5/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Started the day with a new man in the trench, Michaelle had been rotated out, and now I have Phil to deal with... The first thing I did was to lable the semi-circle of stones along the North baulk L. 1024, this should have been done days ago.........&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then we had one of the workmen level L.1023, while we measured in the part of L.1008, we were going to cut away, to do further study of the strata. Especially the relations between the foundation and the floor layers. This cut was labled L.1025.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After breakfirst Jakob had stomach-cramps and had to retreat from the site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The work in B3 was continued by Aziz, after which he helped in cleaning L.1023, while Phil excavated L.1025, and leveled it with L.1021. Taner Re-cleaned L. 1022, which had been filled with dust during the 8/3, storm. At this point Aziz made fun of Phils Turkish skills.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While scraping down L.1023, we came upon a pit in the NW corner of the trench. The soil is very dark and ashy, and very soft. The whole ting was cleared, leaving a pit with a sloping bottom of a hard paked soil. In the pit was found a small cylinder seal. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/6/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today I was given the complete command over this trench and its two workmen Aziz and Taner, unfortunatly I had to give Ali to another trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Started the day by taking elevations. After which decided  to close L.1024, by removing the stones. There by opening a new L.1029, which is the dirt between the stones and the bottom level of L.1023. Found some pottery with this soil (KT# 1139).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then had 2 new loci created, both with objective to find the"floors" as seen in the Loci L.1022 and L.1026, which I closed at the same time. Then had the workmen dig the 20 cm it would take.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Soon discovered that there were no floors/surface, and the color difference between the two parts of the trench still is there. The 2  loci were L.1027, which is below L.1023, and L.1028, which is below L.1021.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Iam not finding anything..........Andi calls it a middle phase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The rest of day was spent on leveling the trench....... which will take a couple of days.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/7/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Due to total misunderstanding of notebook/dayplan system, I spent the morning remasuring the trench. While Aziz and Taner continued to work with leveling the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After breakfirst I went back to Bismil and started redoing/retyping the notebook.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/8/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Still typing, miss my trench, the sun, the dust, the tepe...................&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Went "MWHAHAHHAHAHHAHAHHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAH" while typing, I am no longer depressed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/12/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Around 11 o'clock we began work at trench B1 againg. We started to level off L1027 and L1028. During which I removed the two potsmashes from L1027, KT#1155 &amp;amp;1156. Then the baulks were straightned and the trench was sweeped. We are still finding oven pieces in L1027.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/13/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started the day by removing the sourthern section of L1008,  this was done by dividing the soil into layers and loci that resembled the loci on the eastern side og the wall, so L1030 = (some of) L1007, L1021=L1031 and L1028=L1032, L1025 was closed and the soil beneath it was part of L1032. The following Loci was opened and closed in the process L1030, L1031 and L1032, and I closed L1025.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I then extended L1028 to cover the area of the southern section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Have begun to dig L1028 another, seem to have hit an area of some ashy stuff, will dig more carefull and scrape afterwards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jeg foeler mig noget traet efter gaarsdagens solskin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Removed the cobbles from the northern section of L1008, and there by closing it, used the same procedure as used in southern section, opening and closing loci L1033, L1034 and L1035, decided to extend L1027 under L1035.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this we were sweating a lot, because it was VERY HOT and a bit humid. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then closed L1009 and opening L1036 under it, removed the dirt and extended L1028 under L1036, there by closing L1036. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this we cleaned/sweeped the trench, in doing so we discovered a posible pit and a potsmash in L1027, along the north baulk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/14/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Started the day by digging the pit (discovered yesterday), as L1037 and took a soil sample, in doing so I discovered that it was a thin layer of dust................I then stopped the paperwork on L1037, and cancelled that locus, so I could use the number later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this we dug 10 cm in L1028, while Djengis articulated the potsmash in L1027, finding that the most of the pot was in the baulk, and will be completly removed at a later date.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While scraping around the potsmash, we uncovered a "big-ass" sherd, KT 1188.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I am beginning to believe that the 2 loci I have are very similar and maybe equal, therefore we began to level the whole trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we were ploughing through the soil of L1027 we turned up, 2 very preserved pots. One a small nipplebased cup, the other a some what coarse piece of kitchen ware (?).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we were cleaning for photo of the two pots, we uncovered a rectangular pit in the NW corner of L1027, naming it L1037 (due to lack of locus sheets.......must remember!) After cleaning, Bradley came by and outlined several pits in the trench, and advising me to close L1027 and L1028, which I then did. I will assign new loci tomorrow. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8/15/2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Started the day by assigning new loci for the entire trench (see day plan #17).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L1039 is a small pit in the eastern part of the trench, much of the soil seem to be ashy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L1038 is a large pit dominating the south western corner of the trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L1040 is the remaining soil from L1027, located between L1039&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;and the East baulk. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The rest of the trench was labled L1041 and L1042. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then we began sifting the remaning material from L1037, plus taking soil samples from it, soon after this it seemed that we reached the bottom of the pit, the soil looked like the soil of L1042 (anot. In doing so I took final elevations and closed L1037.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then I had the baulks straigthened. (Damn I have a headache, can't consentrate) Began to dig L1040, bringing it to the level of L1042 and then closing it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then I turned to L1039, and began to dig it, took 5 bags of soil samples. We found potsherds from 1 or 2 large pots in the pit, plus a lot of "cÃ¶b", Djengis was a bit too overzealous with "Bessie" and cut the walls of the bit so the last of the pottery bags is probably mixed goods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this we began more well coordinated work on the large pit in South west corner, L1038, we sifted 7 buckets of dirt out of 20 buckets, and took 6 (medium) bags of soil samples. The L1038 pit seems to be softest and deepest in the Eastern end. As I was scraping through that area of the locus, I found a single stone bead.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this we closed for the day, of corse we sweeped the entire area.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench Summary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;for B1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench B1 was opened on the 7/21, it was marked off as a 5x5 m square, where the active field was 4x4 m, leaving the rest for the baulk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The topsoil was named L1000, which we excavated at once, it was only a few cm's deep, before we changed locus to L1001, because of a change in soil coloration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Seeing that we were finding nothing, except a sligth colorchange, we split the trench into two Loci, L1002 and L1003, after digging we saw that there was no change in the soil color, and we made them equal, while cotinuating digging L1003, we turned up an aligment of rocks, we immidiatly changed loci to L1004, which was the fill on the NE side of it. L1005, being the soil on top of the wall, that later was named L1008. L1006 being the fill on the west side of the wall. After leveling the trench, we changed loci again to L1007, being the soil below the wall L1008, on the other side of the wall L1009, a small triangular locus, like L1006, which it was located below.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The next couple of days we focused on L1007, excavating in the area, we found a layer of debris, this made us change loci to L1014, which became the debris, this area of debris was located in the North-western part of the trench. Along the East trench we uncovered a high consentration of potsherds, a so called "potsmash", we then renamed that part of the trench L1011, to catch the entire potsmash, right west of this potsmash, we thought we had a pit, L1010, which turned out to be nothing. Later, having defined the potsmash in L1011, we decided to give it its own locus, L1013. The same day we had uncovered another potsmash, naming it L1012&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: B-1-2000-08-015-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/ACDA9FCB-9FC4-423F-BF6E-E6B7E278B3BD</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+B-1-2000-08-015-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FACDA9FCB-9FC4-423F-BF6E-E6B7E278B3BD</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830582</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812856</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/ACDA9FCB-9FC4-423F-BF6E-E6B7E278B3BD">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 1</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>ACDA9FCB-9FC4-423F-BF6E-E6B7E278B3BD</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:38:14-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:38:14</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
