<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="B908AAA6-85EA-4CBB-49D6-92D846DE3F40" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>A-2-2002-Summary</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">FC96A49E-FE12-488B-4EFF-02D4E147B885</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/FC96A49E-FE12-488B-4EFF-02D4E147B885">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>FC96A49E-FE12-488B-4EFF-02D4E147B885</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59">
              <oc:name>Area A</oc:name>
              <oc:id>F40478A6-1844-4650-2080-905040836D59</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:A-2-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Final Trench Summary, Year 2002 Season&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Area A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Trench 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 12, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:justify"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; Trench A2 is the top portion of the step trench on the north side of the mound. This 2m- wide by 10m-long trench is oriented according to the slope of the mound, rather than exact cardinal directions, thus A2 runs roughly SSE to NNW. Trench A2 was continued from last year by the same excavator, Eleanor Moseman, who reached the bottom of subtopsoil and had begun excavating slope wash layers above the sealed contexts she excavated this year. The south terminus of A2 for the 2002 season lies at the 5m peg, measured from the original south baulk at the 0m peg. The north terminus of A2 is co-equal with the south baulk for Trench A8 (roughly at the 15m peg). The step trench was formerly named A2 from the 0m peg to the 25m peg; this year the step trench was divided into 5 parts: from 0m to 5m remains A2 but was closed due to dangerously high baulks; from 5m to 15m also remained A2 (active this season); from 15m to 25m became A8 (excavated by Ilya); from 25m to 32m became A9 (excavated by Michaelle); and a 2m x 2m sounding called A10 was dug at the northern terminus of the step trench (dug by Rob). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench A2 ended 2001 field season with Locus 2111 and began the 2002 season with Locus 2112. The 2002 season ended with Locus 2146. When A2 was begun this year, it was approximately 2m deep, measured from the top of the west baulk to the base of the trench at the 5m peg. When the 2002 season ended, the trench was approximately 5m deep at the 5m peg. The goal for A2 this season was to "flatten" the step from the 5m peg to the 15m peg, creating one continuous step; by the end of the season A2 was "flattened" up to the 12m peg, leaving two small steps of 1.5m length each (these contained loci 2121, 2122, and 2123 which were not excavated this season). The purpose for digging A2 was to produce sealed loci for stratigraphic sequencing of the mound. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A2 in a nutshell: at the end of the 2001 field season we had not figured out what the never-ending ash layers between the 5m and 7m pegs were. This season we discovered that these ash layers are slope wash on top of a massive mudbrick wall with a stone foundation. Also, the area between the 8-9m pegs seemed to be a surface at the end of the 2001 season. This year, we confirmed that indeed from roughly the 8m peg to the 10m peg lies a series of surfaces associated with the massive mudbrick wall. We did not dig north of the 12m peg this season. I will discuss the excavation of A2 in two parts: first the massive wall and second the series of surfaces north of the wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Massive Wall&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began slowly, using big picks and small picks to push down the fill below last year’s ash lenses (these ash lines are preserved clearly in the east baulk). We peeled off L2114 as fill from the 5m peg to the 7m peg and continued pushing down there with a big pick. In L2114, we encountered patches of large (25x30cm), seemingly unorganized mudbricks in plan-view. We continued digging with a big pick, expecting to read the baulks to determine what these patches of mudbricks compose. Simultaneously we peeled off L2113 and L2115 at the 7-8m pegs as fill and found the top of two mudbrick bands, L2126 and L2125. We peeled back with small picks at the south edge of 2126, looking for the base of the band, expecting to find courses of a wall. We encountered another mudbrick band with alternating green and red bricks south of 2126; this band later became L2132. We cut a 1m wide section with a big pick (dug as 2114) into the east end of 2132 to identify the structure; in this eastern half corresponding to 2132 we came down on a white impression of a reed mat (L2130) running into the south edge of 2126 and the east baulk. This reed mat was identical to the reed mats that came up in A8 and Area C this season. There were very few sherds and only bone associated with an animal burrow in the east baulk that came out of the soil above 2130-reed mat. Thus I decided that the reed mat was not an occupational surface. We continued pushing down L2114 as "fill" looking for the foundations of the three wall sections 2132, 2126, and 2125. We also scraped off a layer of crumbly fill (as L2127) from the top of a layer of harder mudbrick (later named 2129) that is the western continuation of mudbrick wall 2126. This crumbly fill layer (2127) appears to be part of a long band of crumbly, clay filled "trash" that is preserved in the west baulk all the way to the south baulk. We did not see this band during excavation of 2114, until we could view it in section. This band of crumbly clay "trash" marks a transition between undifferentiated mudbrick collapse in 2114 above the clay band and clear brick bands in 2114 below the clay band. Because we could never find organized brick bands in plan as we excavated 2114 south of 2132, we cut into this component of the wall system. Once we interpreted the mudbrick bands of 2114 as a wall structure, and once we found the reed mat (2130) in the eastern half of 2114, we switched to L2131 to excavate the area of mudbrick bands south of 2132. Still, in L2131, we could never find more than 3 or 4 contiguous, neatly organized bricks in plan, and continued to dig with a big pick looking for the base of wall 2126/2132 on the south side. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally while digging 2131 one half at a time with a big pick we came down onto the tops of large cobblestones at the west baulk, south of 2132. We called these cobbles L2139 and articulated them, expecting that they served as the foundations for the wall system we had been excavating. We changed locus to 2140 at the south edge of the cobbles-2139 and pressed down 2140, only to discover a second white impression of a reed mat (L2141) 1.3m below and to the west of reed mat 2130. Finding reed mat 2141 confirmed that these reed mats were used as structural components for building mudbrick walls, and were indeed not occupational surfaces. This hypothesis is consistent with the reed mat and mudbrick relationship(s) in A8. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While digging the west half of 2131, we identified a white line running east-west through the mudbrick area near the south baulk. As we pressed down 2131, we saw in the west baulk and in the section on the east half of 2131 that the white line migrated southwards, creating a diagonal line in the baulk and section. Before removing the eastern half of 2131, I excavated brick layers above the clear top terminus of this white line and then cut away the narrow band of soil between the white line and the south baulk to get a section on the line. I suspected that this line might be a reed mat lying vertically between two components of the mudbrick wall. Seen in section this white line turned out to be plaster instead of reed mat. Having answered this question, we pushed down L2131-east to the level of the cobble foundation L2139. We saw that the wall founded on 2139 is oriented east-west. We pushed down south of the foundation locus, removing the reed mat L2141 in the process, in order to find the base of the foundation courses. In sum, we found 3 courses of cobbles on the south side of L2139. While pressing down this area of 2140 (mudbrick layers), through 2141 (reed mat), and into L2144 (more mudbrick layers below reed mat), we encountered a third reed mat (L2145). This reed mat remains &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;in situ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; at the close of the 2002 season. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the north side of the massive wall system, we pressed down through a series of surfaces, which I will discuss below. On the north edge of L2125-band of mudbricks, we exposed large white stones that were the northern terminus of L2139-stone foundations. We shaved back the north edge of 2125 with trowels and exposed the entire band of stones corresponding to 2139. Once the mudbrick wall on top of 2139 was "floating" in space, we tore down The Wall. We accomplished this using big picks to rip out the components of mudbrick bands locus by locus in order to preserve any potential sequencing of construction. After the entire foundation (north to south edge) was exposed and articulated, we created a measured drawing and stopped digging in the southern-most part of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Series of Surfaces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began by excavating L2118, which was an ash "hump" intruding into L2115 (these loci were left over from last year and renamed). We then pushed down this area as L2124; this locus contained a significant amount of occupational debris. Once L2124 reached the level of L2116, we shaved off L2116 with trowels and small picks. L2116 also contained lots of occupational debris. We changed locus underneath 2116 when we reached the top of an ash layer (L2128) visible in the north section of this mini-step. We trowel southwards as L2128 to remove the ashy soil, which ended well before reaching the north edge of L2125. Thus we retained L2124 as the locus adjacent to 2125. We changed locus once 2124 and 2128 were at the same elevation, in order to unify the mini-step which no longer bore distinguishing sub-divisions in plan-view. The new surface locus 2133 was a beaten earth surface with a shallow ash lens at its north edge. We peeled off this surface with small picks and trowels and exposed the underlying ash surface, L2134. We peeled off this ash layer and exposed the underlying beaten earth surface L2135, which had an odd reddish area in the south-east corner adjacent to 2125 and the east baulk. We named this reddish area L2138 and cut away L2135 with small picks. We changed locus to L2136 after digging down 10cm into L2135, because logically, I did not think a beaten earth surface should be much deeper than that and we had no freshly cut section to determine what we were digging. Thus we dug the west half of 2136 down to the level of a soil color change to red (this red soil became 2137), as seen in the north section cut. When we dug the eastern half of 2136, we exposed oven parts or mudbricks charred on one side (not quite andirons, as they would not come out intact). After we removed 2138, we saw that the east baulk preserves the very hard reddish soil of 2138 as well as a clearly defined chocolate-brown brick slumping northwards in section. Additionally, the southern edge of 2138 has neatly applied gray mortar from the base of 2138 up to the top of 2138; this mortar connects 2138 to 2125. This gray mortar does not extend a single centimeter lower than the base of 2138. I do not know what 2138 is, but it seems that it was intentionally and carefully positioned flush against the north face of the massive wall system. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To continue with the series of surfaces: we removed the east half of 2136 down to the level of the brown to red soil change and switched to L2137. This locus seems to be hard packed mudbrick-like fill resting on top of a series of stone surfaces. L2137 lies on top of the southern continuation of L2117-pebble surface (the northern part of this locus was excavated last year and left &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;in situ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;). This pebble pavement L2117 did not continue up to the wall 2125/2139. The space between the southern edge of 2117 and the massive wall was named L2142 and excavated as fill; in retrospect, this locus is equal to 2137 as fill. We peeled off the fill of 2142 (screening 1:3 on a small gauge screen) and found another pavement (L2143) constructed of small cobbles extending underneath the pebble pavement-2117. This cobble pavement 2143 runs up just short of 2139 and stops in a clean line 8cm north of the mudbrick supporting 2139 (see photos). I think that this 8cm gap is caused by the workmen undercutting the foundation too severely and means that 2143 probably abuts 2139. At this juncture we took a spider shot of the trench, showing (from south to north): L2140 (terminating in a white plaster line), 2141, 2139, 2143, 2117, 2120. We peeled off L2117 and screened 100% of the soil on a small gauge screen from that pavement as we came down on the northern continuation of 2143-cobble pavement. We then took another spider shot of the trench (nb: in the mean time we had peeled off 2141-reed mat and dug down through L2114-mudbrick layers and left reed mat L2145 exposed for the picture); this second spider shot shows (from south to north): L2145, 2139, 2143, 2120. After taking this spider shot, we peeled off L2143 cobble pavement and exposed the underlying pebble pavement L2146. This third stone pavement runs up to meet (and possibly runs underneath) the mudbrick base supporting the stones of 2139 (this joint is visible in the west baulk where the small stones of 2146 run into 2139).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;h3 dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Baulks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The south baulk preserves a record of the massive mudbrick wall. The top edge and down c. 1m was excavated last year; this area shows a mudbrick wall of alternating yellow and gray bricks in the east half. This mudbrick wall is cut by a large pit of gray-brown crumbly soil. There are amorphous bands of green clay and red mudbricky soil as well as bands of ash layers, corresponding to the ash lenses excavated last year. At the top of L2114, only mudbrick collapse is visible and then, below the area corresponding to the green clay band in the west baulk, the form/outline of the motley red, gray, pink, brown and pink brick layers in the south baulk becomes more defined. At the elevation corresponding with the top of 2139, the colors of the brick bands shift to stronger/darker red and no green bricks are used. There are traces of plaster lines preserved in the lower west corner of the south baulk. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The west baulk tells the story of the massive wall. The mudbrick collapse in the upper elevations of 2114 is visible above the green clay band. Below the green clay band, the brick bands become more distinct, and wrap around into the south baulk. The green brick bands stop below the top elevation of the foundation L2139. Beside the foundation to the south, the bricks are strictly red and brown (no green) and the diagonal plaster line dives into the south baulk. It is clear that this plaster line separates an area of mudbrick collapse that is falling northwards the massive wall, but that the bricks south of the white plaster line belong to a separate entity from the massive wall (or may be rebuild that is slumping northwards?). At the 7-8m pegs, the courses of 2132, 2129, 2125 are clearly preserved in the baulk. North of the wall, the ash layers corresponding to the series of surfaces are preserved, although they are less legible than the mudbrick wall. The cobbles and pebbles of the stone pavement series are preserved at the base of the west baulk. From the north edge of the series of surfaces, most of the west baulk is slope erosion and topsoil all the way down to the southern baulk of A8.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: A-2-2002-Summary</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/B908AAA6-85EA-4CBB-49D6-92D846DE3F40</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+A-2-2002-Summary&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FB908AAA6-85EA-4CBB-49D6-92D846DE3F40</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830724</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813314</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/B908AAA6-85EA-4CBB-49D6-92D846DE3F40">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 2</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>B908AAA6-85EA-4CBB-49D6-92D846DE3F40</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:48:37-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:48:37</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
