<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>F-13-2002-08-06-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>196BEB51-85D9-4D2B-B53E-A60D815FCCD8</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/2348228B-9020-415B-FB85-3CAC278B8A10">2348228B-9020-415B-FB85-3CAC278B8A10</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002-08-06</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="person" info="Recorded by">9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="resource" info="Previous">17195B55-934D-4A41-F12B-61188E201271</arch:docID>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">BB9FFCD6-AA38-4E8D-006D-7B4708FD4D87</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/BB9FFCD6-AA38-4E8D-006D-7B4708FD4D87">
        <oc:name>Trench 13</oc:name>
        <oc:id>BB9FFCD6-AA38-4E8D-006D-7B4708FD4D87</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E">
              <oc:name>Area F</oc:name>
              <oc:id>85B36DE2-96FC-40AF-B3FB-D35CCDE2189E</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
    <oc:diary_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/documents/17195B55-934D-4A41-F12B-61188E201271">
        <oc:name>F-13-2002-07-29-Weekly</oc:name>
        <oc:id>17195B55-934D-4A41-F12B-61188E201271</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Previous</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:diary_links>
    <oc:person_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/persons/9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F" cite="contributor">
        <oc:name/>
        <oc:id>9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>Recorded by</oc:relation>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:person_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of excavation season, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the full season's activities in each trench. This summary was the first step in building the interpretation and archaeological narrative of each trench.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:F-13-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;FINAL TRENCH SUMMARY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Area: F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Trench: 13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Aug 5-6, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;F 13 was laid out as a 10 meter by 10 meter square trench with intersects also laid at the 5 meter mark, but this year we only excavated the Eastern one meter of the trench. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The trench is near other trenches in the same area of F, to the Northeast is F7 being excavated by Katie Smith; to the East is F9 which was excavated last year by Downell Moon. A bit South and East of my trench is F1 being excavated by Chris Moon. West of F 13 are F 15, F 16, and F 17 which I also excavated this season. F 14 –one of the new trenches- is located immediately North of F 13 and is being excavated by Nergiz Nazlar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Area F is located on the lower town of Kenan Tepe on a cliff above a bend of the famed Tigris (Dicle) river near the town of Bismil in Eastern Anatolia. As the cradle of civilization, this area of Mesopotamia is rich in archaeological deposits of rich historical contexts. Our purpose in this trench and in this area has been to enlarge our understanding of activities that took place in this part of the tepe. F 13 was one of a number of trenches excavated and/or that will be excavated in an effort to locate work and/or living areas, interpret activities from the cultural remains found, and, identify the time and the spread of habitation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span class="bodyText" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;To begin, we cleared all of the thorny bushes and other vegetation from the 10x10 trench and marked off the one meter that was to be excavated. Interesting to note that the thorny bushes produce a small berry which children from nearby villages pick for some income during their summer vacation off school. Locus 1 which included the first 0.05 meters of topsoil had a beginning elevation ranging from 570.82 meters on the Northwest corner to 570.44 meters on the Southeast corner. This 0.38 meters difference in elevations within such a short distance is due not only to the natural down sloping of the area towards the Tigris River, but also to long abandoned plowing furrows. My guess is that cotton or some type of winter wheat was grown in this area of the tepe. I would also guess that the field was left fallow then later abandoned some 10 years ago. Mechanized plowing may have had a lot to do with the low quantities of pottery and other cultural remains found in this trench. A trend that I believe holds for most of the trenches in area F.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Removal of locus 1 also included the sub-topsoil layer, which was followed by a deep layer of a darker soil with a lot more organically decayed content (locus 2). When locus 3 was removed the soil used for Munselling must have came from one of the reddish soil deposits that began at about 0.60 meters because when I marked the baulk the color just didn’t look the same to me. By locus 4 we started to encounter the white pebble material characteristic of virgin soil (as observed in F 4). I found myself theorizing about the origin and purpose for the white speckled soil and whether it might have had a special purpose or reason for appearing where it does. My early theory was that anyone moving or re-depositing virgin soil from one area to another must have had a good reason for undertaking such a labor. One might wonder rather safely that there was a purpose contained in the use of this soil. One would question that if the white speckled soil is virgin soil, why was it moved, or what was it used for? One guess that arises as part of its composition is that the white chalky pebbles contained as part of it may be components in brick making or brick laying! perhaps it was used in plastering or coloring of the bricks. With that idea in mind I found myself directing excavations in those areas that exhibited the white pebbles in the hopes that they would point towards walls and/or other features. It is noteworthy to mention two kinds of white pebble. One is a hard and feels more like a pebble would. The other is more like a chalk-clay and can be turned into a powdery material easily. This latter one could have been used as a plastering medium. Both types have similar white coloration, also vary in shape, and are found in abundance in certain layers. The harder pebbles are more abundant.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After excavating the fill in locus 5, we encountered a mass of medium sized river cobbles (locus 6) followed by a surface (locus 7) on which lots of pottery was located, both of these were near the North end of the trench. Due to the small area of these loci and the lack of other contexts it was difficult to make associations or even interpolations of the certainty and usage (if any) of these two loci. We had also hoped to intercept a wall feature observed in the West section of F 9 after we cleaned it on my first day of excavating. That feature showing four courses of bricks was clearly indicated in the baulk but its direction was not so clear, our aim had been to dig down on F 13 until the wall was intercepted and then worked on its interpretation. But we either cut through it or its signature was all too difficult to identify at the time of excavation. As I have looked at the baulk in the last days of excavating, the signature of bricks is still hard to see, more visible on the East baulk of F 13 are a couple of mortar lines, and a reddish square close in line to where the bricks are located in F 9. Careful removal of the baulk between F 13 and F 9 will provide next year’s excavator with a better picture of the extent and direction of those bricks. Near the middle of the trench and next to the East baulk we followed a wall pattern that showed about a 0.20-meter wide, wall like pattern of about 0.24 meters from and almost perpendicular to the East baulk. This became locus 9. We removed that formation but no wall was evident to us. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The first really interesting feature encountered was a huge layer of ash located at about 0.90 meters in depth. This layer (locus 8) is also a feature which Dawnell Moon had to contend with in F 9. As the excavation of the trench progressed this layer extended through a large area (see final plan) with some deeper parts than others. This layer of ash seems pretty well compacted and noticeably darker than the soil next to it. This ash layer also lacks the white pebbly stuff found earlier in the excavation. This is interesting because the layer being too long to be a pit might indicate an area of refuse, yet why didn’t it become commingled with the white pebble soil? Was the ash layer deposited all too quickly through an intense fire to have avoided "contamination"? Is the ash’s provenience from a workshop or kiln setting? How large is it? It is fine and dark. Why was it deposited here? And by whom? The direction that the ash takes may help indicate that it was leaning against something like a wall or that it would have followed a road, or a natural bend or depression in the topography. The walls which perhaps we missed, may have served as a natural break or place where the ash just came to rest. If this was the case the wall idea seems like a very good possibility. If there was no wall, what concentrated it over such a large area? Until provenience and associations can be made and found for this feature more questions than answers will continue to plague us. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other features worth mentioning are the arrangement of rocks (locus 13) found while excavating the fill in locus 10. This feature exposed 4 large rocks organized in a semicircle with some smaller rocks and cobbles in the middle. It appears to have been used as a pot-stand. Unfortunately the majority of what may complete a circle is beyond the exposed wall. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In an effort to have a better look at emerging walls or features, and especially waning to look at locus 9 in section we decided to open the trench towards the West. It is hard enough to look at a section when all you have is about 0.50 meters of area to look from. The decision was to cut a 3 (North to South) by 1.50 (East to West) meters beginning two meters from the South baulk. The contents of layers similar to those on the original 1 by 9 meter trench were collected separately an can be related to each other for the following loci: 12 with 3, and 15 with 4. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This cut provided us with two important loci, both of them pits. The first one (locus 11) was a small shallow pit that was likely associated with the locus 2 level. The pit provided some bone and was quickly disposed off. There were no structures associated with it. Locus 14 is the larger pit from which we also extracted bones and pottery. All of the soil from both of these pits was sifted after collecting two 2-liter samples of soil for archaeobotany studies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pit (L14) with an almost symmetrical circumference appeared to me to have been more carefully planned than other pits, after carefully excavating down to its top (initial) level we can associate it with some of the adjoining features. First of all, it appears that the white plastered surface was surrounding the pit for at least its Eastern half. This plastering would point to a specialized function for this pit such as that of storage but many bones were recovered from it, not to mention all of the ash. Most people wouldn’t plaster a cooking pit unless its presentation was important to others, such as in an open market setting where presentation was important to others. Plaster was not located for the Western half of the pit up to this point, but it may be found one or two centimeters below the current surface L 12 or maybe even L 10. Elevations are similar between this pit the oven remains (L 20) and the remaining piece of wall (L 18). If this can be better established we may be able to make the association that would place all of these features as contemporary with each other. The function may have been –as mentioned above- that of an open market setting where edible goods were made and sold. Loci 8 and 16 the ash layers may also have a contiguous association to the pit and the other features. Obviously since the oven (L 20) appears to sit on the L 19 surface, the surface may be a continuation of the surface in which the pit (L 14) was dug into.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Next year’s excavation can strive to answer a number of the questions raised in this summary. A better definition of walls needs to be ascertained so that all of the other pieces can be better related to each other. Also in need of an answer (a difficult one until more of the trench or the adjoining areas are excavated) is the provenience of the ash. The size and usage of the pit and the oven may go a long way in also helping to answer some of the questions. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p class="body_text" awml:style="Body Text" dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;text-indent:0.5000in"&gt;&lt;span&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
   &lt;p/&gt;&#13;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: F-13-2002-08-06-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-02-28</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:contributor href="http://opencontext.org/persons/9034B710-8EC0-426F-C5D8-61E5255DF22F"/>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+F-13-2002-08-06-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.contributor=&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FC6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.8314565</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.815349</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 13</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-03-20T09:28:19-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/03/20 09:28:19</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags>
      <oc:tag type="chronological" status="public">
        <oc:name>(3,100 BCE - 2,900 BCE)</oc:name>
        <oc:chrono isDuration="true">
          <oc:time_start>-3100</oc:time_start>
          <oc:time_finish>-2900</oc:time_finish>
          <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6">
            <oc:source_name>Trench 13</oc:source_name>
            <oc:source_id>C6BD4769-30AF-40CA-C4DC-45ED33DF51C6</oc:source_id>
          </oc:metasource>
        </oc:chrono>
        <oc:tag_creator id="oc">
          <oc:creator_name>Open Context Editors</oc:creator_name>
          <oc:set_label>Default set</oc:set_label>
          <oc:set_id>Default set</oc:set_id>
          <oc:set_date>2012-03-17T12:52:56-07:00</oc:set_date>
        </oc:tag_creator>
      </oc:tag>
    </oc:user_tags>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
