<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="DC619A01-0835-4C01-FE6C-7C1A14E7CE3E" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-5-2001-08-018-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>AD72AC5D-D01B-41CE-D5D9-0F7C60E93753</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/45E9D409-EAF2-4551-988A-206ADAB882D9">45E9D409-EAF2-4551-988A-206ADAB882D9</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001-08-18</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2001</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6">ED1E972B-AF76-4E35-6CC5-6529A73BB4F6</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2001</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4">
        <oc:name>Trench 5</oc:name>
        <oc:id>5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-5-2001-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Groupings: L5015/5025/5030/5018/5020/5021--Stone Surface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	       L5034/5037/5038/5039/5047--Northern house&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	       L5028/5033/5036/5048--Pottery-lined pit assemblage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	       L5031/5008/5027/5040--Southern house&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	       L5066/5073/5065/5029--Painted pottery surface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	       L5045/5058/5060/5061/5062/5063/5064/5068/5069/5072/5074/5076--Mudbrick house&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench Summary 2001--Area D, Trench 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;BACKGROUND:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The trench is located in area D, which occupies an area about half-way down the eastern slope of the main tepe, where there is a slight bulge in the slope's profile. Trench 5 is a 5 x 10, made from the combining of S-N abutting trenches 1 and 2, which were started late last season, but likely due to the steep slope had only begun to come upon cultural material by the end of the season. Trenches 1 and 2 were dug briefly this season before the two were merged. West of trench 5 is trench 4, a 5 x 10 encompassing last season's trench 3 and also opened this season. The southern half of trench 5 and northern half of trench 4 are separated only by a baulk. The trenches are staggered such that the northern half of trench 5 and the southern half of trench 4 extend out from the abutting core:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	|________==========|      -----&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	|       D-4        |         N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	|==========|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	            |==========|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	|Slope	|       D-5        |&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	|/	|==========|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because of the grade, the eastern edge of D-4 is almost 2 meters above the eastern edge of D-5.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The hope coming into this season was that we would encounter good sealed contexts as the previous season (and early portion of this season) has cleared out the extensive layer of fill. We were not disappointed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;KEY CONTEXTS, STRATIGRAPHICALLY FROM TOP:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;1. The Wall Hiding in the Baulk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The first thing we had to do when merging trenches D-1 and D-2 was cut out the baulk between them. Low and behold, taking the baulk down carefully and stratigraphically we encountered at least three mudbrick walls, built atop each other, hidden almost completely in the baulk. None of the walls were especially well-preserved, and as the area that would have been abutting the wall on the N and S had already been dug, the loci assigned where the wall(s) was identified at different elevations (L5004, 5005, 5012, 5014) were mostly without context, until the very bottom of the feature where one of the walls (L5031) was found to have a NW-SE orientation and be associated with a surface (more about this later). Of note, there were two otherwise unattached patchy plaster areas on the north and south of the wall (D-2 L20.. and D-5 L5026, respectively) which may have been collapse from one of the walls. The walls are also important because they might be part of a buttress structure for a retaining wall allowing terracing of the slope, which appears to have taken place as some key contexts from D-4 and D-5, on preliminary examination, appear to be from the same period despite a vertical distance change of around three meters. Later, when the wall was being removed, a fragment of a pebble surface, L5049, probably the same as the one visible in the W section, was uncovered. It had an ash pit beneath, L5050. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;2. The Cobble Feature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The cobble feature was first discovered at the end of last season, but not excavated. This season it was excavated first in D-2 as L2015 and 2025 then later in D-5 as L5015 and 5025. To date, the function of the feature is undetermined. It was a series of four layered cobble surfaces (as determined by an abundance of flat-lying pot sherds) with larger stones flanking the surface on the S, E and W. The feature fades into a stone-barren area (L5021) to the N, which in turn comes into a rock jumble on its N, L5020, which may have been part of the same feature as L5025, but is close enough to the topsoil that the preservation was close to non-existent. It is also possible that L5021 is a different entity entirely. Within the cobbles features there was an abundance of tool-making cores, grind stone fragments, yet curiously no bones or small debitage. On the S, the feature is bonded to by a one row, one course mudbrick wall, L5018. The fill below the feature (L5030) was soft brown fill with, in sharp contrast, many animal bones. In the end, the feature may be a wall fragment, some sort of dump or a succession of occupational layers but the preservation of the surrounding area did not allow better analysis in context.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;3. The Pottery-lined Pits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A group of three small (mouth ~ 20 cm, best preserved was ~40 cm deep), circular, pottery-lined pits were found in various levels of preservation in the east-central portion of the trench, in order of best preservation L5036, L5033 and L5048. The three appear to be associated with a possible surface fragment, L5028, but otherwise their context is unclear save that L5048 cuts lower wall L5039, dating them after that period.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;4. The Southern Structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mudbrick wall L5031 turned out to be associated with was L5027, a packed-earth floor found when the mudbrick collapse above (L5011) started coming off in flat-bottomed chunks and some scattered flat-lying sherds. In the very south, going into the baulk, the surface had an area of ash deposits atop it, L5041. In the area near wall L5008 a sounding (L5040) was dug to confirm the surface, which it did. The surface's extent to the east was unclear, where a large pit (L5024) cut into the area abutting the S and E baulks. Otherwise, the surface was bounded by mudbrick wall L5008 on the W, L5031 on the north and in the south it continued into the baulk. Originally we thought it might be an Ubaid structure, as pieces of black on white painted pottery with sharp flares below their rims were appearing in small numbers, but it now looks as though those were coming from a large oven, L5029, which is associated with a lower surface (L5066) and may have been used as a pit in this period or otherwise caused some contamination with sherds from earlier periods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;5. The Northern Structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Below the cobble feature in the northern half of the trench, another architectural layer was quickly found, just below L5030, in surface L5034, its eastern mudbrick wall, L5039 and northern mudbrick wall L5037. It continued into the baulk in the west and became unclear moving towards the center of the trench and L5031. The surface was identified because the layer of fill above could be peeled off and produced a flat bottom when a trowel or hand pick was used. The surface was a packed earthen floor very different from the soft fill above. On the floor were flat-lying pot sherds, scattered bones, lithics and pebbles and a thin layer of sandy/silty deposits, L5038, which continue over much of the trench to the S with a slight downslope grade, and I think are actually an accumulation coming from a period of disuse/abandonment. It looks as if walls L5037 and L5039 once came to together to form the northeastern corner of the room, but neither are preserved all the way to that point, which is not surprising as the slope of the tepe would not have offered much protection in the eastern segments of the trench at this feature's level. Under the entire surface and wall L5037 was a thin, black ash layer associated with ash pit L5047.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;6. The Floor and Oven with Painted Pottery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Between the northern and southern structures and this surface was a thick layer (up to 30 cm) of fill heavy with silt and sand (L5038, 5054, 5044) which, as mentioned previously, to me indicates a period of abandonment. When we were finally to the bottom of the layer of fill (it took almost two weeks worth of very careful digging and small sounding placement to make sure we weren't missing any important features) we came upon this area of flat-lying pottery, some sherds of which were very large (up to 50 cm). Some areas of the floor had a plaster surface. In the north a fragment (apparently cut by an unexcavated pit) of a plaster-lined mudbrick wall was uncovered (L5073). The surface contained at least half a dozen of the black on white painted sherds, including some rims and could be followed to oven L5029, which it appears to be associated with, via L5055 and 5065, which also produced some painted sherds. Universally found beneath the surface was an extremely (like 1 mm) layer of gray/white ash which retained fibrous organic impressions of the material which was burnt and separates this strata from that of the mudbrick house (explained below). Some portions, particularly in the NE under L5054 of the surface remain in sealed context, as there was not time in the season to properly dig them, whereas areas in the south and southwest were removed to try and find more contexts associated with the mudbrick house as the season was coming to a close. A couple notable small finds came from L5066, including a rim sherd from a bowl constructed of ground obsidian (KT 5419) a circular stone (~ 10 cm) with a hole in the middle and notches on the outside, possibly a loom weight (KT 5420) and a spindle whorl fragment (KT 5426). Preliminary pottery readings date this structure to the 2nd millennium.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7. The Mudbrick Structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;coup de grace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; of the season was a mudbrick structure which appeared at the end of the season and most of the last week's excavations focused on. Though it looks like most of the structure can be found where it continues into the western, southern and eastern baulks, portions of two rooms reside in the southern third of the trench. The northern wall is formed by mudbrick wall L5074 and the NE-SW portion of L5045, some of which is plaster-lined. Towards the eastern baulk, wall L5045 meets the wall of hearth L5062, which produces a bulge that forms the outer wall of the structure until the eastern baulk is reached. The two rooms are separated by the SW-NE segment of wall L5045, the first portion of the structure we discovered and on the top of which a row of mudbricks can clearly be seen. The N-S wall is two bricks wide, whereas the E-W wall is two bricks wide along the western room and a single brick wide along the eastern room. Unfortunately, courses could not be seen on the walls (probably due to a use of mud-plaster) but the white plaster on the outside of the northern wall confirms their depth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The eastern room, which is also bounded by wall L5061 on the south, has a softly packed earthen floor (L5063) and an oven or hearth, apparently built directly into the NW-SE portion of wall L5045 and bulging to N to form the structure's northern wall in that segment. Grain-rich soil samples (KT 5402 and 5384) and a few carbon samples, which can hopefully tie a date to the structure, were taken from the oven. Cutting into the circle of the oven on the south and leading me to believe it is, in fact, a hearth is a lowered, circular area was found in front of the hearth, with a very thin layer of fibrous ashes at the bottom. The sunken area is also the only context within the house area that has produced a significant amount of pottery. A sounding (L5070) was dug in the NW corner of the room to confirm the surface, which it did, and attempt to find how deep the walls were founded, which seems to be about 12 cm below the surface. A strange red-painted, baked clay artifact was discovered on the surface (KT 5427 and 5445), as well as an almost completely intact finger bowl (KT 5391).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The west room, which was discovered later as oven L5029 and the upper surface significantly cut into its distinguishing walls and possibly part of its plaster floor (L5068) in the far SW, has a plaster floor (or series thereof), L5068, above a very hard (think concrete) earth floor, L5069.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the N of the building, a group of three fishnet weights (KT 5468, 5469, 5470) was uncovered at a level similar in elevation to the interior surface levels. To the west of them, a stone jumble was uncovered with some areas of ash (L5076) which may be some sort of hearth built up against the wall or which may just be unclear as all the stones have yet to be uncovered (and won't be until next season). Finally, a small, circular burnt mudbrick feature was discovered (L5072) which had some burnt cereals in its vicinity. The latter looks like some sort of oven associated with the house, but there was not time in the season to dig it fully.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Preliminary pottery reading dates this structure to the Early Bronze, and distinct from the level above. My guess is that the thin ash layer separating the two contexts is in fact a destruction layer, and the deposits may well be ash from a thatch roof of the mudbrick structure burning. Notably, the ash deposits were thicker inside the structure. The structure appears to be domestic due to the hearth, simple construction and fishnet weights found outside, but the lack of pottery is strange. Perhaps, if there was a destruction, it was caused by an invading force and the residents had warning and were able to move out most of their belongings before the destruction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;GENERAL ANALYSIS:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This season we moved through at least 4 distinct strata--the cobble surface, our only stone architecture; the northern and southern structures, which appear contemporary; the surface with the painted pottery; and the mudbrick structure. Whereas the mudbrick structure and surface with the painted pottery are separated by only a thin ash layer and are probably close in age, the silty layer between the painted pottery level and the northern and southern structures probably separates them by a greater period. The cobble surface and the northern structure didn't have much fill between them, but as the cobble structure is that last coherent stone architecture we encountered (and may have some relation to some stone architecture in D-4, indicating terracing) the relationship between it and the northern structure will hopefully provide some good data on that transition. It will be interesting to see how carbon dates and final pottery analysis turns out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another notable feature is that all the architecture encountered in the trench was on a NNW orientation, indicating the slope and/or orientation of the terracing was consistent over a long period, and should be something future excavators in this part of area D should watch out for when they come upon architecture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;NOTES ABOUT SECTIONS:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Very little can be seen in the E and N sections, the notable exceptions to this being a pebble surface dug in D1 (L10..) visible in the southern part of the eastern section, where pit L5024 can also be seen in the SE corner, and at the very bottom of which is the southern half remains of where hearth L5062 went into the section can be seen. The two exceptions in the north section are ash pit L5047 in the NW corner, and the mudbrick of wall L5037 immediately above.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The west section is the most comprehensive, showing a pebble surface (a portion of which was L5049) sealing the entire western portion of the trench. Of particular note is oven L5029, which can be seen in the SW corner, and how a surface can be followed from it to surface L5066, in some places with plaster, and below there where the plaster surfaces of the mudbrick house (L5068) can be seen immediately above the current bottom level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The southern section is most notable in that it is the only section which clearly shows the surface of the southern building, L5027, which can be seen as an ash lens (which is actually L5041, which was immediately above said surface) in approximately the middle of the section. Pit L5024 dominates the SE corner while oven L5029 dominates the SW.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;NOTES ON EXCAVATION METHODS:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Most of the work in the trench this year was done with hand picks and trowels, though occasionally the big picks came out of large areas of fill (L5044, 5054, for example) or the removal of the baulk. Articulation of surfaces and features was generally done with trowels, though hand picks were used in some cases where hard surfaces made the picks a better option as fill would evenly flake off the surface. Dental tools were occasionally used for plaster articulation and articulation of areas around artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;TO FUTURE EXCAVATORS:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Most of the architecture surrounding L5066 seems to be poorly preserved, if at all. Watch out for a mudbrick wall, either NW-SE or SW-NE as you dig through the fill of L5054, as well as the continuation of the surface. Also be on the lookout for a possible pit at the easternmost extent of wall L5073. In areas the surface is still extant, watch for the thin ash layer (sealing mudbrick house related loci) beneath or a 5-10 cm layer of packed sand, which was coming up in some more eastern portions at the end of the season and may be related to L5038.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The far south areas related to the house were mostly dug to, but no removed. Watch for the hard surface, L5069 in the west, and the softer surface, L5063 in the east. Be sure to label the areas below the surfaces as fill beneath floor and get a soil sample. Also, there probably a bit more of the hearth (L5062) to be dug out, so look for its distinctive thick charcoal areas. Once L5066-related loci have been removed in the north, watch out for architecture and features on a similar level with and contemporary to the mudbrick house.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the far NE, there may still be a little topsoil or at least heavily disturbed sub topsoil remaining above coherent architecture due to the slope, so if you lose features in that area, don't be surprised, it's probably not your fault.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-5-2001-08-018-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/DC619A01-0835-4C01-FE6C-7C1A14E7CE3E</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-5-2001-08-018-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FDC619A01-0835-4C01-FE6C-7C1A14E7CE3E</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830708</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813714</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/DC619A01-0835-4C01-FE6C-7C1A14E7CE3E">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 5</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>DC619A01-0835-4C01-FE6C-7C1A14E7CE3E</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:55:03-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:55:03</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
