<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="E6471C77-5FB0-4DD8-BD95-F354563269F6" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>C-2-2000-08-013-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>9FAA3F73-C13E-41ED-A639-41D1F3C80103</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/5B3CA943-190A-4216-C2D9-90AB47E475B0">5B3CA943-190A-4216-C2D9-90AB47E475B0</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-08-13</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>7080C9EE-10F9-43E0-0715-033E2AE4571E</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C">
              <oc:name>Area C</oc:name>
              <oc:id>48465CC5-ECB3-4101-6A78-F2118BE4323C</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:C-2-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 21, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Workers: Jenghis and Meki.   We laid out the grid for the trench and began digging to a depth of 10cm.  The soil was loose in composition with a mixed context of pottery.  We guessed that most of this pottery is Hellenistic.  At 10:30 we found a loomweight.  At 10:51 we found a chert core.  By lunch time we had two-thirds of the trench dug to a depth of 10cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 22, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	began by cleaning trench. we will continue to excavate L2000 (topsoil layer). We will open a new locus L2001 (though the soil color and texture appears to be the same), knowing that we have removed the topsoil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At 8 am we opened L2001. It appears to be the same as L2000. Looking at the stratigraphy there is a definite topsoil layer only 4 cm deep. Everything below that at our current depth of 34 cm (at the east wall baulk) appears to be one stratigraphic layer. The top of L2001 appears to be a mudslide with pockets of loose soil impinging a majority of tightly packed a majority of tightly packed soil (ie the mudslide). The loose soil might be caused by rodent burrowing, but more likely is caused by tree roots. Just below the surface of the trench one can see 6 or 7 small tree stumps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At 47 cm below the surface, we have uncovered a small rock alignment made up of 2 large stones. White pebbles of plaster (perhaps) are found in the immediate area (about 0.5 meter radius).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began digging L2002 at 10:25. L2002 appears to be the same as 2001, except for a rock alignment which is made up of 2 river stones about 20 cm in diameter at our present height. These lie atop packed dirt. We have yet to see the extent of this wall by the time we closed for the day. We will start tomorrow by excavating around the wall to find it’s extent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 23, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by cleaning the trench. We plan to continue excavating L2001 which appears to be a packed mudslide layer. We will also continue excavation of L2002 which we believe contains a wall. One change we plan to make is to contract L2002 so that it contains just the area where we believe the wall is. After digging down about 4 cm in L2001 a scatter of animal bones was found in the southwest corner of the trench. We believe this to be a pit and have designated it L2003. The pit is characterized by loose and darker soil than the surrounding soil. The bones are associated with a small root system in the far southwest corner of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After excavating L2001 about 10 cm below L2002 (rock alignment and packed soil) we uncovered a fairly symmetrical "platform" or mudbrick fall. After consultation with Bradley we divided the trench on its north/south axis. We closed L2001 and opened L2004 and L2005 which lie directly beneath L2001. L2004 is the western portion of the trench and L2005 is the eastern portion. We did this so as to not contaminate the "mudbrick fall" with any other artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After a section was taken from L2002 (called L2006) Bradley sprayed the baulks, to see any existing mudbrick lines. Nothing definite was found. Our strategy for tomorrow will be to cut the top off of L2002 in order to determine the nature of this deposition. We will also lower L2005 by 10-15 cm to further expose L2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 24,  2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by excavating the animal bone deposit (L2003).  Our plan is to slice the top off our "mudbrick fall" (L2002) to determine its nature, lower L2005 by 10-15 cm to further expose the mudbrick fall, and then continue excavation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	when we arrived at the site we noticed that some long bones that were protruding from the L2003 yesterday were removed today by looters.	&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After consulting with Andy we concluded that we had two mudbricks and a possible eroded fallen mud wall.  We proceeded to section the trench into quadrants.  The mud platform would be leveled to the same depth as L2005 with the exception of the two mud bricks and a rock between them- L2002.  We closed 2003 and opened the area beneath it as L2007.  L2007 appears to be a layer of fill with some animal bones sticking out.  We believe it is the same as L2004.  We will dig L2007 sown another 10-15 cm.  The eastern half of the trench will be divided into two halves- a north and a south.  After taking down L2007  we will proceed to lower L2008- the southeast corner- by 10-15 cm.  Hopefully this will illuminate our situation with our mud brick wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We divided the trench into quadrants and changed loci.  At 12pm we are working with 4 loci(2007, 2008, 2009, 2010) and our mudbricks (2002).  We split the trench into quads in order to have greater horizontal control, over this seemingly large fill area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In L2007 we have uncovered the top of a possible potsmash.  We will continue to lower these loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	As we investigate the section on the east side, we can see some indication of a possible mudbrick construction (some thin red lines separated by a thin white line) but this is very uncertain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 25, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today we will need to get elevations for L2010.  We will then proceed to excavate the quadrants beginning with L2009 then going on to L2010.  The depths of the east and west halves of the trench will be staggered into a steplike configuration with loci 2007 and 2009 being deeper than loci 2008 and 2010.  By doing this we hope to determine if the mudbricks we have unearthed are at the top of a wall and by going deeper we can uncover it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After consulting with Bradley we decided to level L2010 to the same depth as L2008.  Then we will take a section of L2002 to see if the fallen mudbrick wall is more apparent.  After that we will consult with Bradley again.  In L2002 there are a few clumps of pottery, a couple of which look articulated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After consulting Andy we decided that we definitely had a three tier mud brick wall, but we weren't sure where it went.  We decided to take L2009 down by 20cm because it seemed fairly empty .  Though we are keeping our eyes open for pits.  We will trowel down the edges of L2008 and L2010 as well as the bottom in the hopes of better defining our mudbrick will.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After going down on L2009 we came across a deposit of ash- an oven.  To define the area of the oven we took out a smashed pot in L2007 and renamed it L2011.  We will now go sown on L2007 to help define the oven.  We continue to level and trowel L2008 and L2010 to define the limits of our mudbrick wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 26, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We will begin today by taking elevations of all the presently existing loci.  We will then continue to level and trowel L2008 and L2010 in the hope of defining the course of our mudbrick wall.  We will also clean up L2007 and L2009 in order to better define the area of our oven.  Then we will probably go further down on L2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After consulting with Bradley we noticed that we had at least three mud brick walls in our trench.  We are still trying to define where the wall in L2008 goes, but the walls in L2007 and L2010 are fairly clear.  Our hearth turned out to be three hearths.  We believe it is a migrating hearth where one was built and then it gets moved around for one reason or another.   We are currently trying to determine the depths of these hearths.  The hearths become opened up as a new locus- L2012.  We came to the bottom of L2011 and closed that locus.  A wall is now becoming apparent in L2009.  This along with a stone wall in L2012.  Also in L2012 we have uncovered a small ceramic piece which looks to me like an open chicken beak.  This is probably the first true small find of the dig.  We took measurements and diagrammed the walls and hearths in our day plan, page 6.  Tomorrow we have the day off, but the day after that we will probably come down around the hearths and the walls.  All in all it was a good day of excavation and it is too bad that Chuck wasn't present for it.  Most important, our small find and plethora of mudbrick walls really shows up our archrival trench, those B2 bastards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;28 July 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today we will excavate the hearth (l2012) and our strategy will be to further define our mudbrick walls.  We are as yet uncertain as to the nature of the south side of the trench because no definite structural lines can be discerned, but this looks to be the same texture as our definite mud bricks in the north side.  Therefore we think it is mudbrick, but we do not know if it is a collapsed wall or a more definite configuration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After consulting with Bradley we decided to take a section from L2008 and opened it as L2013.  The purpose of this was to determine if we had another mudbrick wall or just collapse.  Sure enough we began to see a wall from this section.  we finally closed L2002, its purpose having been served to locate mudbrick.  We leveled our migrating hearth L2012 and observed that the pit had been covered with "slup"- eroded mudbrick wash.  In fact the hearth has major sluppage action.  Not surprising we were the only trench with sluppage action.  All the loser trenches had no sluppage.  Below the slup was more ash layer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In order to better define our mudbrick walls we decided to come down 10cm on the fill between our walls which we opened as loci L2014 in the north and L2016 in the south.  The fill will be opened as L2015. The fill between L2016 and the southside of the trench becomes L2017.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	By closing time we decided to combine L2007 and L2009 into a new locus L2018.  We also decided to combine L2008 and L2010 into one locus L2019.  We did this because they appear to be the same and we wanted to simplify our loci.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In conclusion we once again proved that C2 is where it is at.  Our screaming chicken and plethora of mudbrick walls shows that we are badasses.  Our asses our so bad it puts every other trench to shame,  especially those Nazi bastards in area B.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;29 July 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today we will continue to clear off the mud brick erosion (L2018) from the top of the migrating  hearth (L2012). We will then remove the remainder of L2012. Meanwhile we will also excavate L2019 starting at the rock lense (L2020) in the southeast corner, exposing it to see if it is the base of our mudbrick debris in that location. Meki will excavate L2019 close to the mudbrick wall on the north side of the trench (L2014).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	By 11:35 am we have dug L2019 about 15 cm deeper, L2015 10 cm deeper, L2012 (ash pit/migrating hearth) we have been articulating the edges further, which surprisingly have run underneath L2016 (mudbrick wall, SW corner). This could be due to an animal burrow found nearby (about 10 cm to the west of the ash layer). Brian has been working in the SE corner articulating a rock-bone-pottery (L2020) which indicates a new level of deposition. We have also exposed a pit which is mostly located in the section, but extends 32 cm from the south section. Below it's ash fill is a layer of small stones, perhaps lining the bottom or thrown into it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The fill to the northwest side of L2014 (mudbrick wall) has been designated L2021. About 10 cm down we found a stone alignment with a large corrugated potsherd. To the east of this locus, Andy suggests that another wall exists (see drawing):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In L2019 after scraping it flat Andy found some distinctively red soil. We will give this a new locus (L2025) and work around it for the time being. Andy also thought he saw possible mudbrick lines bisecting L2018 and L2019. Tomorrow we shall investigate these possible mudbricks and plan our strategy accordingly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In summation, we have once again proved that the C2 Screamin' Chickens have the best trench of the entire tepe.  Our mighty walls, numerous pits, and complex loci just make everyone else look bad, especially the simplistic, don't know how to take out a disk or shut the door, uncircumcised Philistine sons of bitches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;30 July 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Our strategy for today will be (1) to determine the depth of L2014, (2) to excavate and articulate the new mudbrick walls that run from north to south (3), to continue to find the margins of the pit L2012 (4), to articulate the rock scatter on the east side of the trench L2020 (5), to finish removing the pit L2022 and close that locus (6), to pedestal the stones in L2021 to see if they are associated with those in L2018.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Because of the large stones and pottery located in L2021 and the fact that they were floating suggests that they rested atop a surface and were unrelated to the stones in L2018. We will now change the locus to L2024 to be a surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The depth of L2014 is still undetermined at this time. It is at least 2 maybe 3 courses high. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;31 July 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began the day by getting photos of L2020 and plan shots of some of our walls. We took out the pottery and stone debris from L2020 and closed that locus. Below it we opened L2026, a fill layer composed of a very hard mudbrick debris. We also leveled L2019. While cleaning up L2026 we came to a softer level which we decided to open as a pit L2027.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At about ten to eight am we closed up L2013. Later while digging in L2026 we came upon another pit which was quite deep. We believe it is another oven, perhaps destroyed or an ash pit associated with a food preparation area. L2022 looks like a kiln because of all the hard-packed stone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	To make our trench more simplified, we consolidated L2019 and L2026 in to a new locus L2029. We did not see a difference between these two loci, thus we combined them. We ended the day by digging 10 cm into L2029. We also articulated our north/south mudbrick wall (L2023) down about 10 cm. The southwest corner of our trench is becoming quite interesting. On the east section is an ash pit of a relatively large and deep size - filled with ashy soil and charred bone. to the immediate southwest of this pit is what we believe to be the kiln L2022. A great deal of diagnostic pottery was found in the structure. It's base is a very hard pack of fired clay and stone. That will have to stay in our section as pulling it out will leave a large hole there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Our strategy tomorrow will be to excavate L2029 to the level of some green-yellow mudbrick material seen in a section under L2023. We will also finish L2022 and photograph it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began the day by taking elevations to double check some questionable figures of yesterday. We then got photos of two pits L2022 and L2028. We then proceeded to take down L2029 by 5 cm. We are cautious when diggin near L2023 our north/south mudbrick wall because we are looking for the second course of brick which is designated by a yellowish green tint. Our man plan is to dig L2029 down to the level of L2018. We will then re-evaluate our loci and plan our strategy according to the layout of our trench at that more uniform elevation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	11:30. We decided to take L2025 down by 5 cm at first and then probably more depending on what we see. We also noticed a mudbrick between L2022 and L2028 so we opened up that L-shaped area as L2030. Hopefully we will be able to consolidate L2029, and L2018 because they appear to be the same color and texture - a light grayish brown mudbrick collapse. We also hope to close out L2022 and L2028. All of these could probably be combined into a singular locus. We also want to articulate our mud brick wall L2023. Perhaps we can even get a good plan photo before the day is over. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We did consolidate L2029 and L2018 as they appear to be the same material. We are continuing to articulate L2023 our north south mudbrick wall. Our plan photo will have to wait until tomorrow, however.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In conclusion, our ability to handle the extreme complexity of our trench proves we are far beyond the operating level of the other trenches.  C2 is a textbook example of how to excavate  a trench.  We're putting on an archaeology clinic.  I do have one major point of contention today and, surprisingly, it doesn't involve B2.  Instead it is B1, at least, half of B1.   That stupid piÃ§ took a nice cold bottle of Uludag out of our cooler at the end of the day.  There was no consideration whatsoever, just petty theft.  Now I don't want to disseminate any stereotypes, but right now I'm thinking that the Danes are an ethic-lacking people.  They don't seem to belong to society, but are rather a parasite gorging itself on the rest of civilized humankind.  But that's just my opinion, I could be wrong. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We begin by troweling the soil of loci 2029, 2018 looking at this soil it appears to be composed of the same material with small exceptions of root pits and some looser soil on the southern extreme between L2017 and L2022. We will not dig that area until we lower the major portions of L2032. After that we will articulate the loose pocket of soil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Our main strategy today is to articulate all mudbrick walls and mudbricks and then to prepare our trench for a trench plan photograph.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After investigating L2025 we have decided that it is not mudbrick, but possibly a debris fill. No outlines could be defined and the soil is mottled with light gray and yellowish green. The yellowish green soil could be (and is probably) a mudbrick layer. As we look in the section of L2023 (mudbrick wall running north south) on can see a course of yellowish green soil that is quite symmetrical. Andy decided that it was probably structural. the texture of this structural material is very chunky and brittle and quite loose. It is not nearly as compact as the top few courses of mudbrick found in L2014. After digging a few centimeters of L2025 a larger deposit of yellowish green soil was found, though there were no signs of mudbrick lines on or near its surface. Therefore we decided to cut further into it to catch it in the section of L2023. We will designate it a new locus. Other curious facts about the yellowish green soil are that it is heavily paced with white hair width roots. And regarding the yellowish green in L2023, it does not appear as symmetrical on the east side section as it is on the west side section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	This was our stopping point for today. We dig 10 cm lower in L2015 to expose more yellowish green material as well. After that point we prepared to take a trench plan photo which was nearly completed today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We return to work on Saturday, August 5th. Our strategy will be to finish photography, take elevations and to remove the mudbricks and continue downward.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In summation, I have a number of gripes today.  The first was actually from yesterday, but at the time I was too speechless to address it.  It concerns the desecration of my beloved Old Blackie.  That goyim apikorsim Drew boy took Old Blackie while I was taking elevations and used a Sharpie to draw a face on her.  This is a blatant violation of everything the Fraternal Order of Archaeologists holds sacred.  You never mess with another man's trowel.  That is just a given.  It is an unwritten more of society.  The only way to rectify the situation is to wash the trowel clean in the blood of the offender.  Only then will the Trowel Goddess of the Hatti lands will be appeased.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Another point I would like to make concerns the management.  While writing in this journal we were approached and asked if we could help with the shopping.  Now I have no problem with helping out.  The problem is that they want to do it now while everyone is smack dab in the middle of entering their notebooks into the database.  If we had been told ahead of time or asked to go in fifteen minutes I have no doubt that their would be many volunteers.  Instead management will go and sulk.  So to hell with it.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Finally, I will just say that the Screamin'  Chickens of C2 are leaving all the other trenches in our wake.  We are sexy bitches.  Yeah baby, yeah.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;5 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Because of the wind storm on Wednesday, August 2nd, cleaning the trench is extensive. We need to re-photo the trench for our trench plan, take elevations for our day plan and tag the loci in the east section of the trench. Hopefully we will accomplish this in a few hours and be able to remove the mudbricks in L2014 and L2016. We would like to continue to excavate down to the yellowish-green structural layer. If it is a mudbrick type we should see some symmetry. Perhaps it will follow the orientation of the existing mudbrick walls. It looks as though it follows L2023 and is found closely associated with L2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Michealle is a guest today. We spent a lot of time plumb bobbing strategies sections of the trench for the plan so that Drew has reference points. After about an hour of that we tagged the stratigraphic layers in the east baulk with very large nails. The trench now looks like a garage sale when there is nothing left to sell out the tables. Bradley/Andy asked us to photograph the phases of the mudbrick walls, another hour or so of inactivity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	finally after all that we were able to chop 3 courses off the wall in L2014 on the east side. It was a cathartic experience. There is now a pile of 3000 year old mudbrick rubble on the floor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Tomorrow we will finish closing L2014 and L2016 as well as begin the search for more mudbrick in the south of L2032 and the floor of L2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;6 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Continuing where we left off yesterday, we cleaned the mudbrick debris from L2014 and found a pit L2034. Michaelle articulated the fill layer of the pit (a dark silt charcoal) and has arrived at a rock-pottery-bone layer. It looks strikingly similar to L2022. We will photo it and continue to dig it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We are also digging the rest of L2033. It looks as though it spills out into L2032 shallowly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	L2012 continues under our mudbrick wall L2016 so we are sectioning L2016 to see what came first, the pit or the wall. It looks like the pit cuts into a second course of wall so we are moving cautiously to see what comes first. After some digging, it looks as though the pit L2012 continues under the mudbrick wall L2016. L2016 also contains a semi-course of mudbrick under the more definite bricks. This could be a mudbrick "mortar" laid over the pit to hold the bricks in place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We also excavated L2024 down to the present level of the western half of the trench. Nothing new was found in that loci except a few more large stones. They may be associated with the stones found along the west side of L2023.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After excavation of L2034 and finding a stone that looks to be a partial door post resting atop the layer of plaster and packed stones and pottery that this could have been a door post. We will trowel around that area to see what kinds of things are associated with this locus. We will not finish excavating this locus until we bring down the surrounding locus L2032 because of the hardness of the pit surface and its depth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We also found a pit located in the east baulk on the north side and partially under L2035 (the fill under L2014 - the mudbrick wall). This pit is called L2036. It contained very little artifacts but was filled with an extremely fine white ash. We did not completely excavate this pit as time ran out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Tomorrow we will finish with the pits L2034 and L2036. We will also dig the large fills L2032 and a currently unnamed locus on the west side of the trench to see if our north south mudbrick wall L2023 continues to have courses beneath it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;7 August 2000	&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by finishing the pit L2036. We got through the very white ash layer and beneath that (immediately beneath) was found some broken long bones (in very small pieces) and a tooth ( a very thick incisor), and a bead. We logged the bead as a small find. The tooth looks more animal than human, so I am assuming this is still an animal deposit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We also lowered L2032 significantly. This is the fill on the east side of the trench surrounding the pits on the east baulk and the wall L2023 which bisects the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	directly beneath L2015 we were able to articulate another mudbrick wall or surface that runs almost parallel to L2023 called L2037. there is another mudbrick on the northeast corner of the trench called L2038. The space in between L2037 and L2038 looks also to be mudbrick. A mudbrick network is arising.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We dug L2032 down about 20 cm and it is spotted with 2 small pits on its west side. these pits look insignificant, but will be removed with caution. We are now digging a new locus L2039 which is the fill to the south of a small reddish colored mudbrick wall L2040. L2039 is located to the north of the pits on the south baulk (L2022 and L2033). We will excavate it about 20 cm lower that its present level. My overarching plan is to remove enough soil on the east side of the trench so that the east and the west sides are approximately the same elevation. once that has been accomplished with will examine both sides together.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We lowered L2028 another 15 cm and found a small metal band. Quite interesting though it was found in an ash pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We lowered L2039 about 20 cm and found nothing significant except an additional mudbrick in the wall L2040.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We finished the day excavating 5 cm from a new locus L2041. This is the fill below the ash layer L2012. 60 Minutes filmed us working on this locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;8 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by finishing leveling out the west half of the trench L2041. It looks as though there is some mudbrick on the north side of L2041 called L2044. After scraping and sweeping we definitely have mudbrick walls, probably a continuation of L2037 and L2038. Once we remove the north/south wall L2023 we should see L2044 and L2037 and L2038 connect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While deciding how to approach L2023, our north/south mudbrick wall, we dig 10 cm lower in L2039. At the bottom of this locus we found a rock alignment following the southeast trend of L2040.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	One of the biggest questions I had today was the nature of L2023, and if it had any relation to the mudbricks found in L2037 and L2038. I also wanted to know how many courses L2023 has. in order to answer this last question, I sectioned the wall into a new locus L2043 on the west side where the bricks were best exposed and found that L2023 has definitely 4 courses and perhaps 5. I suspect however that this fifth course is actually L2037 running underneath L2023. This because the color of this "course" is the same as L2037.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Before this section L2043 was taken, however, I had a plan photo taken of L2023 knowing that it would be removed today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	I finally named the rock alignment found near the center of the trench (L2042) and took opening elevations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At the bottom of the section L2043, we found another rock alignment running parallel to L2042 with 2 courses of mudbrick between them. This looks to be a continuation of L2037. When we remove L2023, we should see its relationship to the rest of the mudbricks in the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After investigating the mortar lines of L2023 and L2037 I saw that they didn't match up and that L2023 runs more north/south proper and L2037 runs more in a north, northwest direction. Therefore L2023 looks to be a later phase of construction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Finally, we began to remove L2023 and will finish that job tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;9 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by removing L2023 in order to expose L2037 and L2038 and L2044. Hopefully L2038 and L2044 are the same.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After scraping L2032 we find what appears to be the bottom of some mudbrick debris. under this mudbrick debris we see a dark silty layer. We may change loci depending on how extensive the dark layer is. It may only be redent root pits. After investigation, we decided to keep L2032 intact as it is. The pits referred to earlier are too minor to change locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Additionally we see some possible mudbrick bordering the pits L2028 and L2036. These may be structures bordering or walling-in these pits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We have started a new locus L2045. It is in the southwest corner of the trench. Lots of pits mixed with some packed mudbrick debris.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While digging out L2023 we found that L2044 was not mudbrick as it was only 2-3 cm thick. Under that is another course of stone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Regarding L2032 and the surrounding pits, we thought earlier today that the pits were bordered by walls. After spraying the area, some colors of red mudbrick showed, but no articulation could be made. Therefore no walls.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After digging L2045 for about 15 cm, nothing new surfaced except for large stones (1 conglomerate riverstone, and one smooth stone) and some pottery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We are now moving to L2039 and bringing that down 15 cm. It looks as though we've come upon a surface. It is covered with pottery and small rocks. A course of stone is also bisecting the locus - running southeast.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We sectioned L2034 to find its depth and to see the rocks and pottery in their configuration we also found in excellent charcoal sample below the pit. We no longer think its a door post so much as we believe it to be an oven.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We are also removing L2030, L2031, L2040. There is not enough evidence to prove if they are mudbricks. The top resembles mudbrick, but the sections show no definite stratigraphy. Below them we see a course of stones in section. We will close L2040, 2030, 2031 and L2034 hopefully today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Investigating L2030 and it looks as though the brick is resting on part of L2028.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We closed L2034, 2030, 2031, 2040 and 2044 today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;10 August 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We began by cleaning and articulating L2045 and L2039, getting them ready for a photo, at same time we opened a new locus L2046, which is a cobblestone wall, beneath the fill, which consisted of the L2030, L2031 and L2040. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We then opened L2047, which is line of mudbrick running parallel to L2037, although on a lower level. It abuts L2037, L2041 and L2046. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After this we opened a third locus L2048, which is a stone wall below L2044, we can see 2 rows of large cobbles in 1 course along the north baulk, abutting L2041.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	When we had done this, we agreed to remove L2022, very carefully, fearing that it could bring a large part of the south baulk down. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While searching for the precise border of L2038, CE found an area with burnt wood, you could almost see the grains in the wood/charcoal, this wood was below L2034.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Jakob suggests that the kiln / oven L2034 and L2036 the ash pit beside it are the same phase. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We think that the burnt wood in between them could have been used to feed the fires in the oven / kiln. We saved a great deal of the charcoal for a carbon sampling and we took a soil sample from the same area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We are working on articulating mudbrick walls to the east of L2037. These are probably related or the same as L2047.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We closed L2039, because we have come down to a surface with a potsmash, cobbles and other pottery are lying flat. This surface is located south of L2046 a stone alignment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	By noon  we uncovered another row of cobbles parallel to L2048 and we decided to extend L2048 to cover these stones, as they seem to be part of the same structure. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 12, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We continued to dig L2041 down to the level of the stones of L2048 in preparation for a plan photograph.  We are also continuing to excavate L2045.  We believe it to be a surface similar to L2039, though it does not have pottery on its surface.  It does, however, have a grindstone frag at the day's opening level.  We are also straightening our baulks for drawing.  We are only exposing L2045 a few cm because of its likeness to L2039.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We plan-photoed the trench and will plot some reference points for Drew tomorrow.  That is where we will pick up tomorrow.  We opened L2049 which is a surface below L2039 and L2045.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 13, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Today our plan is to finish the trench for this year.  This entails finding out the courses of our walls (L2045, L2038, L2037,  L2047, L2042, L2046), We will also remove the surface L2049 and continue to excavate the pit L2028.  We also must begin drawing the East baulk today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: C-2-2000-08-013-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/E6471C77-5FB0-4DD8-BD95-F354563269F6</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+C-2-2000-08-013-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FE6471C77-5FB0-4DD8-BD95-F354563269F6</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830723</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812647</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E6471C77-5FB0-4DD8-BD95-F354563269F6">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 2</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>E6471C77-5FB0-4DD8-BD95-F354563269F6</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:37:48-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:37:48</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
