<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="EBFFB420-631B-4FFE-33F6-613BA8DB846E" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>D-5-2002-Summary</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2002</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7">7D6F837E-D0C1-4E80-28AE-7FB32FC779F7</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2002</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4">
        <oc:name>Trench 5</oc:name>
        <oc:id>5CB3DFFF-05FF-4B85-61FB-8A2C063A84C4</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61">
              <oc:name>Area D</oc:name>
              <oc:id>64E926FA-087A-4873-DF43-FFEE0E1EBE61</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:D-5-2002-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Final Trench Summary, Kenan Tepe 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Trench 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 21, 2002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Following the late discovery of the mudbrick house last season and subsequent digging in almost exclusively in the southern reaches of the trench, an early focus this year was to get the remaining two thirds of the trench down to similar levels that we might see if we could find any further contexts linked to the structure. As it turned out, we found many, all linked to the Ubaid by ceramic analysis. We discovered so much, in fact, that the majority of the season was spent doing fine excavation in these areas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The northern third of the trench, however, managed to maintain some of its enigmatic nature as pit after pit, often cutting one another, areas of surface tumble and a human skeleton all turned up in the mix.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	All-in-all it was successful, if somewhat slow, season. The western and southern baulks were drawn at the conclusion of excavations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Ubaid Contexts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The southern two thirds of the trench were all revealed this season to be not only of an Ubaid context, but a single contemporary one. The area appears to be the interior area of a structure in the S, with the far S wall being a later addition to the structure. The central third of the trench, alternatively, appears to be an outdoor space which was used to either store or tresh grain as evidenced by a surface of compressed, decayed grain found there. And finally, along the eastern baulk, a large oven, similar to but better preserved than the one attached to the mudbrick house, was uncovered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Collapse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The entire area in the central-W part of the trench is occupied by a thick (as much as ~70 cm) layer of collapse made up of fill, several areas of stones and mudbrick. We began to uncover this area last season as L5066 but due to time limitations didn’t get particularly far into the context. This season we were able to take the whole region down. The collapse was relatively undifferentiated, and from top to bottom excavated loci were 5079, 5094, 5097, 5099, 5100, 5103, 5108. Of note, L5099 and 5097 had higher than usual concentrations of stone, though never as articulatable architecture. L5103 contained extensive amounts of mudbrick as well, though similarly unarticulatable. The areas of unaritculatable mudbrick and stone helped lead to the conclusion that the region was all a large collapse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	One particularly interesting find that also gave credence to the collapse theory was a piece, approximately 1x1 m, of preserved fabric that was wrapped around or draped over a mudbrick (KT 5094.8, 5094.23, 5094.24, 5094.25, 5094.31, 5094.35, 5094.39, 5094.40, 5094.55). Given the pottery in the context dates to the Ubaid it is amazing the material preserved so well. That combined with the preservation of the grain surface seems to indicate a significant and large single-event collapse occurred.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Also of note, among the lithics uncovered were a large number (~40-60) of small obsidian blades.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Grain Surface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Essentially the largest single find of the season, a surface made entirely of compressed, decomposed grain was found under almost all the region of collapse. Uncovered as L5098 and excavated in four quadrants, L5042, 5043, 5044 and 5045, the surface was one to four centimeters thick and was the lynchpin linking the various Ubaid loci. In addition to containing a large number of Ubaid-type sherds itself, the surface could be seen abutting and leaning against the northern wall of the mudbrick structure (L5040, 5041) and also the western wall of the E-central oven, L5138. One odd feature of the surface was that it was completely unflat, having almost 30 cm of vertical differentiation from its highest point in the SW to its lowest in the NE. One possible explanation for its incline is that we are approaching the natural surface of the mound (indicating there was originally some level of hill there). This is not entirely implausible given that the Ubaid is the earliest context on the tepe thus far and survey hasn’t revealed any indications of earlier occupation. As such, we toyed around with the idea of digging a sounding into the SW corner of the trench to look for more layers of occupation (be they Ubaid or earlier) and/or virgin soil but, in the end, the idea was nixed for now due to time constraints and the possibility of severely damaging some possibly excellent contexts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In our last several field days we removed the grain surface and some regions of the fill beneath it (L5146) only to uncover another, earlier packed earth/plastered surface. L5148. Rather than expose it all in a half-cocked way this season, it was deemed a better idea to, after being sure of its existence, leave the full excavation until next season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	In its far northern extent, the grain surface linked to the last Ubaid context before the pits cut the area, L5132, a region of hard-packed earth surface with many flat-lying Ubaid sherds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	There was a previous, albeit smaller grain surface at a higher and more northerly location which presumably linked to the Ubaid (L5095), though its somewhat unclear. However it, like all the western Ubaid contexts, found itself cut by pit L5085.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;E-central Oven&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another physically large find this season was an oven in the central-E portion of the trench. Probably having about half of its extent in the trench, the diameter appears to be around 2.5 meters with a slightly ovoid shape. The oven itself was designated L5138 and its interior fill was excavated in arbitrary layers, from top to bottom L5111, 5120, 5121, 5123, 5124 and 5127. Also within the oven was a smaller piece of architecture—a semi-circle of burnt mudbricks, L5126, possibly a firebox or something similar due to (even for the oven) unusually high concentrations of black ash inside of it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Aside from being associated with all the other Ubaid contexts by its connection to the grain surface, the oven is interesting in particular because it is very similar in size and design to what we were able to discover about the oven attached to the mudbrick structure last season. Though we believe both are contemporary, this one due to its association with the grain surface and the other due to its direct connection to the walls of the mudbrick structure, the latter is founded much higher, lending additional credence to the idea of the Ubaid context being built upon a slope, be it natural or coincidental to earlier occupations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At its northern extent, the oven was cut by ash pit L5116, possibly causing some mixing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Mudbrick Structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Not much work was done inside the mudbrick structure this season, having uncovered what we believed to be its interior surfaces last season and having concentrated more on following its context northward. Nonetheless, some work was done inside the structure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Firstly, we did work, first by partial and then complete excavation, to confirm the walls and their extent. What we uncovered is the following: the southern wall, L5104, appears to either be some sort of step or a later addition to the house as evidenced by the appearance of another segment of grain surface underneath it (no loci designation, only appeared within centimeters of the baulk) and there not being a direct abuttal between it and the N-S wall, L5139. In addition the western portion of the northern wall, L5142 is extant but founded upon an earlier phase of construction when there was another large oven in the WSW of the trench (L5149). The oven feature also appears to have been re-used in the currently exposed phase of the house as a surface, given its quality hard/brunt surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	One of the minor enigmas of the season, a small plaster-lined and covered pit, L5147, was uncovered up against the east side of wall L5139 in one of the few remaining areas of the surface from last season. When excavated, the pit was only several centimeters deep and completely devoid of content. What soil was removed was taken for a float sample (KT 5147.1).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;The Northern Trench&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Whereas the southern part of the trench was occupied by the wonderful Ubaid context, the north was a rather confusing jumble of pits cutting pits and surface tumble. To spice things up further, a perplexing human burial and awkwardly placed human skeleton even found its way into the region.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Plaster-lined Pits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cutting and marking an end to the Ubaid contexts was a very large plaster-lined pit, L5085. At approximately a meter and a half in depth and 1 to 2 meters in diameter, the pit dominated excavation in its region of the trench for pretty much the entire season. Though it did cut the Ubaid contexts, it was an interesting feature in its own regard, containing butchered cow bones (5085.19), the horns of a figurine (5085.31) and a complete vessel (5085.40). It appears from early analysis that the pit dates to the 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;nd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; or 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;rd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Another, much smaller but similar in construction pit, L5122, was found to the east of L5085. What’s its whole original extent was will likely remain unclear, though, due to its being cut on the north, east, and presumably top by ash pit L5116.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Surface Tumble and Pit L5116&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At only about a meter and a half below modern-day surface levels, the NE corner of the trench remains the most enigmatic. For most of the season we couldn’t make heads or tails of the region. Especially perplexing was a series of 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="vertical-align:super" &gt;rd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; millennium pedestal bases found at the same horizontal level as Ubaid sherds to their west. A sounding (L5093) was dug to try and determine the relationship between Ubaid context L5079 and the more easterly L5084 but unfortunately nothing concrete came of it. In the end I was forced to conclude that either we are dealing with a some poorly differentiated pits or we simply are still dealing with surface tumble in the NE and (until we reached oven L5138) and central-E of the trench. To be fair, this is really not at all unlikely given we plowed through over a meter of topsoil and tumble in others areas of the trench before we encountered good contexts and with the slope of the tepe in area D one can reasonably expect a thick layer of tumble.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Apparently below the thick tumble layers, however, was a very large ash pit (L5116), occupying roughly the majority of the NE corner of the trench and, notably, cutting both plaster-lined pit L5122 and oven L5138. However, other than its size and what it cuts it was relatively uninteresting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic" xml:lang="en-US" lang="en-US"&gt;Human Remains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Towards the end of the middle of the season while digging a small sounding, L5125, in the NW corner to try and determine if we were below the level of pit L5085 (we were, as we had found the plaster bottom of the pit) we uncovered a human elbow and subsequently ball of the femur stick out of the western baulk. After some time debating over how to deal with the skeleton, it was decided that because it potentially could be from a very important context we would take down the baulk to its level, back approximately 70 centimeters to see if we could make it excavatable. All went well in the baulk reduction and the bone specialists commenced excavating the remains as L5135. We had originally hoped we might be able to trace the remains, which were in a very odd position, flexed and face down with tucked legs, to the Ubaid contexts below the pits but were unable to do so. We did, however, find a distinctive Late Chalcolithic sherd literally wedged between the hip and femur of the skeleton, pretty definitively dating the skeleton to that period. The context, however, remained more unclear. There was no clear burial trench so we were left to ponder if perhaps this person was thrown in a pit or got caught in some sort of structure collapse. My guess is the latter as, when coming close to the remains there are a number of mudbricks in the section where there hadn’t been at higher, pit-penerated levels, however, definitive answers, if they’re to be found, will have to wait until next season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: D-5-2002-Summary</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/EBFFB420-631B-4FFE-33F6-613BA8DB846E</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+D-5-2002-Summary&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FEBFFB420-631B-4FFE-33F6-613BA8DB846E</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830708</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.813714</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/EBFFB420-631B-4FFE-33F6-613BA8DB846E">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 5</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>EBFFB420-631B-4FFE-33F6-613BA8DB846E</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T21:24:14-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 21:24:14</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
