<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="F0CD7FC4-22B8-4C39-1D83-1B44B9DEF461" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>B-2-2000-08-015-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>A9252B4C-F1A7-4931-B9AF-FE0B6310A7C1</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/37F59561-78E1-4AD4-36D6-F7AEF62DA634">37F59561-78E1-4AD4-36D6-F7AEF62DA634</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-08-15</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23">
              <oc:name>Area B</oc:name>
              <oc:id>CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>The purpose of the daily journal was to record the activities taking place in a trench each day. This included which loci were excavated, how and why loci were excavated and the ongoing impressions of the relationships among loci. It should be noted that journals record the actions, impressions and ideas of trench supervisors during the excavations. They are not, therefore, the final interpretations or syntheses of the emerging data.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:B-2-2000-Journal&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 21, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Laid out trench, swept perimeter. the elevation was taken as the average between the highest and lowest points. we started digging locus 2000 in the southern half of the trench. we dug roughly 10cm through the topsoil, which was dry and clumpy. we found many, many pot sherds in this section and one bone fragment. a possible lithic was put in the pottery bag to be washed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;roughly 10 cm down, we hit a harder packed surface, sloping downhill to the west and lighter in color than the topsoil. this extended across the entire southern half of the trench. we didn't open this as a new locus because we had to finish digging the northern half of locus 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;the northern half was similar to the southern half except that it was rockier and only about 5cm thick from the surface to the layer of harder packed soil below, which was contiguous with the layer on the southern side. we found many more sherds here, and also a larger bone fragment. we did not entirely finish excavating this section of locus 2000, and so will continue tomorrow before opening locus 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;surface find consisting of a large fragment of a stone pot was located 86 cm east and 193 cm north of the southeast corner of the trench. both measurements were taken from the 5 meter trench line, not the 4 meterbalk wall. as the fragment was found outside the trench, it was not given a kt number. the work day ended before an elevation could be taken. it will be taken tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 22, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stone pottery surface find is at elevation zero (2.57) according to the line leveling method which was changed to stadia rod measurements today.  Elevations taken on 7/21 were adjusted and recorded in the notebook according to the stadia rod measurements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Potsherds were ecenly distributed throughout the loci and most pieces were 1.5 cm thick.  We dug 10 cm on the southern side in soil which was densley packed mud wash.  This continued so we began digging the eastern side of the trench in an attempt to level it.  We swept things clean and no new locus appeared so we dug another 15 cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After digging these 15 cm we encountered a large body sherd .5 m SW from the NE corner.  We searched for more fragments, but didn’t find anything else.   Later as we were cleaning and straightening the balk wall in this area we found a pot smash which this earlier sherd seemede to fit.  We estimate the pot was 10 cm below the previous sherd.  We are working on cleaning the area and leveling it for photographing tomorrow.  The pot is 19 cm off the E wall and 47 cm off the N wall.  A rough size estimate of the debris field which is colsely articulated is 32 cm wide and 34 cm long.  When it is more fully unearthed tomorrow we will get more specific meaurements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also midway along the E wall were large stones which appeared to be cut and were at the same level as the pot.  We will look for a possible suface tomorrow in this area and 2-4 cm below the pot and rocks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 23, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began by straghtening the balks and leveling the floor surrounding the pot smash.  Drew came and took 2 photos.  One close up plan shot for drawing and one at an angle.  He later returned and took one in context which also shows L-2002 which we opened today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Additionally we found a piece of basalt midway along the east wall abutting the balk.  It was a piece of grindstone and was given KT 2011 and bagged as a small find.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We then began digging down a raised section midway along the east wall of the trench.  It was ground outside of the 1m section around the potsmash and consequently was not leveled before the picture.  After it was at the level of the potsmash and surrounding earth we dug the eastern 2m of the trench down 10cm attempting to find any surface the pot may have been resting on.  As we did so we noticed the earth became slightly more moist and it was more brown in color.  We then opened L-2002 for the estern half of the trench.  Locus-2001 remained opened in the NE corner in a 1m square surrounding the pot smash and in the western half of the trench.  We were then advised that the area around the pot should be given its own locus to avoid contamination of its context.  We opened L-2003 in a 1m square surrouding the pot which had formerly been a section of L-2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our workman Matine found a large potbase when he was picking the eastern side of the trench.  We estimate it was located 12cm off the E wall and 80 cm off the S wall.  It was 16 cm north to south and 12 cm east to west.  We took the elevation and bagged it as a small find.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We then uncovered 2 large rocks which as yet don't seem to be anything but rocks.  One was along the north balk and 99cm off the E balk.  The other was in the center of L-2002.  176m off the N wall and 116cm off the E wall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After cleaning off the southern third of L-2002 we came upon a ring of reddish soil surrounding a white center.  We call it the Red Donut.  The ring was about 90cm from both the south and east walls.  We gave this area a new locus, L-2004.   The ring is 18cm in diameter, but we are currently unsure of whether it is a surface and a larger area should be designated L-2004.  We will clean further tomorrow troweling the surrounding area more level to determine the appropriate designation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Earlier in the day we also found examples of basalt grindstones.  The first was found in L-2001 and was lodged next to the E balk 218cm off the S balk.  The next is slightly questionable as to its function as a grindstone, but it was found in L-2002 105cm off the E balk and 30cm from the S.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 24, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started by troweling the area around the red donut to bring it down the same level. as we did so, 2 more rocks appeared next to the rock 1.76 off N balk and 1.16 off E balk. This rock was found yesterday as it was taller than the others and stuck up into the 10 cm taken off yesterday. A large rock was also discovered in locus 2003 which was of similar size and could be in line with the other two. Another rock was discovered in locus 2002, somewhat smaller but also in a line with the larger grouping. it was located about 1 m south of the trio of rocks. we will continue to trowel this area in search of more rocks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;in addition to the rocks, we found other areas of reddish discoloration. we are tracing around them to see if they could be a surface. the new red spot in locus 2002 is between 1.40 and 1.52 m off the S balk, and between 1.36 m and 1.48 m off the E balk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After we had smoothed out and swept loci 2002 and 2003, Andy came and sprayed the eastern half of our trench. the E balk had a orange mark in the southern half which slanted down from right to left. Andy thought this may have been a mud brick line, though we did not remember encountering anything more than scattered bits of brick while we were digging. We decided to dig the western half of the trench to bring it to the same level as the eastern half and see if there were more reddish marks, mud bricks, or any indications of a surface. we designated this level of the western half of the trench locus 2005 and dug it a third at a time, going from south to north. the eastern side was dug roughly 20 cm, and the western roughly 5. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;there were many pot sherds in L 2005, especially compared to 2002 which otherwise seemed equivalent. two reddish spots were also found, one in the southern third of the locus, and one in the middle third. A large number of whitish flakes were found in the southern third of the locus, which we took to be rmenants of a plaster surface. Rocks and corrogated sherds were also common in this part of the locus. in the middle third, we encounter a number of sherds which twisted, as if they were part of a spout.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After completing the excavation of 2005 to the same level as L 2002, we swept out the trench so that Andy could take a picture of the entire trench. Tomorrow we will dig 10 cm in L 2003 to see if we can locate the bottom of the potsmash. Andy believes that the surface may be below where we have dug to already, although we did find flat lying sherds and several stones in 2003 today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 25, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began today by sweeping down the entire trench so that Drew could come by and take another photo because the ones yesterday were washed out.  The picture was of L-2005 which we opened yesterday.  After that we took elevations and measurements of several rocks and a series of aligned corragated pot sherds.  We felt that they could be on a surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After this Bradley and Andy reccommended that we start a new locus in the northwest corner around the L-2003 (the pot smash locus).  So we opened L-2006 in this area.  A mud floor was found 1-2cm under this locus.  We called the floor L-2007.  However the pre-floor layer was deemed important as it was directly on top of the surface so we saved the soil for a floataion sample in the hopes that we could find some seeds or other light items that had rested on the floor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While we excavated L-2006/7 Matine and Zafir dug another 5cm in the southern third of L-2005.  Another rock was discovered in this area as well as a flat lying group of pottery sherds, possibly a small pot smash.  We took elevations and measurements for these items and gave the sherds KT# 2026.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We continued to epose the floor in L-2006, but it seems to end toward the north end of the locus.  The floor and pre-floor layer have yielded not great finds except one possible piece of grindstone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We were excavating L-2003 in the hopes that the pot was resting on the same mud surface.  We could not find the mud floor, but multiple rocks were found to the west and south of the pot.  Two seemed to be lodged under it.  However we could not find this rock layer to the north of the pot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We decided to open a new locus in 2002 because it could possibly be a pre-floor layer as well.  We excavated the south third of locus 2002 down 5cm and it became L-2008.  We will excavate the entire L-2002 leaving L-2004 (the donut) intact so we can get a plan section and see if it's anything cool.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We used the Munsell color chart today and decided that the red donut and its sister red marks were "reddish yellow 6/6".  T he pre-floor layer, L-2002, was "light olive gary 6/2".  The floor was "light gray 7/2".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 26, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began by sweeping the trench really, really well for a publishable photo of our floor.  This took about 2 hours and was quite tedious. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After the photos we noticed that the south eastern corner of the trench seemed to be a different color and texture from the surrounding soil.  The section seems to indicate a change as well.  I have designated it a pit and given it L-2009.  The color was matched to Munsell's "gray 6/1".  Other than ascertaining these few facts this new locus was left alone for the rest of the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Phil was feeling very sick and went home after breakfast.  I toil alone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I dug 15cm in southern half of L-2005.  The area seems to be simply wash from hillside erosion so I felt that 15cm was justified without fear of tearing up the floor from L-2007 that doesn't seem to exist on that side of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I also took a section around L-2004 down about 10 cm.  I am trying to determine if the red stain extends below the surface layer.  After the section is cut precisely around the circle we will cut the circle in half and see what lies within.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I also took elevations for the rocks that surround the pot smash.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I finally took out the pot smash today.  The area surrounding it was to the a point 4-5cm under where the pot rested so it was not needed for context anymore.  Additionally we were worried that someone might mess with it since its been in there for a few days and lots of people know about it.  Since we have a free day tomorrow and will be out of town, out came the pot.  The dirt inside was gven L-2010 and it was all saved (KT#'s 2041 &amp;amp; 2042) for a floatiation sample.  Some pot sherds that were found yesterday in the rocks surrounding the pot were at roughly the same elevation as the bottom of the pot.  (Pot 96.36 Unarticulated sherds 96.38)  These sherds were given KT#2039 and were marked as a possible mend with the potsmash.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 28, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We swept the trench as usual so we could visually evaluate what we had. We think there could be mud brick lines in L 2008 near L 2009 in the southeast corner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We took opening elevations for L 2009, a potential pit. Some areas were not measured on July 26, so we took elevations for those as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dawnelle is cutting a section through the donut, L2004. The section shows that the donut only goes down about 5 cm. underneath, there is a layer of ash that extends into the area around the donut. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Phil, meanwhile, is excavating the pit L2009, which contains a few potsherds, some small bones, and a small piece of obsidian. He has not reached the bottom of the pit yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We had our workers and Jakob and Michaelle's dug about 10cm in L2005.  Possible mud bricks appeared in the southern half, and we decided to dig 5 cm more on the northern side. We found a large pot sherd with a matching smaller one here, KT2055. Further to the west, we found a possible pot smash, not as complete as the earlier one in L2003. We assigned this KT 2053. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After looking at the donut section, we removed it and saved the eastern half of the soil for analysis. The ash layer continued under the donut. We designated a new locus 2012 for the ash area. The boundaries so far are indistinct. This locus cuts L 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While reviewing our notebook this afternoon, we discovered a couple of problems. The first was that our elevations for the past two days are out of whack with those from previous days. We are not sure what caused this problem, but figure it could be due either to a transit that was moved without our knowledge, or to a transit that had been knocked out of level. Hopefully, if it is the former case, we will be able to fix our measurements by taking an elevation off the rocks that remain in the NE corner of the trench.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The other problem is that Dawnelle and Phil had some miscommunication about which locus was where. Consequently, some KT numbers were put in the wrong locus. We think we have this under control now, but will have to check the tags on our pottery from today. KT 2053 and 2055 are from L 2005, not from L 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 29, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We found out this morning that the bad elevation snafu was stemming from an incident that occured on the afternoon of the 25th, when Phil was placed in charge of taking the measurements. The bad data is confined to the closing elevations for that day, and was possibly caused by an unlevel level. We will try to replace what measurements we can by taking elevations off the balk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We scraped L 2005 in order to see what we could see. While we were doing this, our workmen brought L's 2007 and 2011 down approximately 10 cm, evening them out with the bottom of the section of L 2008 that was dug on the 26th.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile, back in L 2005, we came across the top of a mudbrick wall running east-west through the approximate center of the locus. This wall was renamed L 2013. The area to the south was labelled 2014; that to the north was called L 2016. A small, clay lined pit discovered in the southwest of L 2014 was named L 2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The workmen then dug the eastern half of L 2014 to a depth of 20 cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L 2015, excavated by Dawnelle, was discovered to be a 34 cm diameter circle, lined with broken potsherds. Similar to the donut discovered some days ago (L 2004), the soil appeared burnt. Its color was established as reddish yellow, (6/6). Also like L 2004, the pit was rather shallow, terminating in a large rock which was continuous with L 2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While Dawnelle was digging L 2015, Phil was engaged in the painstaking excavation of several small ash pits located underneath loci 2011 and 2008 in the southeast corner of the trench. An arbitrary area, L 2017, was set up to include all of the pits, which were then excavated as if they were one larger pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After Dawnelle had completed excavating 2015, the workmen dug the remainder of L 2014, except for a small area along the south balk which may possibly be another mud brick wall. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 30, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started the day by having our workmen attempt to flatten L 2014, so that we could look for mud brick and other neat stuff.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While this was going on, Phil continued digging in the pit, L 2009. Later, Bradley and Andy came by and told us to create new loci in the eastern half of the trench. The south side of the trench, under L 2011, will be L 2018. This area is mostly softer crumbly dirt. The north side of the trench, under L 2007 and the northern ~15cm of L 2011, will be called L 2019. This locus has areas of hard material, possibly mud brick debris. Other parts are similar to L 2018.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In addition, we are assigning a new locus number to the hard, mud brick like area in the eastern part of L 2016. It will now be known as L 2020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;July 31, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We opened two new loci today L's 2021 &amp;amp; 2022. Consisting of the two piles of rocks in the eastern half of the trench, these loci were excavated by Bradley (with the help of Betsy) in the space of approximately 2 minutes. We had quite a time corraling flying chunks of basalt, pottery and other miscellaneous heavy stuff. Not to mention trying to assign everything KT numbers. Anyway, after excavating around the rock piles on previous days, we had come to the conclusion that they were free floating and probably sitting on the same surface as our beautiful smashed pot. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L 2021, the area of rocks straddling L's 2018 &amp;amp; 2019, contained the three chunks of grindstone assigned KT's 2074-2076. L 2022 is the area of rocks associated with the pot smash, and contained one large chunk of basalt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After the morning's excitement, we settled back into our routine of straightening balks, sections, and floors. The mini balk around L 2009, created when 2018 was being dug, was removed. In addition, L 2020 and the southern part of L 2014 were troweled in the hope of discovering mud brick lines. The area in the middle of L 2014 is very soft and is quite possibly a pit. Once troweling and cleaning is complete, we may assign it another locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L 2014 is now closed. We found we think to be a section of wall heading north out of the S balk. This wall, L 2023, is interupted by the soft pittish area, L 2024. East of the pit and wall is now L 2025; to the west is L 2026.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After these numbers were assigned, we had the workmen dig the eastern half of 2013 down to the level of the mud bricks that we found in the north of what was L 2014. These bricks have been, for the time being, incorporated into L 2013. We are not sure if they are collapse, or if they represent the true line of the wall, as they veer off from the upper part of 2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 1, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started out by sweeping the trench so that Drew could take a photgraph of the new Loci in the SW quadrant of the trench. After that business was complete, we chopped the northern third of L 2019 down to the level of L 2020, and straightened the balks and sections so that we could look for mud bricks again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Erdan was put to work excavating a new pit in L 2018, L 2027. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy came by and said that L 2019 still didn't make any sense. There was a lot of slumpage, and no clear lines. To try and figure out what's going on, we are nowgoing to dig the rest of L 2019 down to the level of L 2020. The soil in this section appears to be compacted mud brick debris, with areas of looser crumbly soil. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;While L 2019 was being dug, we also dug the remainder of the hump in L 2013, so that the entire wall was approximately level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drew came over and asked us to make him do manual labor, so we had him dig and scrape balks for a while.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After finishing digging L 2019, we dug the northern half of L 2018. Andy came by to look for mud brick, and then had us complete diggin L 2018 to the same level as L 2019 and L 2020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 2, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We have Erdan's (sp?) brother today. We started by having him clean the balks while Matin dug in L 2024. We found a strange egg shaped vessel in this locus. Bradley and Andy came by to look at it and told us to dig L 2018 lower, so that it would be even with L 2013. We are trying to have Matin dig level, but don't know if he will, as he hasn't really ever been able to so far.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bradley also noted that our pit L 2027 didn't totally correspond to the boundaries of the pit in the section. It was a little too big. We redefined the edges of the pit and made it a new locus, L 2028. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is a possible mend for our egg shaped cup in KT 2099. Dawnell found a handle of an appropriate size for the cup yesterday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pit L 2024 was closed today after Dawnell reached the end of the loose soil which was its defining characteristic. The bottom surface of theit is the same hard packed mud that seems to be everywhere.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We continued scraping and picking L 2018 and L 2019 down to the level of L 2013. The wall, L 2013, now appears to continue into the eastern half of the trench. We are waiting for Andy and Bradley to come and take a look.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also, we seem to have missed a pit in the southeast of L 2018, just north of our other pit L 2028. It appears to cut into the wall just discovered in L 2018.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;When they finally arrived, Bradley and Andy sent off our workmen to dig at Ellie's trench. They were very impressed with our wall, which consists of three rows of bricks. The inner bricks are large and square, while those on the outside are as long, but half as wide. L 2020 looks like it may be a wall running north from L 2013 to the north balk, and L 2023 looks like it might run south from L 2013 to the south balk, cut in the middle by L 2024, the pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;After Bradley and Andy left, Dawnell started digging L 2028, which yielded a few bits of pottery and bone. The soil remained loose and dark until the level of the wall, at which point it became the omnipresnet hard mud fill once more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;L 2020 was scraped by Phil so that it was flat and even with L 2019. It is looking more and more like a wall running perpendicular to L 2013, of the same construction and thickness. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 5, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There has been a change in personnel.  Phil has gone to work with Jakob in B1-3 and then to his own trench.  Brian has come to this trench to do an intensive search for mudbrick lines in L-2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We took closing elevations for August 2 this morning.  It was too windy to hold the level straigt on the second.  We were gone the third and fourth for lab and rest days respectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brian and I spent the time until breakfast scraping L-2013.  We are trying to find good lines to create a continuous wall connected to the mud bricks in L-2018.  L-2013 is a few centimeters higher than the developing wall in L-2018 so most of the pre-breakfast time was focused on taking the elevation down so that continuous lines would be recognizeable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The post-breakfast scraping was fruitless.  We concluded that L-2013 was still too high and the lines were covered with slump.  We had the workmen hand pick a few centimeters deeper.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We removed the pot smash in L-2016.  The elevations in the notebooks look odd, but they are correct.  The first piece removed was a sherd standing on its edge, KT 2102.  The top elevation was originally taken from this top edge because it was assumed that it was just one big, nice sherd.  As we dug we found the other lower pieces which had an elevation of 95.76, KT 2024.  As the area around the wall decreased in elevation we were able to remove the remaining sherds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brian continued looking for lines in L-2013.  I began scraping L-2020 in the hopes that we could find lines which would connect it perpendicularly to L-2013.  As of the end of the day there was no absolute connection and no good lines as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 6, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We began by sweeping.  This was followed by more scraping after a fight with Jakob because he sent his worker minion over to our trench to steal our trowels.  It turned out to be a moot point because we sent our workers away to help open the new trenches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I also shot 2 closing elevation points for yesterday.  They looked obviously wrong.  I think I misheard when the number was originally shouted out.  The new numbers fit correctly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brian has pulled up some good lines in the western half and central area of L-2013.  I'm still working on L-2020.  I've handpicked about 3cm because it is above the level that the lines appeared in L-2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I decided to make the mudbricks in the east their own locus.  They do not exactly match the wall that is L-2013.  So for better control this wall is now L-2029.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 7, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The grindstone pictured on the day plans is sticking out of the balk.  Since I'm well below it I'll stop picturing it.  At the end of the season we may try and remove it from the balk, but right now that would be hazardous to the straight balk situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pit L-2024 that cut the wall stub L-2023 may have mud brick debris at the bottom.  Perhaps part of the wall connecting it perpendicularly to L-2013 exists at this lower elevation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This probably should have been done yesterday, but I'm doing it now.  Since the wall in the eastern half of the trench is a new locus L-2029 the areas it abuts and cuts are now new loci as well.  To the north once L-2019, is now L-2030.  The south, L-2018, has become :-2031.  The area in the north west quadrant that is enclosed in walls 2013 and 2020 was once L-2016.  It is now L-2032.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We sprayed this morning.  You can see mud bricks in the section.  We also saw in the very south eastern corner of the trench what appears to be a pit.  So it seems the pit we closed there earlier should not have been closed.  Thankfully we haven't dug in the surrounding locus since we closed that previous pit.  So I have opened it in the incarnation of l-2033.  The whole corner seems to be part of a gigantic pit system.  I won't dig it for a while because I'm focusing of articualting the walls and any associated surfaces.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy speculates, and it seems plausible to me, that L-2029 was an older wall cut by the "L" shape of L-2013 and L-2020.  The 2 wall system is a lighter gray and is narrower.  They appear to have the 2 square brick construction.  L-2029 has the square-rectangle-square 3 course brick construction.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I'm digging the north half of L-2031, 20cm.  Then I'll check the section and if nothing appears take down the southern half.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;No floor in first half.  Two whacks with the pick into the southern half reveals a beautiful potsmash, KT 2132.  Now we're articulating it.  We'll get a photo.  Means while we'll push down 20 cm in L-2030.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Th potsmash turned out to be two potsmashes.  The rims are separate but the body sherds are all mixed up in context.  Both seem to be IA.  The sherds will be bagged together.  The thickness of the sherds should help indicate which piece is from which pot.  Sherds from this smash may have appeared at an earlier elevation and been bagged with the general pottery in KT 2131.  I also think there are pieces of the potsmash in L-2016.  It was KT 2101 and 2124.  These sherds which appeared at the same coordinants but a lower elevation were bagged as KT 2133.  None of these were removed today as 60 Minutes drpped by and wanted to film them.  From bitch of the tepe to show trench.  Oh ya baby.  They will be removed tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I pushed down in L-2030.  Nothing came up but I articulated the fallen piece of mud brick from L-2029 better.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 8, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I had Drew take another pot smash photo and then I took them out this morning.  Metin is leveling the area they were sitting on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I've gone down 10-15 cm in L-2030.  Nothing's coming up yet.  We'll just keep following the wall down.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are some rocks with pottery sitting around in L-2031.  They may be a pit, but I don't know.  I'll trowel around there.  Then we can push down in that locus.  L-2031  may be an outside locus in relation to the wall.  If that is so the large pit system currently in the form of L-2033 makes sense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Turns out that the rocks and pottery are yet another pot smash.  I am truly the pot smash queen.  The elevation has been taken so I'm taking them out.  It was only a few sherds.  Nothing fantastic.  In the context was a pestle.  I small finded (found?) it and gave it KT 2142.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pit L-2033 has been cut level to the surface of L-2031.  The pit may have been chopped into L-2031 perhaps contaminating the pottery in KT 2140.  I'm continuing the leveling process west into L-2025 which abuts L-2031.  I'm trying to see more courses of bricks in L-2029 and L-2013.  I also cut off the one fallen brick on the north of L-2029.  We're cleaning the north section for a cleaner view there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There appear to be mud bricks in the north balk of L-2032, near where it abuts wall L-2020.  I can't find them on the current surface of L-2032.  I don't know if we just chopped them out or if we caught the edge of the bricks and they extend north into the balk.  It might be a wall parallel to L-2013 and L-2029.  At this point we're just not sure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I have also leveled L-2026.  I left the wall stub L-2023 alone hoping that we could connect it to L-2013 at a lower course.  At this point the bottome of pit L-2024 doesn't seem much different than the surrounding loci.  I have split it between L-2025 and L-2026.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The last hour was spent straightening balks, cutting in close to the walls to see sections, and cleaning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 9, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drew took a photo first thing this morning to show all that had been dug yesterday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Erdol dug L-2033 20cm.  Metin cleaned around L-2023 to once again look for lines.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mud brick is coming up in L-2030 near to wall L-2029 on the northern side.  The southern side has an area of hardness which may be bricks or tumble.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy came and we scraped L-2029 and L-2013 looking for courses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I pushed down L-2031 20cm, level with the pit, L-2033.  I left the hard area alone so we can look for lower courses and determine if its a wall or not.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down 20 cm in the northern half of L-2030.  Ever slowly and stealthily I'll move closer to the mud brick, exposing it and looking for lower courses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Came up with a neat sherd in L-2031.  It was painted and incised with a weird "N" or "S" shape.  Turns out it's Hellenistic.  It was found near the edge of the gigantic pit, L-2033, so that could account for its appearance in an elevation that has been pulling up Iron Age pottery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A nice ash layer showed up in L-2033.  I got a soil sample of it, KT 2159.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are some areas of really loose dirt in L-2030.  I didn't change locus because the rest of the overall matrix still seems to be the same.  However I'm doing a controlled dig of the area in case it turns out the be a pit or something.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally met up with the mid brick in L-2030.  I straightened the section.  We're working on all the wall sections and then we'll sweep well.  Then I'll have Andy come and scrutinize everything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were a couple of rocks in L-2032 that have been there for 2 days.  I looked at them with Andy today and decided they're grindstones.  KT 2166 is basalt and KT 2167 is some other type of stone.  I took their elevations, measured them, and made them small finds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down 10cm in L-2025.  Founds some small accretions of coarse grained sand.  They didn't turn out to be anything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy chopped down the mud brick in L-2031.  It was just tumble.  Then he chopped into the wall.  The courses are now beautifully visible.   There are three visible so far on the south.  I'm chopping into the northern side as well as the eastern side of L-2013 to look for courses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nothing in L-2025.  Pushing down to level in L-2026.  I'm still scraping walls. Doesn't look like there's anything in L-2026.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Woo hoo, there are 3 courses visible in L-2029 on the north!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down 5 cm (it was supposed to be 20, but it's the end of the day and my dudes were feeling lazy) in the western half on L-2032.  Not much to see.  I'm hoping sectioning that area will help us see what's going on with the mud brick in the balk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drew took an end of day shot of my very tall walls.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 12, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drew came along and did an opening shot for L-2035.  It is a pit in the north east corner of L-2030.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Had a fight about the good level stick.  People will be pissed about this for a while.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dug pit L-2035 20cm.  Found some charcoal looking bits and had them contaminated by fingers.  Opened L-2035 because it was looser soil.  When swept it decreased in elevation creating a perimeter around the pit.  There were areas of yellowish soil that looked like root or bone decomposition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chopped off half of L-2023 to look at the section.  Didn't see anything.  It comes out tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took a soil sample of L-2035, KT 2194.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chopped 4cm into the north face of L-2013.  We have to take some off to make it straight and look for brick lines.  Also chopped into the west of L-2020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Removed the hump of mud brick that extends off L-2029 into L-2030.  The area under it was quite soft.  We removed it to the level of the pit trying to get a section on the hard areas west of this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is a pit in L-2036 in the south west, cutting L-2026.  It is much softer and browner than the surrounding areas.  It also has some ash content.  20cm into this pit a pot smash came up, KT 2208.  Drew came and photoed it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Had Erdol dig 20cm in pit L-2034.  I'm trying to remove it in preparation for a big push in that area to try and find the wall foundation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dealing with the pot took up some time so we didn't dig in all the areas discussed with Bradley and Andy.  We will do so tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 13, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took out the mudbrick wall stub L-2023.  It seems to only have been slump and fill with one brick course on top.  It's gone so I'm closing the locus today.  I'm a little bit confused as to what to do with the dirt underneath.  It looks the same as L-2026 and L-2025, but for forms sake I guess I'll have to make it a new locus.  The course on top was about 20 cm high.  The rest was dirt it was pedastled on.  It was all excavated as one locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since the separating influence is gone I am now redefining the loci in the area.  L-2025 and L-2026 are now being combined into L-2037.  I also closed what was left of L-2031.  Most of it was eaten up by a pit.  The remaining soil is the same as L-2025 and L-2026 so it can easily be incorporated into the new L-2037.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The rock area in L-2032 is also becoming a new locus, L-2038.  The rocks are too dense to be conincidence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;sectioning  45cm of wall in L-2013 next to the west balk.  We're hoping this will define the wall better.  Also sectioning 45cm of wall L-2020 next to the north balk.  Same impetus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sectioned off 30cm of the mud brick in area L-2032.  Trying to see things in section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down 15cm in pit L-2034.  There is a whitish residue coming up on some of the rocks.  It looks like plaster residue.  No evidence in the balk of a surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down all of the mud brick i L-2032.  It was only some slump.  There were some rocks underneath it, but only in the northern most 60cm.  There was a nice grindstone with a smaller pestle hole in the rocks.  It's KT 2221.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down 20cm in the northern 80cm of L-2032.  Trying to associate a surface with the rocks of L-2038 and the mud brick in the balk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Looks like we hit right on a surface in L-2034.  Need to undercut the wall more to look for lower courses to see if the two are associated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The sectioning didn't reveal much.  It needs to be sprayed tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 14, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leveled L-2032 to the point we'd dug yesterday.  At least that was the plan.  I think they took it down another 5cm and picked over the entire area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I'm scraping L-2029 and under cutting it pretty far in my search for more courses.  I'm taking off roughly 11cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bradley, Andy and I made a heart wrenching decision today.  After sectioning and spraying and troweling it seems that I have nursed a viper to my bosom.  A wolf in sheep's clothing.  L-2020 does not look like a wall.  There were some brick lines but they were diagonal and always sketchy.  Today we took the area off life support.  We bashed it to pieces.  There is 20cm let protruding from the intersection where the 3 "walls" met.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dug out pit L-2036 more.  In it we found several thick pieces of pottery.  There are also a lot of stones at what may now be the bottom of a stone lined pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Found a half of a grindstone in the rock pile L-2038, KT 2230, made it a small find.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hamdi found another rock 30m west of the F trenches.  I made it a surface find for him.  He thinks it looks just like a phallus.  Well isn't that special.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down in L-2037 trying to reach the level at the bottom of the pit which might be a surface.  We picked 10 cm and then hand picked to try and extend the area.  We started with the eastern 75cm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I suppose I need to make the surface a new locus, but until I see how far it extends I don't want to do so.  I don't want to have to keep defining and redeining its parameters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took off the last 20cm of L-2020 and the top of L-2013 to the one mud brick we can see.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took off 45cm of L-2029 at the lower elevation, extra course of bricks.  The first 20cm were eaten up by roots so there was no chance to see if the courses extended lower than the 5 visible on the northern side.  Hopefuly the next 25cm will give us something in the way of more courses.  Scraping off the 11cm on the southern side didn't reveal any more courses.  It could still be undercut even more though.  Erdal thinks the wall ends before the floor.  Unfortunately he may be right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pushed down L-2037 in the next 75cm.  The central section had a soft area that looked like animal or root holes.  Either these cut through the floor of we may have lost it this far over.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then we cleaned up and went home for a nice lunch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 15, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today is my last digging day, sniff sniff.  I will  miss Erdal and Metin.  In preparation for closing I have done a number of things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We hacked off the tiny stub of L-2020.  It is gone and closed.  We also hacked off all of L-2013, even passed the one mudbrick we had been saving.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I undercut  the bottom levels of the wall L-2029 another 10cm but the courses don't extend that far.  The wall is about 20 cm above the floor so the contexts don't go together&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We articulated the rocks, L-2038.  They may be part of a foundation for the wall we missed in the north baulk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We scraped the floor thus closing pit L-2034.  As we extend the floor L-2037 will be closed.  We picked 10cm in L-2037 and L-2032 in an attempt to extend the floor.  It reached through the end of L-2037, but not into L-2032.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We didn't get the plan photo done today.  There was so much to scrape to extend the floor.  Tomorrow we'll clean really well and maybe bash some more in L-2030.  Then we'll get the pland and the work will be finished.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Closed L-2037.  The floor is now L-2039 and encompasses that entire area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Closed L-2032 and L-2020.  Called the area L-2040.  As we push into L-2030 later it may become part of it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Closed L-2036.  Met up with a rock layer so the pit stops.  Made the forthcoming rocks part of the floor L-2039.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;August 16, 2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Will take the plan shot before taking down L-2030/  Articulating rocks in L-2038 and L-2039 then we'll sweep and shoot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Got the plan photo.  Plumb bobbed some points for Drew so he can put it all together.  Took out the rock pile before I took the points.  Oops.  Sorry Drew.  Got enought other points to compensate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took down L-2030.  Leaving the mudbrick area next to L-2029 which may actually be a surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Took down all the rocks in L-2038 and leveled the area.  The area underneath has also become L-2040.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Closed all the loci.  My digging days are done.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: B-2-2000-08-015-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/F0CD7FC4-22B8-4C39-1D83-1B44B9DEF461</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+B-2-2000-08-015-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FF0CD7FC4-22B8-4C39-1D83-1B44B9DEF461</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830645</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812783</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F0CD7FC4-22B8-4C39-1D83-1B44B9DEF461">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 2</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>F0CD7FC4-22B8-4C39-1D83-1B44B9DEF461</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:38:06-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:38:06</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
