<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<arch:resource xmlns:arch="http://ochre.lib.uchicago.edu/schema/Resource/Resource.xsd" xmlns:oc="http://opencontext.org/schema/resource_schema_v1.xsd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" UUID="F9A6613B-13EF-4062-BD33-1B0141BC36D4" ownedBy="3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E" type="internalDocument">
  <arch:name>
    <arch:string>B-2-2000-08-022-Season</arch:string>
  </arch:name>
  <arch:properties>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>6953B270-2608-464E-6494-A8F9573E4D21</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>CC034EC7-F0C8-449B-D92F-7896B73E5FF6</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72">1DA5F5DF-E970-48B5-D398-1E0E8C90AE72</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="nominal">Journal Type</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>Season</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>9ED499E4-5B88-4BA4-7BE2-647A027C12D0</arch:variableID>
      <arch:valueID>F73F3489-9D82-4B93-75B8-D395B6079253</arch:valueID>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/81DA70D0-1564-49A3-98DA-9462D97F19E3">81DA70D0-1564-49A3-98DA-9462D97F19E3</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="calendric">Date</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000-08-22</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
    <arch:property>
      <arch:variableID>2120E57F-3EF2-452F-B927-880D873FE896</arch:variableID>
      <arch:integer>2000</arch:integer>
      <oc:propid href="http://opencontext.org/properties/96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89">96327361-0673-4AF7-DD8B-CBAE26377D89</oc:propid>
      <oc:var_label type="integer">Year</oc:var_label>
      <oc:show_val>2000</oc:show_val>
    </arch:property>
  </arch:properties>
  <arch:links>
    <arch:docID type="spatialUnit" info="link">E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D</arch:docID>
    <oc:space_links>
      <oc:link href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D">
        <oc:name>Trench 2</oc:name>
        <oc:id>E161378D-8781-4237-8126-F40327E3809D</oc:id>
        <oc:relation>link</oc:relation>
        <oc:item_class>
          <oc:name>Trench</oc:name>
          <oc:iconURI>ex_square_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
        </oc:item_class>
        <oc:context>
          <oc:tree id="default">
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/1_Global_Spatial">
              <oc:name>Turkey</oc:name>
              <oc:id>1_Global_Spatial</oc:id>
              <oc:level>3</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Region</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/region_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F">
              <oc:name>Kenan Tepe</oc:name>
              <oc:id>5D6B6454-017A-43C1-9F15-6DFE36C3558F</oc:id>
              <oc:level>2</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Site</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/site_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
            <oc:parent href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23">
              <oc:name>Area B</oc:name>
              <oc:id>CC3DDA1A-1C78-41EA-E05A-9BBC248C8B23</oc:id>
              <oc:level>1</oc:level>
              <oc:item_class>
                <oc:name>Area</oc:name>
                <oc:iconURI>http://opencontext.org/database/ui_images/med_oc_icons/operation_area_30x30.jpg</oc:iconURI>
              </oc:item_class>
            </oc:parent>
          </oc:tree>
        </oc:context>
      </oc:link>
    </oc:space_links>
  </arch:links>
  <arch:notes>
    <arch:note>
      <arch:string>At the end of each week, trench supervisors were expected to write a concise summary of the previous week’s activities.  The purpose of this weekly summary was to review the week’s notes, check for completeness, identify any mistakes or missing information, and to begin building interpretations.</arch:string>
    </arch:note>
  </arch:notes>
  <arch:content>
    <arch:internalDocument>
      <arch:string type="xhtml">&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Journal / Summary:B-2-2000-Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Area B Trench 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left"/&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Trench B2 was opened on the eastern side of the tepe.  As a result the western half of the trench sloped downhill.  Obviously then loci continuous across the trench in an east-west manner can have quite different elevations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The topsoil L-2000 was removed rather uneventfully, although the trench was lopsided.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Next came the subtopsoil L-2001.  Both these loci had extensive pot sherds from various periods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	While straightening baulks in the north eastern section of the trench an impressive pot smash was found.  It was given KT 2010.  It took several days to expose it and remove it fully.  A new locus L-2003 was created in a 1 meter square around it to preserve context.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We had already created L-2002 in the eastern half of the trench.  The soil there was more brown than the western half.  On reflection it seems this was only due to the fact that there was more moisture in the soil.  It dried and looked the same as L-2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	L-2004 appeared towards the southern end.  It was a reddish area of oven residue with an ash layer L-2012 below it.  Probably associated with floor L-2007/L-2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Meanwhile rocks began appearing in L-2003.  These would jut through the pre-floor layer L-2006 and rest on floor L-2007.   They were finally given their own locus L-2022.  The pile was obviously associated with the floor as several grindstones were found in its midst.  A similar collection of rocks L-2021 was found in the floor area of L-2011.  It also contained numerous grindstones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We found evidence of a mud brick lines in the east and so decided to  also dig in the west to perhaps uncover similar evidence.  Thus L-2001 became L-2005 as we pushed more carefully looking for mud brick.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	We then found what appeared to be an area of surface near L-2003 the meter around the pot smash.  We arbitrarily surrounded L-2003 with a new locus L-2006 to make it easier to find the floor in a smaller isolated area.  L-2006 was a pre-floor layer.  The soil from which was saved to float.  This layer popped off the floor fairly easily revealing floor L-2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The area south of this was made L-2008.  In the hopes that this too was a pre-floor layer.  It was and is equal to L-2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Scraping for this floor was more interesting as we stumbles upon pit L-2009 in the far south east corner.  Pits in this area would continually haunt us, looking like they were finished only to reappear in the section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	At this point the area in L-2003 had been pushed down enough that KT 2010 could be removed.  The soil inside was made L-2010 and saved to float under KT 2141 &amp;amp; 2142.  The pot went home to be washed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	After digging a bit longer in L-2005 we felt mud brick lines appeared.  This area was designated L-2013, and was thought to be a wall.  It was eventually found to be a fraud and knocked down.  However while we thought it was a wall the area north of it became L-2016.  The south became L-2014.  L-2014 was cut by a pit/oven area L-2015 which was immediately excavated.  It was circular with pot sherds around it and reddish soil.  It ended with a rock at the bottom.  I assumed this was entirely within the confines of L-2014.  So the rock was not given a new locus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	There was an area of small continuous ash pockets taken together as L-2017.  This is in the big pit area so it may have all been part of one gigantic pit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The surrounding area was L-2011 the floor, which was hacked through and made L-2018.  To the north floor L-2007 was taken out and made L-2019.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Another hard area appeared and was being articulated in L-2016.  This area became L-2020.  The area was always tricky as there were intermittent hard spots.  However we thought we found good lines and L-2020 was born.  Later and 1 meter deeper we realized we'd blown through a wall preserving the collapse as L-2020, which oddly enough is what hindsight is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	An area of rocks sitting on the surface of L-2007/L-2011 and somewhat in L-2018/L-2019 was given L-2021.  Several grindstones KT 2074-2076 were found in it.  A similar rock pile, upon which KT 2010 was sitting became L-2022.  These were isolated pedestaled rocks so the loci were closed when the rocks were removed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	As we dug in L-2014 some changes occurred.  A hard mud brick area occurred and was called L-2023.  We thought it was a wall stub.  To the north of it a large pit occurred, L-2024, cutting the end of the mud brick.  We assumed that L-2023 met L-2013 and we'd find lower courses under the pit.  Turns out that neither L-2013 or L-2023 were actually walls.  They were only collapse and both were removed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Before L-2023 was unmasked we lived under the assumption that is was a wall.  Therefore the are to the east became L-2025 and the area to the west became L-2026.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Also during out digging a new pit occurred in the south east.  It became L-2027.  This quickly morphed into new parameters and became L-2028.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Finally we had an important break through.  A wall with visible, real lines showed up and was designated L-2029.  This wall was followed down five courses.  It abutted collapse L-2013 &amp;amp; L-2020.  It may have a hard surface on the north, but to the south the surface (L-2039) is 20 cm too low and appears to run under the wall.  This wall was left standing when the season closed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Due to the presence of wall L-2029 the north eastern quadrant became L-2030.  The south east became L-2031.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The pit system in the south east continues on in the new form of L-2033.  Every time we thought it was closed we sprayed the section and saw the continuing line.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Meanwhile the area between L-2020 &amp;amp; L-2013 came up with a great pot smash, KT 2132.  It was actually two pot smashes mixed together, but in the field I couldn't separate them accurately.  60 Minutes filmed this pot smash for a while, thank you very much!  As a result, not of 60 Minutes, we thought there might be a surface soon so the locus was changed to L-2032.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	The pit in the south east corner spread and covered almost all of L-2031.  This new form became L-2034.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	A pit also appeared in the north east corner, L-2035, cutting L-2030.  L-2030 also exhibited oven residue and this pit, but no good context/surface ever appeared.  It was eventually leveled and became L-2040.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	A pit also appeared in the south west corner, L-2036.  Pot smash KT 2208 came out of it.  The baulk was tunneled into to get it.  I did try to stop that from happening.  It ended at rocks.  They were not made a new locus since the season closed, but they should be examined in their own right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Finally L-2023 was removed and the area including the small portion of left of L-2031 became L-2037.  This was a pre-floor layer.  A beautiful surface, L-2039, came up in the south east ending the huge pit complex.  It extended across the south of the trench, but its existence in the north was not confirmed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	A series of rocks appeared in the north west and became L-2038.  They were free floating, but could be associated with the wall in the north baulk we destroyed.  Perhaps as a foundation for the wall.  They were all taken out.  The soil underneath had a high concentration of horse piss soil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Finally L-2032, L-2020 &amp;amp; L-2030 were all taken down looking for the floor.  it was a cursory look since we closed down.  The floor was not found definitively so the north area of the trench became L-2040.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p style="text-align:left;margin-top:1pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;	Watch for mud brick lines that began appearing in the south western end of the trench.  They are just north of the rocks in the corner.  It seems that a good wall is appearing there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;p/&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</arch:string>
    </arch:internalDocument>
  </arch:content>
  <oc:metadata>
    <dc:title>Kenan Tepe: B-2-2000-08-022-Season</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>Open Context</dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2012-06-30</dc:date>
    <dc:subject>Ubaid Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Late Chalcolithic Period</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Anatolia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Northern Mesopotamia</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Middle Bronze Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Early Iron Age</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Tigris River</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Archaeology</dc:subject>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/21_DT_Person">Bradley Parker</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator href="http://opencontext.org/persons/3BDBEC0E-8D0F-484F-DBD9-985F3D0915F6">Peter Cobb</dc:creator>
    <dc:identifier>http://opencontext.org/documents/F9A6613B-13EF-4062-BD33-1B0141BC36D4</dc:identifier>
    <oc:project_name href="http://opencontext.org/projects/3DE4CD9C-259E-4C14-9B03-8B10454BA66E">Kenan Tepe</oc:project_name>
    <oc:pub_date>2012-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</oc:pub_date>
    <oc:coins>ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Adc&amp;rft.type=dataset&amp;rft.title=Kenan+Tepe%3A+B-2-2000-08-022-Season&amp;rft.publisher=Open+Context&amp;rft.source=Open+Context&amp;rft.subject=Ubaid+Period&amp;rft.subject=Late+Chalcolithic+Period&amp;rft.subject=Anatolia&amp;rft.subject=Northern+Mesopotamia&amp;rft.subject=Middle+Bronze+Age&amp;rft.subject=Early+Iron+Age&amp;rft.subject=Tigris+River&amp;rft.subject=Archaeology&amp;rft.creator=Bradley+Parker&amp;rft.creator=Peter+Cobb&amp;rft.identifier=http%3A%2F%2Fopencontext.org%2Fdocuments%2FF9A6613B-13EF-4062-BD33-1B0141BC36D4</oc:coins>
    <oc:geo_reference>
      <oc:geo_lat>37.830645</oc:geo_lat>
      <oc:geo_long>40.812783</oc:geo_long>
      <oc:metasource ref_type="self" href="http://opencontext.org/subjects/F9A6613B-13EF-4062-BD33-1B0141BC36D4">
        <oc:source_name>Trench 2</oc:source_name>
        <oc:source_id>F9A6613B-13EF-4062-BD33-1B0141BC36D4</oc:source_id>
      </oc:metasource>
    </oc:geo_reference>
    <oc:copyright_lic href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
      <oc:lic_name>Attribution</oc:lic_name>
      <oc:lic_vers>3</oc:lic_vers>
      <oc:lic_URI>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</oc:lic_URI>
      <oc:lic_icon_URI>http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/88x31.png</oc:lic_icon_URI>
    </oc:copyright_lic>
  </oc:metadata>
  <oc:social_usage>
    <oc:last_updated>2012-07-01T22:38:01-07:00</oc:last_updated>
    <oc:item_views>
      <oc:count>1</oc:count>
      <oc:view_time>2012/07/01 22:38:01</oc:view_time>
    </oc:item_views>
    <oc:user_tags/>
  </oc:social_usage>
</arch:resource>
